The boring everyday gets to me sometimes,
BETAAna genjitsu ni tsubusaretemo
but I always get back on my feet, standing strong
uchinomesareta jibun hiroiatsumete
No matter how many times the end approaches me,
nando owari ga otazuneretemo
I'll push my own back forward, keeping me on my feet
sono tabi ni jibun de jibun no senaka otoshita
If I get lost in the meaning of continuing what I do,
tsudzuiteku imi ni nayami
I'll rid myself of those worries and keep myself going forward
sono mayoi sae tachikitte yuku
Always
itsumo
The straight edge that draws the outline of my future
mirai no rinkakusen egaku massuguna jougi wa
is made of all the courage I've mustered up until today
ikutsumo no kinou no yuuki de dekiteru
I'll climb over the tall wall that I never thought I'd face,
omoiegaita no to chigau takaikabe koe
and continue my journey, going past the vanishing point
shoushitsuten no mukou e susunde
This winding road seems to never end,
harukanaru winding road
but it is the road I personally chose
hoka no daredemonai watashi ga jibun de eranda
I set my tiny dreams on fire,
kasukana yume wo zenbu moyashita
and broke through the dark with its light
sono hikaru de yami wo saite
Now that I've broken down the wall,
kudaita kabe no mukou ni
I can see my sky once more
jibun no sora ga mieru