Fix it?
After what Eiji said about our names, we
can't use that for our final manuscript.
What does he mean?
You know that we all went to the office
yesterday to protest the Koogy thing, right?
Yeah.
Well, afterwards, we all got together
and showed each other our names.
And at the end, Eiji said—
I've decided on who's third,
but the other two are tied for first.
What's that supposed to mean?
Is he just trying to mess with everybody to have fun?
He sounds a bit strange in the head to me.
More than a bit.
He's still a genius!
And that was his judgement.
We can't ignore it.
Our goal is serialization.
We can't afford to mess up now!
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Tuesday and Friday
Do you have enough time to rewrite the whole thing?
You guys haven't really had
a break since you started.
You're gonna hurt yourself.
Thanks, Miyoshi.
But I'm still redoing it.
I'll regret it if I don't.
There's nothing wrong with the dialogue.
The problem is my drawings.
I've got to make them match
up better with Shuujin's story.
Fine.
But I've got one condition.
Condition?
Yeah.
Let me change the story, too.
Eh?!
You don't have to do that!
That's my opinion as an author.
After looking at the name of the "Story King"
runner-up, I realized we needed to aim higher as well.
Give me a minute.
I'll put something together in my notebook.
I was saving this idea for after we got
serialized, but this isn't the time to be holding back.
Yeah!
You two really are stupid.
Yep, we've just reached the point where we're
stupid enough to believe our dreams can come true.
What's that supposed to mean?
What the hell does he mean by a tie for first?
If that's the case, then I'll make this so intense
that nobody who reads it can argue that
it's not the best shounen manga out there!
Fukuda is re-writing his name
for the "Golden Future Cup."
I'm just in charge of the drawings, so I can't start
working until I get the final name from Aoki.
Yesterday, she told me to hold off on getting
started so she can get me the name, but—
I guess all I can do is increase
the quality of my drawings.
Yes!
Crow!
This year's
"Golden Future Cup"
is on fire!
Aoki
That's because it's a shounen manga!!
Koogy, how is the manuscript
for your manga coming along?
Don't you worry about the progress of the manuscript
because I've got the whole
thing planned out in my head.
All I've got left to do is put it down
on paper for the world to see.
You were in the running
for the Tezuka Award before,
but are you confident about winning the
"Golden Future Cup" this time around?
To me, expressing myself is much more important
than competing with others
in some ridiculous little contest.
I've been successful as a
musician, an actor, and a designer.
Next, all I want to do is revolutionize manga.
Does that mean you don't
care whether you win or lose?
I didn't say that.
If I win the "Golden Future Cup," I'll
be one step closer to serialization.
And if that happens, I can spread my
"Koogy World" to even more people!
I look forward to everybody's support.
I knew it.
I've made some changes to
the latter half of the story.
It's already been cleared by Aida as well.
Y—Yeah.
This is good.
It's a lot easier to read than before.
But above all, it's interesting.
There are more action scenes and
it feels more like a shounen manga.
And if I'm able to portray your
world at my normal level—
revised name
Aoki Ko
No, even better than I've done before,
we'll definitely win the "Golden Future Cup!"
And after that, we can get this serialized together!
That's obvious.
Where is Moritaka?
He's probably still sleeping.
He came home late again yesterday.
Is that so?
I'm heading out.
I'll probably be gone until I finish the manuscript.
And when exactly will that be?
The deadline is August 2nd.
I figured something like this would happen
as soon as summer vacation started.
Make sure you're eating properly.
And make sure you get enough sleep, too.
I know already.
Well then—
Moritaka.
What is it, grandpa?
Make sure you are satisfied with what you do.
This is what you chose to do, after all.
Just don't forget about all the people
around you who are supporting you.
Don't worry, I won't.
See you later.
Dad, please don't push him so hard.
He's still only a child.
Kayoko, if you don't want to be found out, you
should do a better job of hiding your manga.
Dad, you've been getting into
my alcohol again, haven't you?
Oops.
I ate too much.
Thanks for the food.
So, do you think you'll make it in time?
We've got to do 20 pages in the next 10 days.
25 Pages left
20 Pages left
Summer Vacation
25 Pages left
20 Pages left
Summer Vacation
Two pages a day, huh?
20 Pages left
Summer Vacation
That'll be easy!
Deadline
When you break it up like that, yeah.
Yeah.
But I want to make our manuscript
perfect before the deadline.
We should be able to improve it even more.
"Manga has no limits," huh?
Yeah, and you can always
improve the art and the story.
Yeah.
You started over from the character design
and made something you're satisfied with.
I can't slack off either.
I'll go back over all the dialogue and write
something that will really pull the readers in.
Let's do as much as we can
right up until the deadline.
Yeah.
Alright, let's get back to work.
First we win the "Golden
Future Cup," then it's serialization!
Yeah!
Alright!
I'm starting to get excited too!
Let me know if there's anything I can do to help!
Thanks, Miyoshi.
Alright.
Let's do this!
Battle start!
Nakai
"I look forward to everybody's support."
Deadline
Golden Future Cup Deadline!!
Finished!
Alright, we're done!
I'll go buy something to celebrate!
Oh, we've gotta go turn this in.
We'll celebrate when you get back, then.
I'm gonna call Hattori.
Hello? This is Takagi.
Sorry for taking so long.
We've finished the manuscript.
Are you alright?
You haven't slept for two days.
You haven't, either.
I took some breaks in the middle, though.
I'm alright.
I'll make sure not to fall
asleep before we turn this in.
If we get serialized, I wonder
if every week will be like this.
Is it too much for you?
No way!
We're finally close to being serialized.
I'm getting more and more excited!
That reminds me of something you said when
you first asked me to write manga with you.
You said you wanted to be a rich big-shot.
And you told me there was no
way you'd become a mangaka.
You said most people who become
mangakas were geniuses
and that the rest were just gamblers.
You still remember all that?
You were right, though.
It's been tough, but I've felt like we were
actually doing something everyday.
Yeah.
And if we do manage to get
lucky, we'll get rich in no time!
Keep your voice down.
Huh?
Besides, I'm not in this for the money anyway.
Yeah, you're in it for the girls.
Money?
Girls?
Manga?
The style of the main character
is much more shounen now.
I guess they were inspired
by Fukuda and the others.
Looks like you two made quite a few changes.
Um—
I'm sorry that we didn't talk it over with you.
We thought we'd try to make it a bit better.
I'm not upset.
Eh?
It would have been nice if
you'd mentioned it, though.
That aside, you sure worked
hard to do all this in time.
Well, we really wanted to get
first in the "Golden Future Cup."
Right.
"The Two Earths."
Huh?
"One in a Hundred Million."
"Money and Intelligence."
"Angel Days."
And now your latest work.
I really think you guys have
grown a lot since you started.
You two have really worked hard.
Yes!
Thank you!
Ashirogi Muto's "Shady Detective Trap."
Good work you two.
Thank you very much!
August 9th (Mon)
"Kiyoshi Knight" by Fukuda Shinta
"Golden Future Cup" Entry No. 1
A high schooler with a dagger?
Not even the Yakuza use those much anymore—
And he even stabbed me with it.
Kiyoshi, you're bleeding a lot!
This is really bad!
It's fine as long as it's only blood!
I'd look like a loser if my guts started coming out.
Only a loser loses his guts.
This isn't the time to be making jokes!
You're really going to die!
As long as Shouko is safe, that's okay with me.
I can die if it's for her.
You idiot!
If you die, who do you think will be the saddest?!
Um—
My mommy?
Kiyoshi—
You're supposed to say Shouko even if it's not true.
She didn't even give me any
chocolate on Valentine's Day.
Stop talking!
Man, doing all those thousands of
sit-ups every day was pointless.
It didn't help stop that knife—
How is it?
It's a lot better than the name we read before.
He used a different pen so his lines give it a
lot more intensity than it had as a one-shot.
You think we can win?
We have to.
Fukuda's early results come out
tomorrow and the real deal is on Friday.
The results are out that fast?
That's because it's a weekly magazine.
I wonder if Hattori is going to tell us the results.
I'm sure he would if we asked, but
I don't think he'd tell us otherwise.
He'll probably tell us if we did better
than Fukuda when our results come in.
So if we don't hear anything, then
that means we didn't do as well?
Let's not ask about the results of the other entries.
Let's just focus on writing the best
names for serialization that we can.
Alright.
But I just can't stop wondering.
I really want to be number one.
Niizuma
The early results are tomorrow, huh?
Niizuma-sensei.
Mine is interesting, right?
Kiyoshi is really cool!
It's interesting and the
drawings have gotten better, too.
August 10th (Tues)
Kiyoshi Knight early results—
Please!
Alright!
If I can get Fukuda Shinta
serialized along with Niizuma Eiji,
I'll be the next team captain for sure!
No, I'm not safe yet.
I've still got the real deal and three
other entries left to worry about.
Especially Ashirogi Muto.
And who knows what will
happen with Makaino Koji's votes.
Koji, you know the deadline is in two weeks, right?
I know that, but I had all those interviews.
It can't be helped if I'm a little late, now can it?
August 13th (Fri)
Crow jump!
And times three!
Hattori Yujiro
The real deal results are here!
Hello?
Yes.
Really?
So I can start working on a name for serialization?
You did it! Congratulations!
I'm going to win the "Golden Future Cup" for sure!
Aoki?
Fukuda just got a call from his editor.
It looks like his real deal results were good.
Is that so?
Is that all you had to say?
Uh, well, yes.
It doesn't really matter to me how the others do.
I'll speak to you later.
Um—
August 23rd (Mon)
"Shady Detective Trap" by Ashirogi Muto
"Golden Future Cup" Entry No. 2
Damn it!
You're telling me that the one who suggested
trading the stolen painting for the camera footage—
And that the person who looked
like me in the footage itself—
Was you?!
I don't know who that was.
But the fact that you were in possession of
the stolen painting is indisputable proof.
If you haven't got any proof,
you've just got to create it!
Thank you so much for returning the
painting our father treasured so much.
And about your $100,000 commission—
I've already been paid.
Eh?
Saori's smile is worth more than $100,000.
This is so cool.
Our manga is in Weekly Jack.
"Trap" is really good.
You guys are definitely
better than "Kiyoshi Tonight."
It's not "Kiyoshi Tonight," it's "Knight."
Saiko.
Why the long face?
Seeing this in Jack makes me realize
just how bad my drawings are.
Series like "One Piece" and "Naruto"
haven't just been good from the
beginning, they have individuality.
You wouldn't mistake Oda-sensei's or
Kishimoto-sensei's drawings for anybody else's.
That may be true, but you're
comparing yourself to two of the best.
That's probably Miho.
New Message
Azuki Miho
I told her that your manga goes on sale today.
Mashiro
"Shady Detective Trap" was great!
I even sent in the questionnaire
postcard. *lol*
What'd she say?
Did she tell you what she thought?
She said "Trap" was good!
This gives me confidence!
We'll definitely get first!
He hasn't changed a bit.
This is good.
The drawings and the story are even
better than they were in the name.
That's Ashirogi-sensei for you.
The story is great and
the drawings fit it perfectly.
Is it better than mine?
Hm, I'd say it's a tie.
So he was talking about Fukuda's
and Mashiro's manga before?
If that's true—
Did you see the early results?
Yes.
August 24th (Tues)
It looks like this year's "Golden Future
Cup" is going to be pretty interesting.
What about yours, Aida?
I've got a really good one too.
Next week's is going to great.
Takagi Akito
Hello? Takagi?
This is Hattori.
I understand.
Right.
Thank you.
It's only the early results,
but he says we can go with
"Trap" for a serialization name!
Alright!
Thank you.
I'll take your manuscript with me.
Thanks.
Koji, did you read "Kiyoshi Knight"
and "Shady Detective Trap?"
I already know I'm going to win by
a landslide, so there's no reason to.
Alright, I'll see you later then.
I'm looking forward to the questionnaire results.
August 27th (Fri)
"Trap's" real deal—
Please!
Wait, this is—
Where did I put last weeks results?
I'm going to have a cigarette.
Really?!
Thank you!
The real deal results are the same!
Yay!
So did he say if it was better than "Kiyoshi Knight?"
Oh, he didn't say.
But he said to write the name for serialization, so—
"About the same?"
What exactly does 'about' mean?
Can't you be more specific?
That must mean that Ashirogi's
results were good too.
You're not allowed to say yet?
That sucks!
August 30th (Mon)
"Hideout Door" by Aoki Ko and Nakai Takuro
"Golden Future Cup" Entry No. 3
A—A fairy?!
I—I can't believe that.
You're the one who opened
that door and came through.
You still can't believe it?
You have two choices.
Accept the soul of a fairy and become one of us—
Or end up as something's dinner.
Eh?!
What's this?
This is crazy.
He's done stippling on all the backgrounds!
The drawings are so beautiful.
Nakai did say he was putting his whole
career on the line, but to go this far—
This'll get votes just from the quality of the art.
Yeah, I really like it.
This might be bad.
Even so, there's no way he could keep
this up for a weekly serialization.
Yeah, there's no way.
No, Nakai's speed and technique is amazing.
And if he's got assistants,
I think he'd be able to do it.
Beautiful!
Nakai, this is great!
Fantastic!
What's with this art?
I might've underestimated Nakai.
And that woman.
Her story is still a bit strange,
but she changed enough to make
it feel more like a shounen manga.
Mine should still be able to beat this, though!
August 31st (Tues)
This one too.
I didn't expect this.
I guess I should call Nakai and Aoki.
A—Are you serious?!
Yeah, with an early result
like this, there's no problem.
T—This is great.
I'll be able to work with Aoki.
Nakai, are you listening?
Oh, y-yes!
Thank you!
Nakai, congratulations.
If he's that happy, does that mean he beat me?
Is that so?
Did my ranking go down?
Don't worry.
September 3rd (Fri)
Your 'like' percentage hasn't changed much.
Let's push forward with this.
Understood.
Thank you.
Yep.
Niizuma
There's nothing to be bummed out about.
My rank went down in the real deal too.
And if your editor told you to go
ahead and aim for serialization,
then that's the same as me.
We'll be competing again
in the serialization meeting.
I'm not bummed out at all.
Hm?
It's just that I'm so happy.
That fact that I'm able to fight on even ground
with you and Ashirogi makes me so happy.
Thank you, Niizuma-sensei, Fukuda.
This is all thanks to you.
Cut it out, Nakai.
You're not supposed to cry
until after you get serialized.
Koogy's manga still hasn't run yet.
Y—You're right.
September 6th (Mon)
"Colorfusical" by Makaino Koji
"Golden Future Cup" Entry No. 4
We definitely beat this one.
I don't even know what the heck is going on.
It's like he's so full of himself
that he can't express it to others.
Oh, it looks like you got it pretty well.
I guess it's up to how many of his fans support him.
That Koogy has no idea what manga even is!
Even if his fans do support him,
if he manages to get this serialized, I
don't want anything to do with Jack!
Fukuda-sensei, you're so cool!
If that happens, then I'll quit writing too!
You don't have to go along with him.
Is that so?
Okay.
Here are the real deal results.
September 10th (Fri)
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
The "Golden Future Cup" was full of great manga.
Next
Episode
Don't worry.
Azuki?
I believe that you guys will get first.
Next time: Call and Eve.
Call and
Eve
We'll size our dream.
We have to believe in ourselves!