I'll try—
No—
I'll make sure to write an
interesting name this summer.
Miyoshi got an email from a
publisher asking her to write more.
Everyone wants to spend time with
the person they like, don't they?
Azuki Miho
Good Morning
It's because I want to
treasure the promise we
made. Because if we wait
until our dreams come true to meet,
our love and joy will be even greater.
You and Azuki are the strange ones.
Time's up.
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Two and One
Shuujin.
I'm going to write manga
on my own from now on.
Eh?!
W—Why?!
I think it should be pretty obvious.
I'm trying to be a mangaka.
You fail if you can't make your deadlines, right?
Yeah, but—
Saiko.
I guess I'll take it back, then.
I don't want you hanging
out there with Miyoshi, anyway.
Saiko.
You've got that part wrong.
The reason I couldn't finish the name
isn't because I was with Miyoshi.
Actually, it's just the opposite.
The opposite?
I've gotten pretty serious about her.
I really want to write
something that'll be successful.
I guess it's kind of like you and Azuki
waiting until your dreams come true.
Love takes many different forms.
I didn't start out doing this for a girl.
But now, I think I'm just like you.
I see.
I guess I did have the wrong idea.
Sorry.
But—
If that's true, then you really
can't miss your deadlines.
I'm going to be a manga writer no matter what.
Even if I have to team up with somebody else.
But your names—
They look like crap, so let me
know when you finish one.
I'll clean it up for you.
Nobody else will understand what you wrote.
Really?
Though, it'll cost you 100 yen each.
Sure.
Thank you.
Also,
if I'm working on my own,
I want to change Ashirogi Muto to Ashiro Muto.
Is that okay?
Okay?
Shouldn't you just use your real name?
No.
I see.
Yeah, that's fine with me.
What are you two doing?
The opening ceremony is gonna start soon!
So what are you doing here?
I was nervous about the new term, so I overslept.
Wow, that's lame.
Later, Saiko.
Let's both do our best.
Y—Yeah—
What about Mashiro?
It's alright, let's go.
What?!
That's terrible!
It's my fault for not keeping my promise.
It's all my fault.
No it's not!
Yes it is.
It's because you spent the entire break with me.
It's not your fault!
We spent time together,
but I was writing scenarios
the whole time, wasn't I?
Yeah, you're right!
All we need to do is to tell Mashiro
and I'm sure he'll understand.
I'll go—
Stop it!
If you do that, it'll just
sound like I'm making excuses.
And don't tell Azuki, either.
It's my fault.
So please don't say
anything unnecessary, alright?
I've got to!
He already knows it wasn't your fault!
It's not like everything is over!
I'm still going to be a manga writer!
And Saiko will keep going, too!
I'm going to keep working
hard because I like you.
No, I can work hard.
I told Saiko too, and he understands.
Because you like me?
Yeah.
I'm doing this for you.
But—
If you say anything to
either of them, I'll hate you.
B—But—
You want to do it alone?
Did you guys fight or something?
We're not that immature.
This isn't a name yet, but I
came up with an idea for a story.
Here.
Story Ideas
A con artist detective who sets up traps
for criminals to discover the truth.
Good.
If you do the story right,
it could definitely be interesting.
But to pull this off,
won't he need Takagi's help?
So you've given up on mainstream battle manga?
This is also pretty mainstream, so—
Yeah.
I guess you're right.
And this is much more suited
to Ashirogi Muto's style, too.
I think the coffee's getting to me.
I'll be right back.
Alright.
Takagi?
This is Hattori.
Why did you guys decide to split up?
He wouldn't tell me anything.
Oh, that's my fault.
I told him I'd have a name ready by the end of
summer break, but I couldn't finish it in time.
That's it?
Mashiro sure is strict.
No, he's just really serious about what he's doing.
Oh.
I also started thinking I wasn't very
suited to writing a battle manga.
Mashiro seemed really set on doing one, so
I guess we just weren't on the same page.
Right now, I'm writing a mystery.
A mystery?!
Y—Yeah.
Would it be possible to have
you take a look at my name?
Oh, um—
Sure. Of course.
So Mashiro doesn't know that
you're writing a mystery right now?
I couldn't tell him I decided
to write something different.
I had planned on telling him
after I finished it this summer,
but I couldn't get it done in time,
so I'll try and become a manga writer on my own.
What's with these two?
If I tell Takagi what Mashiro
is working on right now—
No.
Alright, a mystery is good.
It suits you.
Just hurry up and bring it in.
Even if you tell me to hurry,
I don't have any ideas for the main character.
Just make the main
character a normal detective.
What's important is the
tricks and how they play out.
Don't worry.
You're talented.
I'm always telling you that the whole
editing department thinks so too, right?
Just be confident in yourself.
O—Okay.
Yujiro.
Crow's on the cover of volume 49.
Alright, thanks.
Good timing, Fukuda.
You're at Niizuma's place, right?
Can you give him the phone for a second?
Excuse me?!
Sorry, that was a bit rude of me.
Can I just get you to fax your name in?
Huh?
You want to meet in person?
Fukuda, you're always like this!
Though, I guess that's what I like about you—
Sorry 'bout that.
Oh, that's okay.
I think this is great.
Write me a name.
Your biggest strength is your drawings,
so make sure you focus on
finding a style that fits the story.
Right.
Huh?
You alone today?
Oh, could it be—
That you guys split up?
Oh, I was right?
You're the one who does the drawings, right?
I've been looking for somebody to do the drawings
for the runner-up in the latest "Story King."
If you're interested—
You can't have him!
Eh?
What the hell is going on?
Scary.
Guess I'll get back to work.
Sorry about that.
It's alright.
The runner-up for the latest "Story King."
If you were to do the art and get it serialized, it would most likely be popular.
If something is good, of course it'll be serialized.
Did you want to do it?
Um—
Because if you say you want to,
I can go apologize right now and ask him for you.
If something is good, it'll be serialized.
And if I get serialized—
However,
if you do that,
you won't be able to team up with Takagi anymore.
Do you still want want to do it?
Team up with me and write manga.
I'm going to draw the pictures
and he's going to write the stories.
Fu—
sion!
Ha!
It's non-stop to the finish line!
Yeah!
Alright!!
Thank you, Saiko.
I don't know.
I'm just not sure
what I should do yet.
If you aren't sure, then I don't think it's a good
idea to team up with somebody else just yet.
Right.
Hi, Takagi?
It's kind of sudden, but can you come in tomorrow?
So, I actually asked you here
to talk about Mashiro.
I want you to answer honestly.
Are you completely against
teaming up with him again?
No, not at all.
I'm the one who asked him
to team up in the first place.
Of course I want to work together.
Is that so?
But,
it's my fault things ended up this way.
I'd like to write something that will
make him want to work with me again.
Before he manages to get serialized on his own.
That's good to hear.
Just leave everything to me.
Eh?
If you do what I say,
I'll get you two back together
and we'll make a hit manga for sure.
The truth is that you and Mashiro
are both on the exact same page.
You might say that you couldn't write
different manga even if you wanted to.
I'm not really sure what you—
Right now, Mashiro is trying to come
up with a detective story of his own.
What?
Hattori.
Did you tell Mashiro what I'm working on right now?
No.
I was really surprised that two
people who decided to split up
both decided to write the same kind
of story without telling each other.
In any case,
could you keep this a secret until you're
about to graduate and write a mystery—
No, a name for whatever
Mashiro is trying to come up with?
Keep it a secret?
Mashiro is always trying to
rush into getting serialized, right?
But a detective story should
have a little more time put into it.
So, for the next two years,
let's work on a name together.
But, wouldn't that be like lying to Mashiro?
This is how it works at Jack right now:
If you make a one-shot that's popular
enough, they let you serialize it.
If you submit just three interesting chapters for
a serialization meeting, they let you serialize it.
It's only natural that this leads
to many new series ending early.
It's especially hard on new artists.
But for a while now, I've been wanting to put
some extra time into a series to make it great.
But the only ones who can do
that right now are you two.
I gave you a deadline of six months
to come up with a battle manga,
but if you're going to go
with this, that doesn't apply.
Spend as much time as you can
on this for the next two years
and then get Mashiro to draw it for you.
I'm sure you can make something amazing.
There's no point in getting serialized
while you're still in high school
if it just ends up getting cancelled anyway.
So while you still can, spend time
on making something perfect.
I'll make sure that Mashiro doesn't team up
with anybody else or get serialized by himself.
You can't do that.
If Mashiro manages to get serialized on his own,
then shouldn't you let him do it?
I talked to Mashiro yesterday.
To me, it looked like part of
him still wants to work with you.
Since he turned down doing the drawings for the
runner-up name in the latest "Story King" contest.
If that's so, is there any
reason to not tell Mashiro—
If you do that, Mashiro will
push to get serialized right away.
For his sake—
No, for both of your sakes,
you should make a name that you've
had a lot of time to think about.
So, the character that Mashiro
has been thinking about is—
Please don't say anything!
If you say any more, I'll just end up trying to
write a name that matches Mashiro's character.
I want to try and win something
like "Story King" on my own.
Then, if Mashiro says he's okay
with getting back together, we will.
Takagi—
I guess you're right.
What you said makes a lot of sense.
I guess I think too much like an adult.
Sorry.
I'm counting on you to come
up with something interesting.
Right.
This is fine.
Even if Mashiro tells Takagi that he's
trying to come up with a detective story,
Takagi won't say anything
about what he's writing.
Even if it takes all he's got, he'll
definitely bring in an interesting mystery.
It's too weird to see you guys not working together.
Miyoshi—
I'll do whatever it takes to help you guys make up.
It's not like we're fighting or anything.
It doesn't matter!
Just tell me what I can do to help!
Really, it's alright.
Man, names really are difficult.
Shuujin sure is amazing.
How's he always do it?
How do I make names?
Yeah, tell me.
First, he thinks up everything in his head,
then writes the dialogue out on the computer,
and then turns that into the pages and panels?
Yeah!
I watched him do it all summer long on my computer,
so that's how I know!
Uh, what's wrong?
If even Shuujin wasn't able to do that much,
then I wonder if I'll be able to.
If you don't think you can, just get back toge—
No.
I'm still going to try.
Even if I have to do it alone,
I've decided to do it for Azuki.
I'll do it no matter what!
That's why I'm saying—
You said you'd figured something out,
but I haven't heard anything
about you for two months.
You actually writing?
Y—Yes.
It's going slowly, but—
That's fine, then.
I've got a one-shot in the next issue.
I submitted it for serialization.
It didn't exactly get rejected, but they
made me try it out as a one-shot first.
Man, the editing department just
doesn't have an eye for greatness.
But that's still good news, isn't it?!
Congratulations.
It's not great at all.
If it doesn't do well, there
goes my shot at a series.
Oh yeah, and ever since last time,
Nakai has really gotten serious.
Not sure what it's about, but the
art definitely isn't name level.
It's like a painting or something.
It may have only been for a bit,
but you worked with us too.
You're also part of Team Niizuma—
I mean, Team Fukuda.
So you'd better try harder
so we can all change Jack.
Team Fukuda?
Later, then.
No slacking off.
Right.
I'll do my best.
Fukuda and Nakai are both doing names.
And it's a late night show again,
but Azuki got another regular role.
Can I really become a mangaka?
What? They split up?
Sorry.
Takagi told me not to make you worry, but I—
Here.
It was 100 yen each, right?
Can you clean these up for me?
You wrote a name?
It's only five, but yeah.
You finished five?
Wow, I haven't even finished one.
"Transparent Detective Skeleton"
(Tentative Title)
A detective?
What is this?
It's a name.
Not that.
Why's it a detective story?
Did Hattori tell you I was trying
to come up with a detective story?
Yeah.
But I didn't find out until about a
month after I'd started writing my own.
I got the idea when I saw a cellphone novel
website that was looking for mystery stories.
Oh yeah, it was the day you called
me when I was at Miyoshi's place.
That's the same day I quit as Eiji's assistant.
It's also the same day I came up with
the idea to write a detective story.
What?
The truth is that you and Mashiro
are both on the exact same page.
Great minds think alike, I guess.
So we both came up with the
same thing on the same day?
What the hell—
We're such idiots!
Man, I could almost cry.
Hattori sure is sly.
Yeah.
But there's no way I could keep
you in the dark for two years.
I'd have to hide it from Azuki and Miyoshi as well.
So what do we say to him?
Just be honest and go back to
the way we've been doing it—
No, that's just the easy way out.
We ended up like this because I couldn't
finish the name and you got mad at me.
To be honest, I'm not really that mad.
What? Really?
I thought the reason you didn't finish the name
was because you were just hanging out with Miyoshi.
But now I know I was wrong.
Maybe I was just jealous of her.
I also realized one more thing.
I need your help.
Saiko—
Hey, why don't we fool Hattori?
Us, fool him?
We let him think that we're still working separately
and just keep telling him that we can't come
up with anything for about six months.
Then we use that time to come up with not
three, but ten names ready for serialization.
That's a great idea.
Hattori said to think about it for two years,
but we can't wait that long.
Yeah, it's definitely a better idea to spend
more time thinking if it's a detective story,
but two years is just too long.
My condition is six months.
We take our time and work on a name together.
Yeah, that's good. I like it.
We'll fool Hattori.
That's just like the detective
I've been thinking about.
R—Really?
It's so perfect!
It's decided, then.
Not exactly what Hattori had in mind, was it?
Even Hattori said it.
A mangaka must be able to surpass his editor.
I guess he did.
We were only split up for a month, huh?
Seems a bit short, doesn't it?
That's fine.
There was no reason to split up in the first place.
Now that we've figured that out,
let's head over to the studio.
I want to see your character design.
Sure.
Wait right there!
Huh?
Won't you guys try talking again?
Ashirogi Muto is supposed to be the
dreams of two becoming one, right?!
We've already talked about it.
Huh?
We're getting back together.
What?!
Sorry we made you worry.
What the heck?!
I was so worried that I cried!
Sorry.
We're heading to the studio
now, so I'll make it up to you.
You wanna come?
Yeah!
Uh—oh.
What's wrong?
I kinda told Miho that the two of you split up.
What?!
I told you not to say anything!
But—
Miho was really worried this time.
But she told me not to interfere with anything.
Mashiro?
I'm sending her a message apologizing for
making her worry and to say we're back together.
Send.
Woah, that was fast!
Azuki Miho
Back
Together
I'm so relieved. Good luck! I'm a little jealous that
you and Takagi are more in sync than we are, though.
*lol*
Hey, what'd she say?
Eh?
I guess you can read it.
What's this?
She says you are on the same wavelength?
That's funny.
Shut up.
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
Next up is a detective story.
Next
Episode
How was my "Skeleton: The Transparent Detective?"
Detective stories make great mainstream manga!
And what about my "Skeleton?"
Hey—
Next time: Cooperation and Conditions.
Cooperation and
Conditions
Dreams come in many forms.