This is way better than the last one.
What?
I'm surprised.
You've corrected the weaknesses I mentioned
last time, in both your artwork and your storyline.
The story is especially great.
Thank you! This time I used Mashiro's input as well.
Today is September 30th.
Why don't you guys try submitting
this for the Tezuka Award?
Yes, sir!
We were cut at the final round.
Four works were chosen, one winner and
three honorable mentions, but we didn't make it.
Do you know the difference between
you guys and this Niizuma Eiji,
who won both first prize and runner up?
It's the artwork.
You both got 4 out of 5 on
the evaluation and storyline.
But for illustrations, he got
a 5 while you guys got a 3.
I bet the 3 was a pity score too.
In other words, you have the talent,
but Mashiro's holding you back.
Ishizawa, that was too blunt.
I'm just telling the truth.
You know—
You're really asking for it—
Stop, Shuujin!
It's true my artwork's not good enough.
Look, even he admits it.
Have you ever drawn a 31-page manga before?
Nope.
But I'm way better at drawing than him.
Wanna see?
If you paired up with me, we'd definitely—
Shuujin!
Apologize to Mashiro right now!
Wh—What are you doing?
I'm gonna tell a teacher!
Go ahead!
I'm telling you to apologize!
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Every worry floats up to and fills the spring sky
shinpaigoto bakari ga tsumoru haru no sora wo
I look up, look down,
miagete utsumuite
and find myself looking back up at the sky
mata kao wo ageteru
I swore I'd find myself in this town
kono machi de mitsukerutte kimeta jibun
I tuck away all my important things into my heart for safekeeping
nakushicha ikenai mono wo mune ni
Your love
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Regrets and Understandings
Hey, did you hear?
Some ninth graders got in a fight yesterday.
Really? Who?
I don't know his name, but some
guy who always does well on tests.
Really? Someone like that got in a fight?
Hey, Saiko!
Why'd you keep us in the dark?
I had no idea you were drawing manga!
It's amazing you guys made it to the
final round for the Tezuka Award!
I think better of Takagi now, sacrificing his
grades for the noble pursuit of writing manga.
So, did the thing with Ishizawa yesterday
have something to do with manga?
He says he wants to become a mangaka too.
What, really?
Huh? Saiko?
And to solve this problem, just apply this formula.
Did you get that, Kawasaki?
Why do you always call me out, sir?
Because if you can understand it,
everyone else probably can too.
I don't think Suzuki understands it.
What're you saying?
Then let's have Suzuki solve this problem for us.
Inbox
Shuujin
Takagi
It's from Shuujin.
Inbox
Shuujin
Takagi
Shuujin Takagi
Starting today
I'm suspended for a week. So I
have time to work on a name!
Let's do this!
Shuujin Takagi
Starting today
I'm suspended for a week. So I
have time to work on a name!
Let's do this!
There he is.
Mashiro!
Where's Takagi?
I haven't seen him around today.
He's suspended for a week.
What?! Why?
Ishizawa came to school!
And it was his fault for saying that stuff!
Well, Takagi did go a little overboard.
But I never thought he'd flip like that!
I kind of have a new opinion of him now.
Huh? Wait, you're leaving?
Mashiro!
Team up with me and create manga.
I decided to team up with him to create manga—
An anime by the time we're eighteen?
Towards that goal—
No—
Let's make it a reality!
Then I'll go to North High too.
He's even going to a different high school,
to make creating manga together easier.
And yet I'm still—
The story is especially good.
In other words, you have the talent,
but Mashiro's holding you back.
If only we could've gotten that award—
Hey, Miho, look at this.
Huh?
This is what Ishizawa was taking about right?
I'm so surprised.
I can't believe Takagi wants to be a mangaka!
"One in a Hundred Million"
Takagi Akito ▪ Mashiro Moritaka (14) Saitama
I had no idea at all!
So that's why he's been so
out of it lately. I get it now.
Hey, what are you reading?
Mina!
Oh, Jack!
Mina, do you know Jack?
All the boys at school read it.
I see.
But why are you guys reading Jack?
'Cause someone we know is in it!
Wow!
Show me!
Mina, you shouldn't be bothering
your sister when she has friends over.
But Mom!
She can show you later.
Why don't you go eat the
cake I put on the table for you?
Okay!
Sorry about that, Kaya.
Was she a bother?
Oh, not at all. Especially compared to my siblings!
Is the Takagi you were talking about
earlier, the one in Miho's class?
You know him?
Yes, because he's first in the class and all.
But Takagi got suspended.
How come?
He punched this guy who totally deserved it.
My—
But bad boys do have a certain charm to them.
Mother!
What's a girlfriend supposed
to do in this situation?
Wow! He's your boyfriend?
Well, we're not officially going out yet,
I mean, with him being depressed right now and all.
Wow, so this is a girlfriend's loyal support.
Let's not go that far!
You better do your best too, Miho!
Shut up!
What's the matter, Moritaka?
Huh? Nothing.
Just couldn't sleep.
Oh.
How's the manga coming?
We're doing our best.
I see.
Thank you for paying the studio's utility bill.
Masahiro is the one paying for that.
Dad?
Did something happen?
Not really.
As long as you're still
fighting the fight, it'll work out.
Grandpa,
Yes?
There's this guy I'm drawing manga with,
but I feel like I'm holding him back.
He might not be successful
because he teamed up with me.
I was wondering if he regrets teaming up.
He probably doesn't.
Huh?
He chose you himself after all, right?
So he'll be able to live with it.
If it's something you decide for
yourself, you'll never truly regret it.
That's what it says in "Man's Pride."
Huh?
Volume four of Nobuhiro's
work, if I remember correctly.
He read them? And he remembers them?
It's something he
chose for himself.
So he'll be able
to live with it.
Both Grandpa and—
Kawaguchi Taro believe this.
Mashiro
Bye!
Do you understand this part, Kawasaki?
This part? Sir, is it this part?
Not that part, this part.
I saw Jack.
That's amazing. Congratulations!
I'll work harder!
Uh, This part?
Sir, can you continue your lecture?
Can you please write the
important part on the board?
We still have a long way to go
We'll definitely get there though!
Thanks
We still have a long way to go
We'll definitely get there though!
Thanks
We still have a long way to go
We'll definitely get there though!
Thanks
We still have a long way to go
We'll definitely get there though!
Thanks
We still have a long way to go
We'll definitely get there though!
Oh, sure.
Thanks
We still have a long way to go
We'll definitely get there though!
Thanks
We still have a long way to go
We'll definitely get there though!
Thanks
We still have a long way to go
We'll definitely get there though!
Thanks
We still have a long way to go
We'll definitely get there though!
Is Takagi okay?
I'm gonna go check on him after school
Staff
Room
Here's Takagi's address.
Remember, he is suspended.
Yes.
He's a popular one, isn't he?
Huh?
Yakusa Corporative House
Found it.
Takagi
Oh, right—
Avenge—
You must—
avenge your father!
His mom's probably not here.
Coming!
Oh, Saiko!
Good timing! I was just about to text you!
I managed to come up with something
good, since I have all this time.
I wasn't sure if I should make a name out
of it, so I wanted you to have a look!
Thank goodness. He's totally fine.
It's not much, but come on in!
Okay!
I bet you're surprised by how run-down the place is.
I don't have any slippers, so you
can just leave your shoes on.
What?
Why are they—
S—Sorry for the intrusion—
It's still just prose, but I feel pretty good about it.
Let me see.
If you don't like it, just say so, okay?
NO GOOD !!
He's written this many?
I still have a lot more.
He only deems a small fraction worthy for me to see.
Ah, this one's pretty good too.
Wait a sec, what are those two doing here?
I guess I'm suddenly popular
'cause I punched Ishizawa.
I guess it's true bad boys have a certain charm?
Should you really be saying that now?
I'm glad you came 'cause I had no idea what to do!
I think Miyoshi came 'cause
she was worried about me.
That, I can see.
But what about Iwase?
Seems like Iwase and I are somehow going out.
Seems like?
I don't remember this at all,
but at the end of seventh grade—
I'm Iwase Aiko.
H—Huh? Um—
I'm the Iwase Aiko who ranked
second on final exams this year.
Oh, I see.
Let's motivate each other to do even better.
Y—Yeah, will do!
Supposedly something like that happened.
And just 'cause of that, she
thinks you're going out?
Yeah, 'cause according to Iwase—
We shook hands.
That handshake was your
acknowledgment of our relationship.
—is what she said.
I just thought we were agreeing to be
rivals who compete with each other.
I guess someone as serious as Iwase
could interpret that differently.
You and Azuki haven't even held hands yet,
so Iwase and I have gone farther than you.
This is not a laughing matter.
Wait, did Miyoshi hear this debate
about being in a relationship?
Yeah, Miyoshi said—
Are you really dating Iwase?
If you are, then why'd you confess to me?
—and got angry.
And right then, you showed up and saved me.
I have terrible timing.
This place is like a battlefield.
Hey.
What're you two whispering about?
Man up!
R—Right!
Who are you gonna go out with? Me or Iwase?
Wait!
I never said I'd date either of you.
I only shook hands with Iwase.
I didn't think that meant we were dating.
I only said I wanted to talk to Miyoshi.
I didn't mean that as a confession of love.
Objections?
Idiot—
I'm leaving.
Takagi, do you dislike me?
No, not really.
Then, do you like me?
If I had to choose between like
or dislike, I guess it'd be like.
Goodbye.
Wait up, Miyoshi.
It's the same with you. If I had
to say like or dislike, it'd be like.
What?
How can you cheat on both of
us, right in front of each other?!
Th—That's what you think this is?
She's right.
What are you thinking, Shuujin?
Wait, then let me ask, do
you guys actually like me?
Yes. In a "let's date" kind of way.
Of course I like you.
I wouldn't have let you hold my hand, otherwise.
What?
Why must I be so popular?!
This is so weird!
Huh? Wait a second. HUH?
Why's he freaking out?
Answer me. Who do you like, me or Iwase?
I'll end up dating whoever I say I like, won't I?
But, I have a dream to become a mangaka!
Love comes second!
Even if we went out, I wouldn't
have time to actually go on dates!
That's fine. I'll support you.
Stop writing manga.
You'll definitely regret it someday if you don't.
I don't mind the regret, if I fail in
an attempt to achieve my dreams.
What I don't wanna regret
is not chasing those dreams.
Before I started drawing manga with Mashiro,
I let every day just pass me by.
But now, each day has meaning.
I'm living life with all I've got.
Iwase, I'm gonna go to North High with Mashiro.
I see.
Goodbye.
Takagi.
You'll regret this for the rest of your life.
I'm sure of it.
That's fine. When I do, feel free to laugh at me.
I couldn't—
North High is my first choice too.
No way!
Then it's settled. Since you rejected Iwase and all.
Wow, North High—
I thought we'd definitely go to
different schools 'cause you're so smart.
I'm so glad.
Now we'll be together next year, too!
But, could you look at my homework—
Miyoshi,
Mashiro and Azuki might not be officially dating,
but they both have feelings for each other.
What, really?!
Wh—What'd you say that for?
I asked you about Azuki for him.
Not 'cause you wanted to talk to me?
Right.
I wanted to know more about Azuki—
I'm sorry.
That was my fault.
Yes, it was.
So let me hit you ten more times.
B—But you used to do karate or
aikido or something didn't you?
And boxing.
Then, just three more punches.
I'll feel a lot better after that.
Alright, then punch me!
After I do, go out with me?
H—How's that related at all?!
You said you liked me earlier, didn't you?
Man, I give up! Just punch me!
Are you alright, Takagi?
Go home already.
Saiko, wait! I wanted to talk to you about something.
About manga?
Yeah.
Got it.
I don't wanna get in the way,
so I'll come back another time.
Good luck with your manga!
She's pretty cool.
I guess she's a good person at heart.
What'd you wanna talk about?
I got a call from Hattori earlier.
He said to look over the comments from the
Tezuka Award committee and review our work.
And come by again when we're free.
Got it.
Next time, we'll win and make our debut!
Yeah.
'Cause we're gonna get an anime
by the time we're eighteen, right?
I'll definitely come up with an amazing
name, since I finally have some free time.
I'll practice drawing more, too.
I'll make sure you won't regret this.
I was a real lady's man today, huh?
Ow!
I don't wanna hear that.
Guess I'll head to the studio!
kichi
jo
ji
Station
Make sure you remember how to get here.
It gets pretty chaotic around here.
But your school's pretty close,
and there's a ton of places to eat around here.
And— Niizuma?
Niizuma, you're going the wrong way!
Niizuma!
The boring everyday gets to me sometimes,
BETAAna genjitsu ni tsubusaretemo
but I always get back on my feet, standing strong
uchinomesareta jibun hiroiatsumete
No matter how many times the end approaches me,
nando owari ga otazuneretemo
I'll push my own back forward, keeping me on my feet
sono tabi ni jibun de jibun no senaka otoshita
If I get lost in the meaning of continuing what I do,
tsudzuiteku imi ni nayami
I'll rid myself of those worries and keep myself going forward
sono mayoi sae tachikitte yuku
Always
itsumo
The straight edge that draws the outline of my future
mirai no rinkakusen egaku massuguna jougi wa
is made of all the courage I've mustered up until today
ikutsumo no kinou no yuuki de dekiteru
I'll climb over the tall wall that I never thought I'd face,
omoiegaita no to chigau takaikabe koe
and continue my journey, going past the vanishing point
shoushitsuten no mukou e susunde
This winding road seems to never end,
harukanaru winding road
but it is the road I personally chose
hoka no daredemonai watashi ga jibun de eranda
I set my tiny dreams on fire,
kasukana yume wo zenbu moyashita
and broke through the dark with its light
sono hikaru de yami wo saite
Now that I've broken down the wall,
kudaita kabe no mukou ni
I can see my sky once more
jibun no sora ga mieru
Next
Episode
Hey, Takagi, let's go on a date after school tod—
Can't.
Then tomorrow?
Nope.
We're starting our next work!
But Takagi!
Next time, 10 and 2.
10 and
I have a dream to become a mangaka!