I've said this again and again,
but there's really no reason to get
serialized while you're still in high school.
Niizuma is doing it, isn't he?
And he's working by himself.
Fine, but with two conditions.
Conditions?
One, you submit this as a one-shot for the
next "Golden Future Cup" and it does well.
The "Golden Future Cup?"
That's in the summer, right?
And one more thing before that.
You have to bring me a 19 page
story for this series every two weeks.
So this is a rehearsal for actual serialization?
That's right.
Do you usually do this sort of thing?
No.
But this is how I want to do it this time.
If you can't do this much, there's no way
you can do it while still in high school.
I'm sorry, but you guys are not Niizuma.
And writing a detective manga is completely
different than writing a battle manga.
And even if you don't get this serialized,
it will be a good experience for you.
Thank you very much.
We'll definitely show you we can do this
and then get serialized for sure.
I may have lost to you guys in "Next,"
but I'll beat you for sure this time, Ashirogi Muto.
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Literature and Music
The curry's done.
Thanks.
I thought I was gonna die of starvation.
This looks great.
It's cold!
I made chilled curry this time.
No, it's just gotten cold.
Hey, I put a lot of time and effort into this.
I had to dissolve the soup
stock and the curry powder
and put in a bunch of meat and onions.
It was a lot of work.
Mashiro, have some curry.
You're not going to eat?
No, I'll have some.
Miho said she got another new part.
Really? That's great.
Sounds like she's doing well.
I got a message about it.
Mashiro, at least stop while you're eating.
Tomorrow is the deadline.
He's gotta finish up by the end of the day.
But we just had midterms and there
haven't been any holidays lately.
They won't even extend the deadline by one day?
A deadline's a deadline.
You got into the contest, but you
can't relax and celebrate, can you?
What's wrong?
No, I just realized we're going to be in Jack.
When I imagine not getting any votes and
not getting first in the "Golden Future Cup,"
I get really nervous.
The winner is determined based on
who's is the most interesting, right?
How many other series are there?
Oh, I forgot to ask.
Should I call Hattori and ask?
Don't worry.
We can ask him tomorrow.
You think you'll make it in time?
As long as I don't sleep.
As long as you don't sleep?
Didn't you say you didn't
sleep at all yesterday, too?
You didn't either.
Being a mangaka means dedicating
yourself to drawing, even if it kills you.
Man, I didn't think I was gonna make it.
Good work.
Oh no!
What this?
Didn't you say you didn't
like Koogy not too long ago?
Yeah, but I guess he is pretty cool after all.
I'm actually going to his concert tonight.
Really?!
Did you think about what to do for the next chapter?
How'd you get tickets?!
A little bit.
I'll have something ready by the end of the day.
Hey, are you okay?
I'll be fine.
We've still got three months left until the results
of the "Golden Future Cup" are announced.
And we've got to do a 19 page
chapter every two weeks until then.
That means six more chapters.
If we can't do at least that much,
then there's no way we'll be able to keep
up a serialization while still in high school.
I know.
We've already made it this far, so we can't—
Huh? Nakai?
Eh?
You mean that really good
assistant you were talking about?
Yeah.
The one who was crying
about wanting to get serialized?
Well it sure looks like spring has come.
No, it's probably just a meeting or something.
I don't think somebody that young
and cute could be an editor, do you?
Now that you mention it,
she does kinda look like Iwase.
That's not what I meant.
Hm?
Mashiro?
Long time, no see.
Crap, he saw us.
You here for a meeting about the "Golden Future Cup?"
Why is that bad?
I don't know, it just is.
Yeah.
We've got a meeting at six.
Six?
You still have about 15 minutes.
Why don't you join us for a bit?
Or do you not want to talk
to a "Golden Future Cup" rival?
Eh?
You got accepted, too?
Let me introduce you.
This is the runner-up in last
year's "Story King," Aoki Ko.
She's didn't have anybody to do the art for her,
so I agreed to draw it for
the "Golden Future Cup."
I've been looking for somebody to do the drawings
for the runner up in the latest "Story King."
I see.
This is Mashiro. We worked together on "Crow"
So that's who she is.
for a little while and I taught him all sorts of things.
Oh—
I really did learn a lot working with Nakai.
Oh, stop it.
So that would make you Mashiro's partner?
I'm Takagi.
Nice to meet you.
These two are Ashirogi Muto.
So you're Ashirogi?
You did "Money and Intelligence."
I didn't think it was any good.
She sure is blunt.
It didn't feel like it should
be in a shounen magazine.
It was too serious.
Excuse me, but what kind
of stories do you write?
Don't go getting angry.
If I had to categorize them, I
would have to say they are fantasy.
I was writing for a shoujo
magazine called Magnolia,
Note: "Magnolia" refers to "Margaret," Shueisha's bi-weekly shoujo magazine.
but they told me that a fantasy like this
was better suited to a shounen magazine.
Yeah.
I can't say anything about the story yet,
but it's a good, lighthearted fantasy.
I was introduced to Jack and ended
up submitting just the story.
My drawings weren't right for a shounen manga.
But she can draw really cute female characters.
Aoki will be doing the female
faces and I'll do the rest myself.
I'm putting my career as a manga
artist on the line with this manga.
If this doesn't work out, I'm either going to be
an assistant forever or go back to my hometown!
His career?
I thought he hadn't even debuted yet.
Although, I didn't expect to be up
against you guys and Fukuda, though.
Oh,
Fukuda made it in as well?
Yeah, but I'm not going to lose.
Although it looks like the editing
department is betting on him.
What?
Do they really expect him to be number one?
Have you not heard the order of the stories yet?
The order?
We haven't even heard the
names of the other entries yet.
There are a total of four entries.
The 37/38 combined issue is
Fukuda Shinta's "Kiyoshi Knight."
Issue 39 is your "Shady Detective Trap."
Issue 40 is our "Hideout Door."
And issue 41 is Makaino Koji's "Colorfusical."
They always run the one they expect to win first.
You mean the order isn't random?
It makes sense if you think about it.
That's why they call it the "Golden Future Cup."
They want the readers to
all focus on their top batter.
To name some recent series, "Nurarihyon no Mago"
and "Beelzebub" were both first in
their lineups and ended up winning.
The first one is in an important spot,
but I'm not sure the order after that matter.
I'm not sure we can win against Fukuda.
So he doesn't consider us to be competition, huh?
I read Fukuda's one-shot.
I don't think I've seen anything that
action-packed or energetic in Jack for a while.
He said it came in seventh.
That's already good enough
to submit for serialization.
But he's reworking it to make it even better,
so of course they expect it to do well.
I didn't like that story, either.
It seems like he's trying to portray
how young people are these days,
but I don't think you should use words
like 'drugs' in shounen magazines.
If he really wants to write something like that,
he should do it in a more mature magazine.
Yeah, yeah.
I agree.
I think it's better to have
more carefree series like yours.
"Colorfusical" is the one that won honorable
mentions in the last Tezuka Awards, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Makaino Koji.
That was the one
Makaino Kouji
with the main character who
was going to change the world
by changing the color of objects with his eyes
and people's hearts with his voice, right?
I didn't care for it that much, but I
guess it did well in the questionnaire.
I thought the art was really original, but it felt
like it should be a picture book or a musical.
It was just too surreal.
I liked it.
It was very artistic
and it felt carefree and hopeful.
Yeah, you're right.
Manga's got to give people
dreams and make them optimistic.
Just like ours does.
Crap, it's already after six.
Hello?
Well, we should be leaving.
Yeah, we'll be right there.
Alright then, let's both do our best.
Right.
Don't go too hard on us.
Alright, see you later.
I don't want my story to lose to somebody like her.
And he didn't even pay for our coffee.
I am worried about those two, though.
Yeah, they're going to be strong competition.
She was the runner-up in "Story King" and Nakai's
backgrounds and techniques are really good.
That's not what I mean.
Nakai likes Aoki, don't you think?
Yeah, it sure seems that way.
Right?
I'm worried that he'll just end up
doing whatever she tells him to do.
Either way, it's none of our business.
Besides, it's her story.
She's the lead, so that shouldn't matter.
I guess.
We should be worrying more about our own story.
Good, you finished another one in under two weeks.
The story and the drawings both look good.
I guess we should move on
to the next chapter, then.
I brought in an idea I have.
No.
Let's talk about you two getting serialized.
Eh?
Wait—
You mean—
Yeah, you got into the "Golden Future Cup," so
we should get you prepared for serialization.
Does that mean we don't have to do
a chapter every two weeks anymore?
You two have already proven yourselves.
You should start focusing your
energy on getting serialized now.
That okay with you?
Yeah.
Thank you.
We'll do our best.
Crap, thinking about not having to draw
makes me realize just how exhausted I am.
The last few weeks must have been tough.
We finally got permission to do this,
so I can't afford to collapse here.
Yeah, but if we can't do this,
there's no way we could keep up a serialization.
So you're going to submit our story
to the next serialization meeting
if we get first in the "Golden Future Cup," right?
Yeah.
Coming out on top would of course be great,
but it's okay even if you don't get first.
What?!
The questionnaire cards in the issues of Jack
that have "Golden Future Cup" entries in them
are slightly different than usual.
They have an extra option where you
can either 'like' or 'not like' the entry.
Right.
We look at both the story's overall rank
and whether or not people say they liked it.
Um—
Is that just for fairness reasons?
Yeah.
The different entries aren't
published in the same issue,
so it's possible that two series' overall ranks could be the same
or be affected by that issue's
regularly running series.
That's why we have this other option.
So even if we end up with one series with a
high 'like' percentage, but a low overall rank
and another with a low 'like'
percentage, but a high overall rank,
the editing department considers both and
has to decide on which one is the final winner.
Um—
Yeah?
About the 'like' percentage—
Don't you think the first series to
get published is at a big advantage?
A lot of readers are just going to
be comparing all the other entries
to the first one to decide on
whether to 'like' or 'dislike' it.
I've never really thought about it
before, but you're probably right.
The fact that you thought of that so quickly means
you really do have the makings of an excellent writer.
You can definitely do a solid detective series.
Is he lying to me?
So that's why you don't
necessarily have to come in first.
There are plenty of series like "Muhyo and
Ryoji's Bureau of Supernatural Investigation"
that didn't come in first and were still serialized.
I've only read the names,
but to be honest, it's hard to say
which entry is going to win this time.
To be frank though,
you should think of having an
entry in the "Golden Future Cup"
at the same as getting a one-shot published.
If it does well and you have an
interesting name for serialization,
you'll have a chance at getting it serialized.
But again, I really do hope you two get first.
Everyone else is working hard.
However, nobody else is as prepared
for serialization as you two are.
Personally, I absolutely don't want you to
lose to something like this "Colorfusical."
"Colorfusical?"
I liked it.
Why is that?
Oh, never mind me.
Just pretend like you didn't hear that.
Is it that good?
No, it really was just me talking to myself.
We'll get first.
I want to get first, get this
serialized, and catch up to Niizuma Eiji!
Niizuma, huh?
He really is a genius.
His popularity is holding steady.
With just his first three volumes, he's
already sold over two million copies.
Not even the editing department
thought he'd do this well.
The reprintings can't keep up.
Two million.
The author gets 40 yen for each volume sold.
Two million copies at 40 yen each—
Woah!
Cut it out.
It looks like he's already got
an offer for an anime, as well.
An anime, huh?
Azuki's already got roles and is doing well, too.
Alright then.
Let's aim for first place!
Saying that I'd be satisfied with
anything less was too pessimistic.
I want you guys to catch up to—
No, to overtake Niizuma, too.
The first time you guys brought in a story,
I told my team leader—
So how'd it go with that middle school pair?
No good, at least for the time being.
Not everybody can be Niizuma Eiji.
However, I think that in three years, they'll have overtaken Niizuma Eiji.
And I still think the same thing now.
Hattori—
We may not make it in three years,
but we'll make sure to overtake him someday.
Alright, let's do this.
That's the spirit.
Just make sure to put that passion into the story.
And once you're finished, we'll work on
fine-tuning your names for serialization.
Right!
Man, I'm sure glad we ended
up with Hattori as our editor.
Don't you think?
Fukuda, the one who the editing
department expects to win.
Nakai and Aoki with their amazing art.
And Makaino Koji with his
totally unique concept.
We definitely have no shortage of competition.
DON'T BE AFRAID
Come here, if you leave my side
oide soba kara hanarechau to
you'll be devoured.
kuwareru
SHALL WE DANCE?
in Hell.
jigoku de
If it feels like we're in paradise, your eyes open.
rakeun wo kanjitara me mezamechau
Hey,
nee
If you don't like it, if you want out
iya nara taijyou shitara
YOU—
YOU
still cannot leave.
demo hanarennai
DEEP INTO
THE MIXTURE OF CHAOS
That extacy is
sou ekusutashii ga
DEEP INTO it, and the SOUND is circling.
DEEP INTO mou SOUND ga megutte
It's melting apart.
tokedashichau
As you all know
I have so far been successful in a variety of fields.
Acting, writing, fashion design.
I want to express myself in
ways other than just music.
That desire has not dwindled.
It still burns brightly even now.
And it continues to get stronger.
It's like it's overflowing and
there's nothing I can do about it.
There is something I wish to tell you tonight.
Will you listen?
That was a magnificent concert.
It gives me pride as your producer.
Koogy.
Hyde.
I'll be waiting here for you.
And I'll be sure to come back successful.
Excuse me.
And you are?
My name's Uchida.
I'm an editor at Yueisha.
Hello?
Have you seen today's paper?!
N—No, not yet.
You need to read it now!
The TV's fine too.
Jeez, if you're planning on becoming a mangaka,
then at least glance through the
paper first thing in the morning.
Uh, right. Sorry.
First thing?
You just woke me up—
Announces Sudden Hiatus!
There is something I wish to tell you tonight.
Will you listen?
Announces Sudden Hiatus!
After this concert, I will be
taking a break from music.
And I, Makaino Koji, will become a mangaka.
Makaino Koji?
Yeah, "Colorfusical's" writer is the singer Koogy.
He's playing dirty.
I'm going to be in Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer
He's planning to get his fans to fill out the questionnaire for him.
I'm pissed off.
and continue to broaden my horizons.
I'm thinking about going to the office and protesting.
Everyone, I look forward to your support!
Announces Sudden Hiatus!
Nakai said he'd go too.
I'm fine going on my own, but—
You guys should come too.
Nakai said that you two are in
the "Golden Future Cup" as well,
so I should at least mention it to you.
You want to come?
We have school today.
What time can you come?
If you're coming, we can wait.
Let me talk to Takagi about it first.
Gotcha.
Let me know by this afternoon.
Right.
I agree with Fukuda.
The timing of his announcement is a cheap trick.
Yeah, his fans'll definitely fill
out the questionnaire for him.
The winner of the "Golden Future Cup" would
be in the best position for getting serialized.
We want to get first, right?
Let's go.
Yeah!
Don't you think you should have waited
until you're serialized to
make a public announcement?
If I'm gonna tell the world, now's the best time.
That way my fans will all vote for
me on those questionnaire thingies.
I don't think it'll be that easy—
My drawings are this good.
Manga.
It's so perfect.
I'll succeed in a multitude of
mediums and become a true star.
Everybody's here then, yeah?
We can't let Koogy get away with this.
How can they consent to something like this?
We'll teach the editing department a thing or two.
Team Fukuda,
move out!
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
An attack on the editing department?
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Next
Episode
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Aoki, I'm going to be
resolute and protest this action.
Don't you have something else
you should be doing right now?
You're right, Aoki.
Next time: Solidarity and Breakdown
Solidarity and
Breakdown
Nothing will stand between me and my dreams.