Don't you think you should have waited
until you're serialized to
make a public announcement?
If I'm gonna tell the world, now's the best time.
That way my fans will all vote for
me on those questionnaire thingies.
I'll succeed in a multitude of
mediums and become a true star.
The timing of his announcement is a cheap trick.
Yeah, his fans'll definitely fill
out the questionnaire for him.
The winner of the "Golden Future Cup" would
be in the best position for getting serialized.
We want to get first, right?
Let's go.
Everybody's here then, yeah?
We can't let Koogy get away with this.
How can they consent to something like this?
We'll teach the editing department a thing or two.
Team Fukuda,
move out!
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Solidarity and Breakdown
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Please check in
at the reception
desk.
Yueisha
Excuse me,
but may I inquire as to the
reason of your visit today?
I'm terribly sorry, but this
building is not open to the public.
If you have a meeting, please
check in with the receptionist.
We've got business with Jack's editing department.
Don't worry, we'll be sure to properly check in.
Oh, I apologize.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
What was up with that security guard?
He sure got quiet.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
I'm sure it's because your
sincerity got through to him.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
Guest Pass Return Box
Please be sure to return your
visitor's pass upon leaving.
You're probably right.
Please have a seat in booth number one.
Thanks.
Welcome.
May I ask what your business is today?
Give me a visitor registration form, please.
Right. P—Please fill this in.
Thanks.
Hey, who here's got the most senior editor?
Huh? Hm—
Probably Aoki's editor, Aida.
He's the team leader.
We could always go straight
to the chief editor, too.
We're here to see Weekly Jack's Aida.
So he's asking for Aida—
If he's not available, then Hattori Akira.
And if he's not here either, then Hattori Yujiro.
Um, Just a moment, please.
Hi, this is Aida.
Huh?
Yes.
Mr. Fukuda, Mr. Nakai, and
Mr. Ashirogi are here to see you.
All the entries for the "Golden Future Cup," huh?
This must be about the Koogy thing.
Send them up, please.
Hattori! Yujiro!
We've got trouble on the way!
Huh?
They've sure got some
nerve letting Koogy compete.
We can't let the "Golden Future Cup"
turn into some lame popularity contest.
Right.
We're all pouring our souls into our manga.
That's right!
You just wait, Jack editing department!
All of them?
Yeah, and I'm sure you can guess why.
Yeah.
Looks like things are about to get noisy.
Evenin'!
Excuse us!
It's nice to be young, isn't it?
One of them isn't so young, though.
Fukuda, hold on a minute.
We're not here to talk to you.
At least let us talk to—
Don't be ridiculous!
You'll talk to me.
This is cheating, isn't it?
So it was about that.
It's Koogy, so he's going to have a few
votes in the bag already then, isn't he?
Every time he releases a new song,
his CD sales and even online
downloads hit top three in all the charts.
Personally, I absolutely don't want you to
lose to something like this "Colorfusical."
So that means Hattori knew this
was going to happen, huh?
He's putting his music career
on hiatus to draw manga.
I don't think it's cheating at all.
Actually, I think his fans will want him to
keep writing music instead of drawing manga.
If his manga isn't any good,
he's gonna be in trouble.
He's prepared to take that risk.
Then why is he making this announcement now?!
Isn't he just doing it to get
the support of all his fans?
He printed a comment asking for support
and it even says he's advertising
himself on a bunch of music shows.
It's the same as a celebrity
running in an election, isn't it?!
And what's the problem with that?
Even if that is the case, a manga
artist's job is based on his popularity.
Here, the most popular person wins.
That's bullshit!
Are you telling me you think it's
fair to do anything to get votes?!
Hey, I'm a pacifist!
I agree with Fukuda!
It doesn't feel like we're competing
with the content of our stories anymore.
I'm pouring everything I
have into my manga this time.
This is my last chance.
I'm already 33!
If you don't like it, then
just drop out of the contest!
The contest entries haven't been announced yet.
Koogy is the one you should
be dropping from the contest!
It's already all over the news that he's
in the contest, so we can't do that!
So you're saying you'd be fine
with all three of us dropping out?
Can you still have the contest if that happens?
Wait, Fukuda, I don't really want to drop out.
What are you doing backing down now, Nakai?!
We can't just chicken out.
Y—Yeah, but—
There are plenty of other
entries we can choose from.
A lot of newcomers are just
waiting for their big chance.
You're just patronizing us, aren't you?
If you want to take it that way, go right ahead.
The only thing that matters to us is
that the readers enjoy our product.
Manga just needs to be interesting.
If it is, then of course it'll be serialized.
Fukuda.
We're not dropping out.
Huh?
All we have to do is win, right?
Just win with your story!
Manga just needs to be interesting.
If it is, then it'll be serialized.
Even if Koogy manages to win because
his fans fill out the questionnaire,
it would be a false victory.
We'll know if we win or lose
based on the quality of our story.
So, that means we just have to write a story
that won't lose to his and that'll be enough.
Even if you're just trying to sound cool,
you're still right!
It's a battle of manga.
We'll pound this Makaino Koji or
Koogy or whoever into the ground!
Alright, let's all check out each other's names.
Eh?!
We'll all give each other feedback
to make our stories better.
Just like that time with chapter five of "Crow."
That isn't cheating.
We may be rivals, but we're
also partners in this, right?
What do you say?
Hattori, can we get a copy of our name?
Sure.
Niizuma Eiji
Hey, Niizuma.
Is it alright if I bring Ashirogi back to your place to
have a strategy meeting for the "Golden Future Cup?"
Ashirogi-sensei? Of course they're welcome to come!
Come on! Welcome!
Alright, we'll see you soon, then.
Roger.
Yeah.
So we all ended up deciding
to give each other feedback.
Huh?
Fukuda, it's okay if Aoki comes too, right?
Obviously.
Sorry about that.
He says that he would be delighted
if you would be so kind as to join us.
Alright, we'll see you soon.
Here's your name.
I made enough copies for everyone.
Thank you.
Don't worry.
I'm sure the readers will judge based on the story.
Good luck.
Right!
Thank you.
Ashirogi, you ready?
Y—Yeah.
Team Fukuda, we're heading out.
Sorry to have caused a scene.
Excuse us.
Sure are a bunch of troublemakers, aren't they?
Yeah, but if you don't have at least that much
passion, you can't become a popular mangaka.
Yeah, you've got that right.
kichi
jo
ji
Station
You were right. The billboard is blank.
In Development
The news was true. I can't believe it.
But Koogy is still Koogy.
I'll support him.
He really is popular.
Yeah, but still—
That Koogy bastard.
He's not taking manga seriously.
There's no way I'm losing to him!
Sorry, everybody.
It looks like Aoki is going to be a bit late.
Go on ahead.
Gotcha.
Oh, could you get some drinks and snacks ready?
And try and clean the room up a bit, too.
Maybe you should take all the trash out, too—
Nakai has totally lost sight of our goal.
This isn't some play date.
Things sure took a strange turn, didn't they?
We went in to talk about Koogy and
ended up having a feedback meeting?
If we can make our story better by
sharing ideas, then it's fine with me.
Yeah, but they're all still our rivals.
Niizuma
Niizuma is busy working, so let's use this room.
Right.
It's pretty messy, but just sit wherever you want.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
I thought our studio was pretty nice,
but this place is pretty impressive too.
Yeah.
This is my first time in this room, too.
Mangakas studios are all
bound to look similar, aren't they?
Oh, let me help you.
Why don't you set out your names?
P—Please, come on in.
Looks like they're here.
We're coming in.
You've already met Ashirogi so I
guess that just leaves Fukuda, huh?
This is Aoki Ko, the writer
of the story I'll be drawing.
Nice to meet you.
He also works with me as an assistant for Niizuma.
So this is the runner up for "Story King"—
I'd heard she was a girl,
And he's one of the participants in the "Golden Future Cup."
but just what kind of story is she writing?
Hi.
Aoki, please have a seat.
Oh, and there are drinks as well.
I apologize for it being so cramped.
Don't worry about it.
Everybody settled in?
Let's start by taking a look at each other's names.
My "Kiyoshi Knight."
Nakai and Aoki's "Hideout Door."
And Ashirogi Muto's "Shady Detective Trap."
When we're finished reading all of
them, we'll give our opinion on each.
Don't hold anything back.
Be straightforward and say whatever comes to mind.
Alright, let's get started.
Excuse me!
This looks like fun. May I join you?
This is Niizuma-sensei.
Nice to meet you.
Likewise.
Niizuma, what about your work?
I'm finished.
And I'm sure this will be a
great learning experience for me.
I would like to help out!
Whatcha think?
I'd like Niizuma to take a look at ours.
Yeah.
What about you?
I have no objections.
Then I'm fine with it too.
Alright then, let's get
Niizuma-sensei's opinion as well, then.
Thank you.
Alright, let's get to it.
Right.
This is the story I almost
ended up drawing the art for.
I wonder what kind of story it is.
This is bad. Aoki Ko is better than I thought.
It almost feels like I'm
watching a movie or something.
It's just a story about a boy who meets a fairy and
decides that he wants to become a fairy himself.
I didn't expect the runner up
of "Story King" to be this good.
What the hell is this?
This story gives me the creeps.
I don't get it at all.
Although, it's something that isn't in Jack right now.
Are they considering that as well?
And I can't forget about Nakai's skill.
If he can represent this world right—
Fukuda said he was going to redo his one-shot
that came in seventh with the same characters,
but this is almost completely different.
And we don't have anywhere
near this level of humor.
This is really good.
It feels like a modern version of "Otokojyuku."
The action scenes are full of feeling and
the comedy makes you laugh out loud.
I'd say his drawings are the worst here,
but they fit well with the story's rough style.
This story is way better than mine.
It looks like Mashiro was right when
he said this guy could become a writer.
So my real competition this
time is Ashirogi Muto, huh?
I guess that calling these two "15 year
old geniuses" wasn't an exaggeration.
And it's not just the story,
the art is outstanding, too.
It's still just the name, but he's even
drawing the characters in detailed poses.
And the panel organization is great, too.
When this is finished, it's
going to be really impressive.
And this guy over here—
Exciting!
Alright, shall we move on to the critique?
I refuse.
What?!
And why exactly is that?
I believe my story is the best one here,
so doing so would be meaningless.
If you'd like to continue, do so without me.
You think this fluffy let's eat a giant chocolate cake
in a house made of candy surrounded
by a field of flowers story is the best?
Personally, I thought it sucked!
Fukuda—
You're wrong. Mine is the best.
Yours is just full of filthy language.
That's because it's a shounen manga!!
Well, I'll just take that as
your critique then, shall I?
I've already been told to tone it
down and redraw this six times.
They keep getting more and more
strict about what you can write.
But even when I say that, they tell me not to
compare things now with manga in the past.
I think it's better to have more
shounen manga like this out there.
It's not like they're textbooks
or some kind of holy book.
It's more interesting if parents are against it.
F—Fukuda, you don't have to be so—
But that's fine.
I thought my story was the best one here as well.
Mashiro, you guys thought
yours was the best too, right?
Yeah, I guess.
Overall, yeah.
So I guess that means this critique is useless, then.
Huh?!
If you have faith in your own story,
there is no need to continue.
Yes, I agree with Aoki.
And my manga will not lose to "Colorfusical."
Eh?
You mean our manga, right?
Alright, we stop here!
Eh?
Fukuda—
It's just like Miss Aoki here said.
Just have faith in your own story.
It's great that everybody
thinks they're going to be first.
And we all agree that we don't
need anybody else's opinion.
That's right.
It's not just Koogy.
Everyone here is a rival.
Since we're already here, why don't
we at least listen to Niizuma's opinion,
because he's the only neutral person here.
Hm, I thought they were all fantastic.
But which one do you think was the most interesting?
Violence.
Suspense.
Fairy-tale.
Everybody's stories are so different,
but if I were to put them in order
of which one I liked the most—
W—Wait a second!
Yes?
I kinda feel like if Niizuma-sensei
says anything, then it'll come true.
I'm confident, so that's fine with me.
Eh?!
I'm confident as well
Same here.
So I can say it?
Yeah.
I've decided on who's third, but
the other two are tied for first.
I'd feel kinda bad for the person in
third, so I won't say any more than that.
A tie?
Why can't you just pick one?
I truly believe that it is a tie for first place.
If that's all you're going to say
then there was no point asking in the first place.
But it really is a tie.
Whatever.
Either way, we'll find out two months
from now when the results are announced.
Will the winner of the "Golden Future
Cup" be somebody sitting here?
Or will it be Koogy?
I'm going home.
Eh?
Oh, Aoki, I'll walk you to the station.
Saiko, we should get going, too.
Saiko?
Oh, yeah.
Good work everybody.
I'm looking forward to reading the finished versions.
Guess there wasn't much point to all that, huh?
Everybody already thinks theirs is the best.
I guess if you didn't, you wouldn't
be trying to be a mangaka.
What's wrong? You've been quiet since we left.
Which two stories were tied for first?
Oh, that's what's bothering you?
Fukuda and Nakai's stories are both
better than I thought they would be.
Yeah, but we're not going to lose.
We can't be sure of that yet!
But that's just Eiji's personal opinion.
The real decision will be made by
the questionnaire and a meeting.
Koogy already has a huge
advantage in the questionnaire.
And Koogy already got an honorable
mention in the Tezuka Award.
If he's giving up music just to write
manga, we have no idea how it'll turn out.
But there's no time left before the deadline.
We can change a few things while
we're doing the final manuscript.
Okay?
Alright.
Don't worry.
I'm sure the readers will judge based on the story.
St. Viz Girls Culture Festival
Performer's Dressing Room
The Underclassmen
What?!
Is says that Koogy is going on hiatus!
That's too bad. I really liked him.
Yeah, his announcement
yesterday sure was a surprise.
He said that he's going to be a mangaka.
He claimed that his story is going to
rock the foundation of the manga world.
Really?
He said he's going to be in
Shounen Jack's "Something-Cup,"
so he asked for everybody's support.
Do you mean the "Golden Future Cup?"
Yeah, that's the one.
But it's a bit unfair, don't you think?
It's only a day after the announcement,
but he already has all these fliers ready.
What's wrong with that?
I like him so I'll support him.
And when he gets an anime,
I will try out for the heroine.
Momo-chan, you just want to meet him, don't you?
But I'm a fan too, so I guess I'll cheer him on.
Then let's all three try out together.
Miho-chan too.
Okay?
Eh?
S—Sure—
It's almost time, so if you'd please get ready.
Okay.
Let's make this a success.
Yeah!
We've gotta do our best for all of our fans!
New Ending
Launch Event
St. Visual's Girls Academy Culture Festival
Wow! It's all boys!
Yeah—
Sorry to keep you all waiting.
Looks like it's about to start.
Please welcome the "St. Viz Girls" choir.
The Underclassmen!!
G—Good afternoon everyone.
Thank you all for joining us here today.
Miho sure is nervous.
Miho-chan, just relax.
Shall we get started?
Onee, good luck.
P—Please enjoy the show.
This is "The Daybreak Symphony."
Do you want to say it or will you hold back?
Please don't hide all the feelings deep in your heart.
It hits you even harder when you listen to it live.
Onee!
Let them all out.
I'm lonely and I want to see you.
I'm so sad that I might break.
I just can't watch anymore!
You can't look away now.
I want you to look only at me.
Miho's up there doing her best.
Into my heart, never wavering.
Your touch, your gaze, your body.
My heart aches just looking at you.
What are you waiting for—
Hey, you two. Take a look at this!
Woah!
When did you take this?!
There was a "St. Viz Girls" event today in Akihabara.
I made her take this afterward.
Why didn't you say anything about it?
Azuki told me not to say anything
about it because she was embarrassed.
She's already been on TV, so what's the big deal?
Takagi, you just don't
understand a woman's feelings.
You're not gonna be able to come up
with a cute manga heroine that way.
Oh, mind your own business.
Miho really did great.
Her singing still isn't that great,
but when she was speaking, she did
her best to get the audience excited.
She spoke about ten times
more than she usually does.
Really?
Even though she used to always be so shy.
Yeah.
Everybody there liked her.
Who's it from?
Azuki.
Eh?
Don't tell her I showed you that picture, okay?
She'll get mad at me.
You're always doing stuff like this, aren't you?
Azuki Miho
It'll be okay!
I heard about the Koogy thing. Don't worry, I'm sure
that you guys will get first in the "Golden Future Cup."
FIGHT!!
What'd she say?
She said she believes we can get
first in the "Golden Future Cup."
Is that so?
Sorry, Shuujin.
Huh?
I'm going to rewrite the name after all!
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
Saiko, are you serious about rewriting the name?
Next
Episode
Eh?! Do you have time for that?
But if we don't do that, we
won't be able to beat the others.
Really? Then I'll be cheering you on.
Tuesday and
Friday
Next time: Tuesday and Friday.
Everybody's dreams are coming together at last!