Finally—
I can't believe we're bringing in a
manuscript while we're still in middle school.
Anyone can bring a manuscript in.
What matters is how much they like it.
Yeah.
I'm Hattori, an editor for Shounen Jack.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too!
Let's get started right away. Could
you show me your manuscript?
Y—Yes.
Thank you.
Tea means we pass!
He's going to trash our work!
I feel like I'm on trial.
Tea! Tea! Tea! Tea!
Tea!
What's the verdict?!
This is very well-done.
I'm gonna submit this for our monthly
prize if that's alright with you.
Huh?
By monthly prize, you mean the prize that's
awarded each month to a selected submission?
Is this going to win?
It's not that easy.
Predicting what'll be a hit is pretty much a gamble.
That was a success, right?
Even though it was our first
manuscript, we got an email address—
What'd you think, Shuujin?
About what?
I think Mr. Hattori's a good editor.
How were those two middle schoolers?
Not good enough. At least right now.
Not everyone can be a Niizuma Eiji, huh?
But he's only been using a pen for two months.
The script's still not quite up to
par, but the idea itself is original—
Be sure to raise them well since you like them.
I think they'll have surpassed
Niizuma Eiji in three years.
I wanna finish another story
before the end of the year.
And this time, he won't say
it should be a light novel.
Yeah, I'm gonna work on the things he
mentioned and make some amazing illustrations.
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Every worry floats up to and fills the spring sky
shinpaigoto bakari ga tsumoru haru no sora wo
I look up, look down,
miagete utsumuite
and find myself looking back up at the sky
mata kao wo ageteru
I swore I'd find myself in this town
kono machi de mitsukerutte kimeta jibun
I tuck away all my important things into my heart for safekeeping
nakushicha ikenai mono wo mune ni
Your love
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Tears and Tears
Morning!
'Sup.
Did you get the name done?
I'm not that good yet.
Aren't we gonna make something more solid before the year ends?
I know!
Last one!
Yes, sir!
So, have you gotten used to sitting next to Azuki?
Well, the tension doesn't make me sick anymore—
You really got sick?
But doesn't sitting next to your
love make you overflow with joy?
Well, it does, but—
Then that's all there is to it.
Note!
Note this.
And this.
Note this too.
Peck
Peeck
Don't forget it.
Now, on to the next page.
I got Azuki to laugh!
Can I talk to her like this?
What's your favorite season?
1. Spring
2. Summer
3. Fall
4. Winter
Three!
Fall!
Her favorite season?
Are you a little kid?!
What else did you ask?
Her favorite color, food—
What?!
Azuki likes rice omelet.
So I told her I like curry—
Did you really—
Your relationship is so boring.
Don't you have anything interesting to ask?
Leave me alone; I'm happy.
Fine.
Are we doing another sci-fi action?
Yeah, that's what I'm thinking.
I figured it'd be better to do another sci-fi.
How so?
Then we can easily see how much we've
improved compared to the last one.
Oh, I see.
By the way, he said he'd submit "The
Two Earths" for the monthly prize, right?
Yeah.
I'm gonna submit this for our
monthly prize if that's alright with you.
Huh?
By monthly prize, you mean the prize that's
awarded each month to a selected submission?
Is this going to win?
It's not that easy.
But people have different tastes,
so maybe someone will consider this a finalist.
It'd be pretty awesome if our
first manga becomes a finalist!
I don't think it's that easy—
But—
If we do become a finalist, I'll tell Azuki.
Yujiro, we're going.
C—Coming!
Looks like the editor-in-chief himself
is going to Niizuma Eiji's home.
Is he really going to let
a high schooler go pro?
He got second in the readers' choice
awards for the last Tezuka semi-finals.
He's the first 15 year old to do that.
Furthermore, he turns in a new work
for the Tezuka Award every month,
and all of them are interesting.
People are saying he'll take all
the Tezuka Awards at this rate.
That's amazing.
It sure is.
If he can write something
monthly while going to school,
he can write a weekly series with a few assistants.
"Prodigy High Schooler!"
That'll definitely catch some attention.
I heard he also wants to serialize.
So the editor-in-chief himself
is going to talk to his parents?
I'm impressed.
That's the middle school pair's manuscript, right?
I'm still not sure about this.
I told the two of them that I'll turn it in for
the monthly contest, but I'm not really sure.
Hey, Hattori, Kime!
Our group's doing the monthly contest
selection this month, so let's get it over with!
Okay, Captain.
Hattori, hurry up and submit that
middle school pair's manuscript!
R—Right!
Aida sure sounds motivated.
The Niizuma Eiji business must have lit a fire in him.
Maybe.
Remember what he says all the time?
"Why do you think there are three
groups in the editorial department?"
"It's to compete for the most popular work!"
He'll probably be on my
case if I don't turn this in.
Jack Editor
Hahaha
You two sure look happy.
Man, I hope we never change seats.
How about the protagonist invents a
machine to grant any wish he wants,
and he wishes to sit next to the girl he likes?
His wish comes true, but the machine goes haywire,
and he literally can't get any
closer than sitting next to her.
Then—
Hey, don't walk away from me!
Don't get so mad.
Why wouldn't I get mad?!
Who are they?
Sato and Yamaguchi from class 3.
I need an explanation!
Didn't we promise when we started going out that
we wouldn't keep any secrets from each other?!
They're going out?
How scary—
They've hit a wall.
Why did you change your high school of choice?
We'll be split apart when we graduate!
Love is so difficult.
Don't worry.
Azuki isn't the type to yell at a guy.
That's not it.
Azuki and I—
are going our separate ways once we graduate.
But will we always be like this?
We're so close,
but we don't even talk—
That's a man's life story for you.
Yeah, until our dreams come true, we should
both try our best without meeting each other.
Until then, we can cheer each other on through email.
Do we have to wait until our dreams come true?
Azuki?
Is something wrong?
I'm sorry.
My pet died last night, and—
I understand you're mourning,
but we're in class right now.
I'm sorry.
I trampled on Azuki's feelings about
realizing our dreams together.
I also felt that it'd be like a fantasy—
That's all for today.
Have a nice day.
Her email?!
So you made her cry?
Yeah, but I'm so lost—
What do you mean?
Why'd she give me her email?
You don't know when you two are perfectly in sync?
We're too close, I guess.
I don't really understand girls either,
but I'm sure she was happy since she likes you too.
You told her that you want to cheer each other on
and stuff right now instead of
waiting until our dreams come true.
I'm sure that's why she gave you her email.
I don't think that's quite it.
She cried because—
I think she cried because I tried to break our promise about our dreams—
Well, she gave you her email, so she
must want to talk to you through email.
Miho?
Are you okay?
Kaya.
I heard.
Momo died, right?
She's alive.
But in class, you said your pet died—
I didn't know what I was supposed to do.
I never thought I'd cry either, but—
What? What are you talking about?
I'm in the dark here.
Well, I might tell you about it in the future.
What? Tell me now!
Just tell me everything!
I'll give you advice!
What about you, Kaya?
And Takagi.
Well nothing to report.
He hasn't said anything either.
I'll talk to you about it tomorrow.
Okay.
Well, say hi to Momo for me.
That night—
I'm going to try my best.
I'll definitely become a voice actress,
then I'll voice a character in your anime.
This is so wonderful.
Then after our dreams come true, will you marry me?
We promised, didn't we?
I was—
I was always just watching her from afar,
but now,
we can both look at the same dream.
I might email you after we change seats again.
We'll always be together once I become a mangaka.
Miho!
Well, look at that!
Look at what?
You look much brighter than you did this morning.
Do I?
So what was it that made you cry?
It's all right now.
It looks like my message was well received.
What?
I'm so lost!
What? You made her cry again?
But she was smiling.
So she was crying out of happiness?
Maybe.
Good for you.
Yeah.
I don't want to see her cry ever again.
And I want to talk to you about something.
Nominations for the Tezuka Award are due at the end of September.
Let's put something together for it.
What?
That's not what we agreed on.
Didn't you want to make a solid
manga we can be proud of?
I did, but—
Besides, it's already September 5th.
If I finish the name, will you really
be able to finish drawing it in time?
I'll make it happen!
I can draw one or two pages on school
days and five or six on weekends.
We also have two holidays in
September, so it's definitely possible!
We'll get half of it done by the 13th.
But Mr. Hattori's already willing to evaluate our work.
We don't have to be preoccupied
about the Tezuka Award!
And quality's more important anyway!
We'll have Mr. Hattori look at it!
We'll have him look at it
before the end of the month,
and put it in for the Tezuka Award.
If we want to win the Tezuka Award,
then we should write something that's interesting
instead of churning something out in a rush.
You need to cool down.
Yeah, you're right.
Sorry.
There's nothing wrong about doing things
quickly, but it has to be interesting.
I'm gonna say something selfish here.
Huh? Sure.
Azuki put on a genuine smile when we
told her that we'll be mangakas.
I wanna see that smile one
more time before we graduate.
That smile she made when we made that promise.
So you want to get a Tezuka Award before
we graduate and make Azuki happy?
It's Yueisha!
Hello?
It's Hattori from Weekly Shounen Jack. Is this Takagi?
Yes.
Are you still writing stories?
Y—Yes.
The manuscript I received the other
day didn't quite make it as a finalist.
I figured I should tell you.
I'm sorry, but can you give me a moment?
Our work didn't even make it to the finals.
I see.
Thank you for telling me.
But you both really have what it takes—
That's great.
It is?
Yes.
We'd look lame with our names in a
tiny font on the corner of the page.
Wouldn't wanna show our girlfriends that.
We'll definitely win the next Tezuka Award.
W—Well said.
That's the spirit.
Yeah.
Thank you for the call.
Let's make Azuki happy
with the next Tezuka Award.
What was I even worried about?
I wanted to nurture them, so I almost
decided not to turn their story in.
Do you mean that middle school pair?
They might've gotten thrilled about winning
even the smallest of awards with their first work.
If they couldn't even make it to the
finals, they might've been discouraged.
After talking to them, it looks like
all my worries were for nothing.
So you two have already agreed
to let Eiji come to Tokyo.
Yes.
Niizuma
We'll leave him in your care.
This is great news.
Yeah.
Eiji, people from Shounen Jack are here.
Hi, Niizuma.
I'm Sasaki, and I edi—
Niizuma?
What a room—
I have a condition for going to Tokyo.
A condition?
If I become the most popular mangaka in Jack,
give me the authority to
end one series I don't like.
The boring everyday gets to me sometimes,
BETAAna genjitsu ni tsubusaretemo
but I always get back on my feet, standing strong
uchinomesareta jibun hiroiatsumete
No matter how many times the end approaches me,
nando owari ga otazuneretemo
I'll push my own back forward, keeping me on my feet
sono tabi ni jibun de jibun no senaka otoshita
If I get lost in the meaning of continuing what I do,
tsudzuiteku imi ni nayami
I'll rid myself of those worries and keep myself going forward
sono mayoi sae tachikitte yuku
Always
itsumo
The straight edge that draws the outline of my future
mirai no rinkakusen egaku massuguna jougi wa
is made of all the courage I've mustered up until today
ikutsumo no kinou no yuuki de dekiteru
I'll climb over the tall wall that I never thought I'd face,
omoiegaita no to chigau takaikabe koe
and continue my journey, going past the vanishing point
shoushitsuten no mukou e susunde
This winding road seems to never end,
harukanaru winding road
but it is the road I personally chose
hoka no daredemonai watashi ga jibun de eranda
I set my tiny dreams on fire,
kasukana yume wo zenbu moyashita
and broke through the dark with its light
sono hikaru de yami wo saite
Now that I've broken down the wall,
kudaita kabe no mukou ni
I can see my sky once more
jibun no sora ga mieru
Next
Episode
We're shooting for the Tezuka Award!
I think this may be miraculously interesting!
Even Mr. Hattori said it was good.
Then this—
will definitely make the nominations.
Next time: Uncertainties and Expectations
Iwase Aiko
Takagi Akito
Uncertainties and
Expectations
A dream brings turbulence into your life.