September 10th (Fri)
Here are the real deal results.
I guess the readers came through after all.
Colorfusical
Yeah.
When Fukuda and the others came in
to complain, I had to stand up to them,
but to be honest, I didn't want
someone like Koji to beat us either.
But that would have just made it worse.
This means that the battle for the "Golden
Future Cup" is down to three entries.
"Kiyoshi Knight."
"Hideout Door."
"Shady Detective Trap."
We're not going to lose!
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Call and Eve
The results for the "Golden Future Cup"
are announced in November, right?
Yeah.
The decision is made at the
end of this month, though.
Serialization Name Meeting
September Schedule
This time they're looking at 5000 questionnaires,
so I suppose they have to count all the votes again.
Yeah.
Again?
Huh?
Why do they have to count all the votes again?
They're not really doing it again.
The 5000 vote count is just more
accurate than the real deal tally is.
There's a chance the 'like' percentages
and the overall ranks could change.
I sent in the questionnaire too.
But don't you think it's strange?
They're having the "Golden Future Cup" contest,
so why do you have to be compared
to the other series that are running?
They should just be ranking
the entries against each other.
That's why they have the extra option
to either 'like' or 'not like' the entry.
It's important to know where the entry ranks overall.
It's not a simple decision.
But then isn't it possible to have an entry with
a high 'like' percentage, but a low overall rank?
That's why they have the—
Shuujin!
The name.
We did everything we could.
Right now, we shouldn't worry about the
contest anymore and just focus on the names
for December's serialization meeting.
You're right.
In any case, this way it's easier for the
editing department to make a decision.
They'll have more accurate information.
September 20th (Mon)
What are we supposed to do about this?
"Kiyoshi Knight."
1312 votes.
Third place.
'Like' percentage: 79%.
"Shady Detective Trap."
1321 votes.
Third place.
'Like' percentage: 76%.
"Hideout Door."
1103 votes.
Third place.
'Like' percentage: 73%.
"Colorfusical."
482 votes.
14th place.
'Like' percentage: 53%.
Not including "Colorfusical,"
these are pretty closely matched.
If everyone who selected 'like' also put
the series in their top three favorites
and everyone who selected 'don't like'
didn't, this would be so much easier.
That's why that option is totally unnecessary.
But without it, we can't compare the
series to figure out which is better.
We can't do that now, either.
If we just compare "Kiyoshi" and "Trap,"
I'd say "Trap" wins, since the average
voting age was 14.3 years old.
Yeah, "Kiyoshi's" average of
17.5 years old is too high.
That's more seinen manga
than it is shounen manga.
If you're going to consider things like
that, then in terms of gender ratio,
"Kiyoshi" is clearly the better shounen manga.
When you consider that over 90% of the votes
came from male voters, this rank is really amazing.
Now isn't the time to be looking at the gender ratio.
"Trap" didn't have a very big female fan base
either and it still got more overall votes.
But "Kiyoshi" has a higher 'like' percentage.
And "Hideout Door" isn't out
of the running either, right?
We don't get very many female votes, but
this story managed to get a lot of them.
It's true we don't have anything
like this one in Jack right now.
It's already six o'clock?
It's almost night already!
The meeting still isn't over?
He said he'd call as soon as the
results were announced, didn't he?
Calm down already.
Eh? It's not like I'm beating myself up about it.
Huh? Beating mochi?
Right, right.
Smack! Smack!
Oi!
They're slow—
What's taking so long?! That
Yujiro didn't forget, did he?
I guess that wouldn't be like him—
I—I'm sure it'll probably be
either you or Ashirogi who gets it.
You never know.
Ashirogi and me both got second in the
real deal results and you came in third,
but it wouldn't be all that strange for the
5000 questionnaire results to be different.
Jeez, how many times do they
have to count the votes anyway?
A different result, huh?
But we've already made it this far.
No offense to you, but I'm gonna win this!
No, I'm going to win.
We're gonna win.
It's time!
Hi, this is Fukuda!
Right.
Hello?
And?
The "Golden Future Cup" is— Ours!
We did it!
But guys, listen—
Alright!
It's not just you, Fukuda—
Fukuda-sensei, good job!
What?
There are two winners?!
Right, yours and "Kiyoshi Knight."
The first tie in the contest's history?
Yeah, although this is only
the sixth time we've held it.
At any rate—
Congratulations.
Yeah, we missed it this time, but—
I see.
So that means we can go ahead with this, right?
Thank you so much!
Fukuda, congratulations.
I'm not too happy about having
to share it with Ashirogi, though.
That aside—
I guess Niizuma-sensei's
prediction really came true.
A tie for first place.
I'm more surprised about Niizuma being
right than about the actual first ever tie.
Even if it was a tie, you got first! That's great!
Uh, yeah.
That's great— right?
Yeah.
Although, this means that we'll be up against
Fukuda again in the serialization meeting.
Yeah, and Nakai's will probably be submitted, too.
You guys should stop talking about that.
For now, let's be happy, 'kay?
Oh, sorry.
We are, though.
We are happy.
I guess you could say we're "updating our goals."
Really?
I'm so glad!
I gotta message Azuki.
Stop crying already.
Alright!
I know you're happy, but you don't have to cry.
Yeah, but still—
It's here!
Eh?
Azuki Miho
Golden Future Cup results!
Congratulations!
I don't know your cellphone number either,
but could you give me Takagi's? *lol*
Why does she want Shuujin's and not mine?
I see.
Hm?
Is Hattori calling again?
The popular ones sure are busy.
Huh? It's a number I don't know.
Hello?
This is Azuki.
Eh?! Azuki?!
Eh?!
Aren't you calling the wrong person?
Takagi, thank you.
Eh?
S—Sorry, I'm going out onto the veranda.
What? Why?!
What are you thanking me for?
I've wanted to thank you properly for a while now.
Mashiro and I are always
saying that if it weren't for you,
middle school graduation would have been
the end of our feelings for each other.
Do you really think so?
All I did was ask Saiko to help me out with my
dream of wanting to become a manga writer.
It's thanks to that dream.
Mashiro says that if you
hadn't asked him to help you,
he probably would have just been drifting
through every day without any sort of goal.
He said that you were the
one who gave him his dream.
I told him that he should tell you himself,
but he said it's embarrassing for
guys to talk about that kind of stuff.
Is that so?
We're still not sure if deciding
to become mangakas
will turn out to be a good
thing or a bad thing yet, though.
I don't think anything bad can come out of
you doing your best to achieve your dreams.
You're right.
There's nothing bad about trying your hardest.
I guess you can talk to boys after all.
I was a bit surprised that
you called me out of the blue.
Huh?
That's because it's just the phone.
I can't even see your face.
And I don't like you that way, either.
I guess that's true.
What the hell?
Don't worry, Miyoshi.
Azuki and Shuujin aren't—
What the hell are you two
talking about so cheerfully?
You don't see something wrong here?!
Miho, Takagi is my boyfriend!
You should be talking to Mashiro.
Eh?
I can't!
Yes you can.
You should at least tell him
congratulations directly at a time like this.
Here, Mashiro!
Eh?!
Take it!
Me, talk to Azuki?
Um—
How long—
How long will you wait for me?
I'll wait for you.
I'll wait for you forever.
We haven't talked since then.
T—This is Mashiro.
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
The First Time Ever!!
A Tie for First!
Golden Future Cup
Winner Announcement!!
Hello?
Afternoon.
Yes, I saw it.
No, not really.
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack Square
This is amazing.
I didn't think the quality would be as good
as it was in the "Golden Future Cup,"
but the feeling and the power
are even better than before.
Is tolerating all this guys back talk
for so long finally going to pay off?
What are you grinning about?
You're creeping me out.
So how is my name?
You're the editor, so do your job properly.
You know, Fukuda,
you shouldn't be talking to me
like that before we even start—
Who cares about that right now?
If you thought I'd be satisfied with just the
"Golden Future Cup," then you were wrong!
I'm betting everything on this!
I'll push my way past all the popular series!
I have to get serialized this time around!
In that case, then let me just say this.
It's not bad.
I still have nothing to say about the art
and the story's metaphors and allegorical
setting give it even more depth than before.
Thank you very much.
That's great, Aoki.
Right? Right?
Let's go with this for the first chapter.
We can use chapter two to pull in—
"It's not bad" means that it's also not great, right?
Aoki, you're just reading too
much into the words he—
If there are any places I can
make better, please tell me.
I had thought losing the "Golden Future
Cup" would have wounded her pride, but—
The line in panel four on the second page could—
Sorry, but we couldn't end the
second chapter in 25 pages.
No matter what we did, we needed 27 pages
in order to get the case solved in only one chapter.
That's alright.
The story is good, so we'll go with this.
Alright, I'll make sure to do the next one right.
We have to make sure to fix more
than just what we were told to.
Then it's on to chapter three.
Right.
You should be talking to Mashiro.
Eh?
I can't!
Yes you can.
You should at least tell him
congratulations directly at a time like this.
Here, Mashiro!
T—This is Mashiro.
I want to apologize for what I did.
I'm home.
Welcome back.
Dinner's ready.
'Kay.
Hm?
Did you say something?
No, I didn't say anything.
Huh.
That manga magazine on your bookshelf.
Does that have anything to do with
why you've been so out of it lately?
Y—You can't just go through your
daughter's room without asking.
"Ashirogi Muto."
Your dreams are in there too.
Isn't that right?
Did Kaya tell you something?
Nope, nothing.
Then how do you know about—
Looks like I figured out who you like.
I—It's not like that.
Miho, are you actually meeting him?
You're not meeting the guy you like?
What are you talking about?
It's weird for a mom to be
saying something like that.
The two of us aren't like that.
And even if we were, it's nobody else's business.
You're right. I'm sorry.
I was just worried you were
doing the same thing that I did.
Huh?
When I was in middle school,
there was a boy that I really liked.
But it ended after years of only being
able to send letters back and forth.
Only letters—
That's really weird.
But if you don't meet for a long time,
don't you think you might think the
other person isn't interested anymore?
I would never think that.
And even if I did,
I'd always believe in him.
Is that so?
I'm glad.
Miyoshi Kaya
Request
Can you give me Mashiro's
cellphone number
Alright, this is good.
Yeah, I'll take it like this.
December 8th (Wed)
Hello?
Oh, you're here?
Alright.
Wait for me in the usual cafe.
I'll be right there.
You sure are working hard!
Good afternoon.
Aida, I have something I'd like to ask you later.
Hm?
Okay, ask me anytime.
I like it.
Chapter three is good.
I'll submit these for the meeting.
Thank you very much!
All we can do now is wait
for the higher-ups' decision.
We know.
We've done all we can.
We look forward to the results!
What did you want to ask me?
It's about Ashirogi Muto.
I'd like you to back them up
in the serialization meeting.
Back them up?
I'm sure somebody is going to ask if they'll be
able to keep up the pace while still in school.
Hey, you're pretty confident.
You don't even know if they'll get that far.
Well, I guess it would end like that.
I'm only submitting the first
three chapters for the meeting,
but they already have 10 finished.
They also have five manuscripts that they did
in two weeks each in case they got serialized.
And that was all while they were also
working on the "Golden Future Cup."
That's amazing.
They really did all this?
I'm not in a position where
I can go to the meetings yet,
so the best I can do is ask you to say they have
what it takes to do this while still in high school.
Please!
Alright.
I'll make sure everybody knows
how much work they've done.
Thank you!
Shady Detective Trap
Serialization Name Chapter 2
Ashirogi Muto
It's finally time, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
I see.
So this is screentone, huh?
Night before the Serialization Meeting
December 15th (Wed)
You sure are working late today.
Well, I'm not actually working.
What about you?
I'm really trying to Fukuda serialized this time.
And Nakai has a good shot as well.
So just in case, I'm looking for assistants for Niizuma.
I went around collecting examples from three
people with good enough drawings to fill the spots.
At this point, I don't care who it
is as long as they can draw well.
Those are the names being submitted
for the serialization meeting, right?
Yeah.
There are a total of 13 series
being submitted this time.
Ashirogi sure got some good feedback.
Yeah, but it feels like most of it
is talking about future prospects.
Hey, you want to go grab a drink?
Right now?
It's better than just sitting
around here worrying, isn't it?
There are four veterans with submissions this time.
At best, there'll probably only
be one newcomer chosen.
No, I think there could be two.
And after looking at the names, there might
even be a total of five new series chosen.
No way they'll choose five!
It's happened before with series like
"Rookies" and "Hunter X Hunter."
That's a crazy story from before
we started working there!
Now, it's usually two new stories at most.
I guess you're right.
I really want to get Ashirogi Muto serialized!
And it's got nothing to do with me wanting credit.
I'm in the same boat, y'know.
Man, I really want to get to the point
where I can be part of those meetings.
They sure look like fun, wouldn't you say?
Yeah, they do.
By the way, this is the first time we've
gone drinking just the two of us, isn't it?
Oh, is that right?
See you tomorrow, then.
See you tomorrow.
Tomorrow, huh?
This time—
I'll get this series serialized—
Tomorrow—
No, I guess it's already today.
It's finally time.
My future.
With Shuujin—
And—
Tomorrow
Mashiro Moritaka
Tomorrow is the Serialization Meeting.
We'll make sure to pass it for you!
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
Next
Episode
The Serialization Meeting has finally started.
We've come so far.
We've done our best for the sake of our dream,
but everything is decided here.
Yes and
No
Next time: Yes and No.
The course of our dreams is—