I spoke with your father.
A—And?
"Let him do it."
"Men have their dreams."
is what he said.
It's for Nobuhiro's apartment.
I left his studio exactly the way it was when he died.
C'mon! I'll show you what a name is!
Huh?
I got my uncle's studio!
What?
The studio hasn't been touched since he died!
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Every worry floats up to and fills the spring sky
shinpaigoto bakari ga tsumoru haru no sora wo
I look up, look down,
miagete utsumuite
and find myself looking back up at the sky
mata kao wo ageteru
I swore I'd find myself in this town
kono machi de mitsukerutte kimeta jibun
I tuck away all my important things into my heart for safekeeping
nakushicha ikenai mono wo mune ni
Your love
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Parents and Children
This building?
Yeah.
Ninth floor.
I feel kind of nervous.
S—Sorry for the intru—
What's all this?
It's all action hero figures!
My uncle claimed them as "business expenses"
since he wrote a manga about heroes.
It was a gag manga about heroes, right?
Are you making fun of him?
Just trying to be respectful.
Try looking behind one of them.
Jack from 1996? These are ancient!
We should read these later!
Seems like he's got every Jack
since it was first serialized.
And the actual studio's in here.
He has a ton of comics!
I thought I had a lot,
but he probably has a hundred times as much!
This brings back memories.
I remember how often I used to come
here and hang out with my uncle!
There's more in there too?
He always said that reading manga
helped the most with creating it.
That might have just been him
though, since he sucked at drawing.
There's some raw manuscripts here too, right?
Can we look through them?
Sure. I think they were in this closet—
Names
Figures
They're so neatly organized.
Manuscripts
Data Materials
Figures
Manuscripts
Data Materials
Figures
Manuscripts
Data Materials
Is it really okay to look through them?
Yeah.
What should I pick?
Guess I'll just start with number one.
I've never seen a raw manuscript before.
Manuscripts are important too, but
you should look at these names first.
You divide the page into frames, make
rough sketches and add dialogue.
So these are names?
Names are like blueprints for manga.
I think I've seen these before
in manga recruitment ads.
First, you draw up a name which then
goes to the editors for checking.
Name
Editing
You keep fixing and redoing
your name until it's approved.
Once it's approved, you can start on a manuscript.
Manuscript
Some artists can just submit a name for review,
but only after they've earned recognition.
We have to submit a completed manuscript
before we can earn that recognition.
Yeah, I get tha—
Wait, Saiko! You're really
gonna make me do all that?
A script's not enough?
Of course!
And wait, you can't just copy
this kind of name either!
The frames are small because it's a gag manga.
Plus, it's too simplistic.
You should base the layout on
what kind of story you have.
I told you already.
I'm not teaming up with you
unless you make a name I like.
Of course I can rearrange panels and make
other changes when I do the final sketches.
That's why you need to think
of a story I'd want to illustrate!
You're really incredible!
Alright! I'll do it!
I'll really do it!
I'm kind of super excited!
Saiko, what kind of manga do you wanna draw?
I like manly manga.
Manly manga, huh?
Which ones, specifically?
What's your favorite manga of all time?
'Ashita no Joe!'
"Throw a drilling punch to his core, keeping your
other elbow tight like it's locked to your side."
That one's a real masterpiece.
What's your favorite manga?
I think 'Dragon Ball'.
It's definitely a genius work like
what you were describing earlier.
'Joe' is too.
Whether it's manga or novels,
I'm gonna do a ton of research,
I'll read anything, even if it's
in the battle or romance genre.
Our story will be even better, if I can expand my
knowledge and get rid of any stereotypes I have.
You really might be able to pull this off.
You think so? Why?
My uncle put an entry in for the Akatsuka Award.
One of the two highest awards
in manga, mostly for gag manga.
Akatsuka Award
Hideo Furugawa Hideo "Nippon Forever"
Winner: Satoshi Minamimura "Morning Rush"
My uncle went through all the past winners
looking for anything they had in common.
He deduced that gag and satirical
manga were popular with the judges.
And he won.
So that's how he won?
It was only honorable mention.
But it's a good strategy if you're serious about this.
Aren't you already about to do the same thing?
Yeah.
Anyways, we should look over these names
since we came all the way over here.
These will be great references!
The red ink corrections seem especially helpful.
I'm sure Shuujin will be able to make
a name with an interesting story.
But I've never seriously tried to draw a manga before.
Shuujin.
What?
Do you think we can get an anime
adaptation by the time we turn eighteen?
There's no way.
Well you didn't have to tell me.
But voice actors become like
pop stars once they hit eighteen.
They might make Azuki into a sellout
because she's cute, and ignore her true talent.
Saiko.
I want us to be mangakas.
And I want you and Azuki to get married—
Just as much as you do.
An anime by the time we're eighteen?
Towards that goal—
No—
Let's make it a reality!
Shuujin—
We can definitely make it happen!
Hey, Saiko—
Do you know where this name's manuscript is?
I'd like to compare them but—
It should be in one of the boxes.
Okay, I'll look!
I'll look too!
Thanks.
But really, how many names are there?
Names
Manuscripts
Finished Checked
Names
All these boxes are stuffed full!
But only 10% of these became actual manuscripts.
No— It's more like 1%.
How did he even draw this many—
I'm gonna go outside to make a call.
To Azuki?
I said I don't know her number.
We're still waiting to hear the government's response.
And onto other news.
Female fans are hosting events in anticipation of rock star Koogy's debut concert—
What's the matter?
You never call me.
Dad.
What is it?
I'm sorry.
I always thought he'd committed suicide.
He wasn't such a coward.
He was a guy who'd just grit his teeth and do
the best he could, when faced with adversity.
You'd never hear him complaining.
Yeah.
Even when everyone was asleep,
he'd be up drawing something.
Moritaka, have you read 'Star of the Giants'?
Huh? Yeah.
Then you know that one line of Ryoma Sakamoto's?
Yeah.
You always did love 'Ashita no Joe'.
Dad, I think I get it.
Thank you.
Sure.
Ryoma Sakamoto's line in 'Star of the Giants':
"A real man faces death
head-on, even if he's in the gutter."
That's when Joe Yabuki completely
burned out and became pure white ash.
By mentioning that unforgettable
line, Dad made me think—
I'm not gonna do things half-assed anymore.
I'm gonna put my life on the
line for manga and for Azuki!
This one's funny. I wonder why he gave up on it.
Don't copy it!
I'm not interested in writing a gag manga about heroes.
What's that?
Letters?
Are these?
Miyuki Haruno
We went to different high schools,
so we never got to see each other.
We just exchanged letters back and forth.
What is it, Saiko?
Letters?
My uncle had a pen pal since middle school.
A pen pal? That's so old-school!
Then it was a long-distance relationship?
No, they were in the same city.
Huh?
It'd be rude to look inside, right?
O—Of course!
That's an infringement of their privacy!
I know, right?
C'mon, let's focus on names!
I, Mashiro Moritaka, and—
I, Takagi Akito—
do solemnly swear to keep the
contents of these letters to ourselves!
We swear!
"Mashiro, how are you doing?
I've finally gotten used to this school.
To describe my classes briefly, they're just
like that old drama, 'Youth: Take Wing!'
I went to The Alfee concert.
I hate the rainy season, but I bought two
gorgeous umbrellas and I love them."
It's all super trivial stuff, huh?
Even though they both liked each other, I
don't think they could ever actually write that.
I don't get that.
My uncle wasn't a gambler out of self-indulgence.
He was waiting until he was a
proper mangaka to finally confess.
Oh, that's how it was.
"Congratulations on the honorable
mention for the Akatsuka Award.
Did I mention that I'll be moving?
I'll tell you the new address once I get there."
It's incredible that they could be
so understanding with each other.
Is that the last letter?
Huh?
These last two are postmarked a year apart.
That means a letter hadn't come for awhile.
"I've kept quiet about it until now, but next spring—
I'll be getting married."
What the hell is this?
She has a different boyfriend even though she
and your uncle never had a chance to meet once!
married
I wonder how my uncle felt when he read this.
When did 'Super Hero Legends' start again?
Oh, um—
I think it's written in the front.
It was serialized beginning in 1996.
Compiled from issues
ran in Shonen Jack 1996
So the letter came two years after that?
It became an anime another two years later.
He didn't make it in time, huh?
That said, it's impressive he waited
faithfully for it to become an anime.
But if it wasn't for her, I wouldn't
have given it my best shot.
Hey, what's that?
Huh?
Isn't there still something in the box?
Yakusa City                Akehi Middle School
Graduation Yearbook
A yearbook?
My uncle said he couldn't even ask for a photo.
Just how innocent was he?
Miyuki Haruno! Let's find her!
C'mon!
I—I get it! I'm already look—
Her name's Miyuki Haruno!
Azuki?!
It's her mom! This has to be Azuki's mom!
Man, DNA sure is scary!
Being satisfied with just being pen pals!
You two are exactly the same!
That doesn't make it a fac—
There's no doubt about it!
C'mon, let's go check!
How would we do that?
We can just go to Azuki's house
again and ask her mother directly!
What?
Tomorrow's Wednesday, so Azuki's
in dance class from 5 to 7pm.
Why do you know that?
Don't underestimate me!
Couldn't we just ask Azuki what
her mom's maiden name was?
Don't you wanna know a lot more?
Crap, it's my parents.
Incoming
Kayoko Mashiro
Hello?
Just what time do you think it is?!
I've had enough!
I'm going to Koogy's concert once exams are over.
You got a ticket to the dome? No fair.
I guess we can go to Azuki's house.
You wanna know more about what
happened between those two, huh?
It's not that.
Alright, let's go!
Hey, why are we being so sneaky about this?
Because it's more fun!
I feel like Gevanni from 'Death Note' right now!
You didn't hesitate at all today.
The second time's always easier.
Yes?
I'm Miho's classmate, Takagi.
I'm sorry but Miho actually just left.
A—Actually, today we wanted
to speak with you, ma'am.
With me?
It's about the mangaka, Kawaguchi Taro—
Does this reaction mean she's really the—
And that we, Mashiro and I, want to be mangakas!
It's nice to be young.
I'll make some tea for you, so come on in.
Yes!
Please, come in.
Wow, she really does look like Azuki!
She's so pretty!
Uh, she's the same age my uncle, so around 42?
She looks so much younger!
So Azuki will look this good in 28 years?
Though at 42, she should
probably get a different hairstyle.
What's the matter, you two?
Nothing!
Well, come on in!
Just sit wherever you'd like while I get the tea.
Oh, okay. Thanks for having us.
This is the living room Azuki's in everyday.
Mashiro, you're Nobuhiro Mashiro's nephew, right?
Y—Yes, that's correct.
Your father was two grades
above us back in middle school.
He stood out quite a bit because he did judo.
I see.
Is coffee alright with you two?
Yes, ma'am!
Mashiro—
Oh, I mean Nobuhiro Mashiro, okay?
He drank canned Black coffee
everyday to help himself focus.
He mentioned that a lot in his letters.
She really is my uncle's pen pal.
Well boys, go ahead and ask me anything!
Um—
Wait, first we—
Oh, right.
We're really sorry!
We ended up reading all your letters!
Oh no! That's so embarrassing! All of them?
Yes!
She's blushing.
She's cute even at her age.
Then I didn't write too
many embarrassing things, right?
Y—Yes!
Your letters were unbelievably refined.
That's a relief.
I didn't really think much about what I was writing.
So that's how it was.
He saved all my letters.
And then you two stumbled upon them?
Well, what's done is done.
I forgive you.
Thank you very much.
Um—
While your letters were incredibly refined,
they were kind of lacking in actual content.
You did like him, right?
Yes, I did.
Then, why did you never write that?
It wasn't that I didn't write it, I just couldn't.
Not only was it embarrassing,
I also felt it'd be inappropriate.
We were probably both waiting
to tell each other 'I like you'.
But I couldn't wait any longer. I found a
new love and ended up getting married.
When Miho was three, we saw on TV—
Heroes are the legends
Heroes are super cool
I was surprised to find out Kawaguchi Taro's
manga had finally become an anime!
Heroes are the burning energy that resides in you
I was so glad, you know.
To see the results of your uncle's hard work.
The burning energy
From there on, this is kind
of embarrassing to admit, but—
I used to read 'Super Hero Legends'
at the grocery store sometimes.
One time there was a short story
called 'The Romance of a Drifter'.
I cried a little when I read that.
I was finally able to understand your uncle's feelings.
'The Romance of a Drifter.'
The protagonist worked hard to become the Defender
of the Universe and earn the affection of a princess.
He was an incredibly pathetic protagonist.
But even though he was weak, the
princess confessed her love to him one day.
"You're not supposed to tell me that yet!
Just wait patiently until I'm the Defender of the Universe!
And don't just pop out of nowhere!"
That story was probably a message to you.
I thought so too.
Nice one, Kawaguchi Taro.
My uncle was able to convey his feelings with manga.
Then can I ask something now?
Yes?
Which of you is dating Miho?
Neither of us yet.
In the future though, it'll be this guy.
Hey!
That's great!
Nerds were never really my type.
Girls like boys who are kind of bad.
But, ma'am—
If that's what you like ma'am, I can be that.
I'm a downright felon.
Hey, sit down!
Oh, that's how it is. Sorry to misjudge.
It's fine if you understand now.
Nope, I still don't.
Um, there's something I wanted to ask.
Miho still doesn't know that you
and my uncle were classmates,
and that my uncle was a mangaka, right?
That's correct.
Then please don't tell her.
I understand. I won't tell her.
You shouldn't either, Takagi.
Y—Yes, ma'am.
Takagi Akito.
Yes?
Mashiro Moritaka.
I'll cheer you on from the sidelines while you
work on becoming excellent mangakas.
Yes! Thank you very much!
Yes, ma'am!
She was super nice and super pretty.
I totally understand why your uncle fell for her.
Those two were quite the idealists.
'The Romance of a Drifter', huh?
Hey, isn't us becoming mangakas
a lot like 'The Romance of a Drifter'?
Why do you think your grandpa just
left his son's studio the way it was?
My dad and my grandpa knew
that I admired my uncle's work.
That's why they weren't against it.
Yeah. They thought it'd turn out like this.
No— Maybe they were hoping it would.
I'm pretty lucky.
It isn't just you, it's us!
I'll definitely make this dream a reality!
If I can't do this—
I won't be a real man!
I'm not a man yet!
Starting tomorrow—
No today,
I'm gonna work on my own manga drawing style.
Alright! I'm gonna work hard on names!
The boring everyday gets to me sometimes,
BETAAna genjitsu ni tsubusaretemo
but I always get back on my feet, standing strong
uchinomesareta jibun hiroiatsumete
No matter how many times the end approaches me,
nando owari ga otazuneretemo
I'll push my own back forward, keeping me on my feet
sono tabi ni jibun de jibun no senaka otoshita
If I get lost in the meaning of continuing what I do,
tsudzuiteku imi ni nayami
I'll rid myself of those worries and keep myself going forward
sono mayoi sae tachikitte yuku
Always
itsumo
The straight edge that draws the outline of my future
mirai no rinkakusen egaku massuguna jougi wa
is made of all the courage I've mustered up until today
ikutsumo no kinou no yuuki de dekiteru
I'll climb over the tall wall that I never thought I'd face,
omoiegaita no to chigau takaikabe koe
and continue my journey, going past the vanishing point
shoushitsuten no mukou e susunde
This winding road seems to never end,
harukanaru winding road
but it is the road I personally chose
hoka no daredemonai watashi ga jibun de eranda
I set my tiny dreams on fire,
kasukana yume wo zenbu moyashita
and broke through the dark with its light
sono hikaru de yami wo saite
Now that I've broken down the wall,
kudaita kabe no mukou ni
I can see my sky once more
jibun no sora ga mieru
I'm racing towards my goal
of becoming a mangaka.
Next
Episode
It isn't just you, it's us!
And I made a decision!
It's not just you, it's us!
Time and
Keys
Number One
Pride
Next time: Time and Keys
Every dream begins with a choice.