Kichijoji, huh?
Azuki lives way out in Hachioji, and
that's still another 30 minutes on the train.
It really is far.
Well, we are 10th graders.
And it's summer vacation.
And it's Shuujin, so it's just a change of pace—
But—
he is writing the name, right?
Niizuma
Niizuma Eiji.
I should be able to gain something from this.
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Conceit and Kindness
Are you Mashiro?
Oh, uh—
Yes.
I'm Nakai.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
It's a bit noisy, but come on in.
Thanks.
Danger!
Look out!
Niizuma-sensei.
Mashiro is here.
Why don't you go introduce yourself.
R—Right.
My name's Mashiro.
I'm your new assistant starting today.
I'm looking forward to working with you.
Oh, hello Mechadoc.
Oh!
Is that too old?
Mechadocrow!
Mechacrow!
What's up Mechadoc?
Niizuma-sensei is like that whenever he's not sleeping or eating.
And when he does sleep, he
won't wake up for 20 hours.
I see.
Nakai.
Please stop referring
to Niizuma as 'sensei'.
You are 17 years older than he is.
This is Fukuda. He started yesterday.
He's been in the running
for the Tezuka Award twice.
Fukuda?
He's got the same editor as Niizuma-sensei,
and is working on getting serialized.
Fukuda Shinta (18) Tokyo
Was that him?
I'm pretty sure he was in Next with us.
Nice to meet you.
Likewise.
He's writing a name!
We end up having quite a bit of free time here
so Fukuda uses all of his to
write names trying to get serialized.
Sure is impressive.
We don't need three assistants.
Niizuma ends up drawing
most of the backgrounds,
so that leaves us with just the
inking, whiteout, and screentone.
Well, we get paid just for being here,
and transportation and meals are free.
And the place is air conditioned,
so I guess you can't complain.
Mashiro, you're better off
finding your own thing to do too.
Mashiro, have you won any awards?
No, I haven't won any yet.
I've only been in Next once.
Recently?
It was a one-shot called "Money and Intelligence" printed last May.
That was you?!
The 15-year-old genius, Ashirogi Muto—
So Ashirogi Muto was a pen-name, huh?
Yeah.
First a genius high-schooler,
and now a 15-year-old genius, too?
I guess that means I lost.
You were third, right?
I came in fifth.
I'm glad a real rival has shown up.
It sure is something to come up with an
idea like "Money and Intelligence" at 15.
But the tone and style wasn't right for Jack.
It was too realistic.
And there's only so much you
can do with a story like that.
I don't think it could make it to the top of Jack
But I guess I probably just
sound like a sore loser to you.
Pretty soon, though, I'll be the new face of Jack.
Twice, Niizuma cheated
me out of the Tezuka award.
I'll be sure to get into Jack and
return the favor with my pen!
I guess that means Nakai
is at the bottom here, huh?
All he's done is win the monthly
award once about 10 years back.
If he's gonna keep calling Niizuma 'sensei,'
we should have him do the same for us.
It's just a joke.
You're just planning on being a pro assi, right?
A pro assi?
Yeah, a professional assistant.
No, I'm still—
Really?
You're still thinking about getting serialized?
But you're already getting old
and I never see you working
on anything in your free time.
Even Yujiro said that he isn't
expecting anything more from you.
There's no way I'm gonna let myself end up like that.
I'm supposed to work in this atmosphere?
Ah, I haven't explained
how things work yet, have I?
First, we take the manuscript pages
that Niizuma-sensei puts on the floor
and do inking and screentones.
Then we put them back exactly where we found them.
An 'X' means inking
and screentone shades are written in blue.
Understood.
For now, just sit here
and wait for Niizuma-sensei to
put the next page on the floor.
Um,
would it be alright if I
watched Niizuma for awhile?
It's not worth your time.
Not worth?
Niizuma doesn't have much experience yet.
And besides, he's not about to teach you anything.
I don't expect him to teach me anything.
I just want to watch him.
He's got the best drawings out of any of us here.
Man, I just don't get youngsters these days.
And they sure are rude.
Same goes for you!
You c-c-c-crow!
I'll show you my power.
Here!
Vanishing point!
Is that how he decides on a vanishing point?
Dark clouds! Dark clouds! Dark
clouds! Dark clouds! Dark clouds!
Excuse me for a moment.
You are in my way.
Perfect!
So I just take this and put it back when I'm done?
Huh?
Ashirogi-sensei!
'Sensei?'
What are you doing here?
I'm here to be your assistant.
What?
I'd much rather you work
on your own manga instead.
Even if I wanted to,
we haven't come up with a story yet.
Really?
Even though you came up with something
as great as "Money and Intelligence?"
The one in charge of writing the stories is Takagi.
I'm Mashiro, the one in charge of the drawings.
Ah, so that's how you do it?
Then I must say, Takagi-sensei sure is talented.
Yeah.
So while he's thinking of a story,
I thought I'd come here and see if there
wasn't anything I could learn from you.
Is there really anything you could learn from me?
Probably—
If you'll let me watch you draw.
Have a seat, then.
You'll be more comfortable that way, Ashirogi-sensei.
No, you're the sensei here.
Even so, I'm so glad we were able to meet again.
They seem close.
I really don't get youngsters these days.
Please make yourself at home.
Do you want melon or chocolate?
I'm fine with whatever.
Here.
So?
How does it look?
Woah!
You've already written this much?
Wow!
Guess that's to be expected of a manga writer.
Still not finished with my own name yet, though.
I wonder if Saiko went to be an assistant—
Isn't it strange for him to just be an assistant?
He's supposed to be your partner.
I can't go with him because I can't draw,
and I'd rather him get something done
than just sit around waiting
for me to finish the story.
Saiko's drawings already pass as a pro's.
Oh yeah!
What you said back then was right.
It isn't as easy as I thought
to become number one.
What?!
Even with a first chapter like that?
The first chapter came in first,
but chapter two came in fourth.
I was shocked.
Fourth place is still great!
The first chapter is fresh and has color pages,
so it's not uncommon to get first place.
They say that even if you
get first on the first chapter,
the hard part starts with chapter two.
Oh, Yujiro said the same thing.
A lot of new stories' second chapters
drop way down in the ranking.
But you're still up in the ranks of popular
manga that already have anime series.
There's nothing wrong with that.
He said that, too, but—
And you're even good enough to write
a manuscript without doing a name,
so I don't think you'll drop
any further in the rankings.
You usually need to submit the first three
chapters for the serialization meetings,
but you can take as much time
as you want to make them.
That means it gets harder
starting with chapter four,
but you don't need to worry about that.
Oh, is that so?
Hearing you say that gives me more confidence.
You can easily keep up a high ranking.
Do that for a year or so, get an anime,
and that'll bump you up to first.
Oh!
An anime will bump me up to first?
Amazing!
You're wrong!
At this rate, your rank will continue to drop!
Eh?!
Fukuda?
Your 10-week trial run'll be fine,
but you'll be cancelled in six months!
Cancelled?
That's what I thought while I
read chapters three, four, and five.
Really?
I don't want to get cancelled.
Please show me chapters four and five!
How are they?
I think they're amazing, as usual.
This makes them really easy to read.
But when you get to chapters three,
four, and five, you get used to it
so I feel like it starts to wear off a little.
Right.
'Amazing' and 'interesting' are two different things.
If the readers don't think it's
interesting, then your popularity will fall.
So what should I do?
Maybe write it so that it's
more fun for the readers.
And maybe make it a little easier to read.
That sounds good.
Niizuma, you need to be more aware
now that you've become a pro mangaka.
If you just want to draw
manga that you like drawing,
then make doujinshi.
But you're a pro in Jack now.
You have to think about
what the readers want first.
And "Crow" doesn't have
anything the readers can relate to.
It just looks cool.
And that will cause people to get bored quickly.
It just looks cool?
Yeah, Ashirogi-sensei has
you beat in that respect.
"Money and Intelligence" was interesting, right?
Yeah.
It's interesting because it
makes people ask the question
"What if the real world really is just like this?"
You're right.
Mine doesn't have anything like that.
Your drawing ability is definitely genius-level.
But you're still at the level
where you're just excited
about the editing department calling you a genius.
At least, that's my opinion.
That's amazing, Fukuda.
You're even better than the editors.
Huh?
Most people aiming to be a mangaka
should be able to give this level of criticism.
They just can't write anything
interesting themselves.
Well, that's not true for me, though.
I get it now!
I'll rewrite chapter five in the
two days left before the deadline!
Please help me to make it more interesting!
Huh?
You're joking, right?
Why would I help out a rival?
You give amazing advice!
That doesn't mean that—
Wait, why am I even giving advice?
Still, I want to try.
Mashiro?
I want to help figure out
what would be best for "Crow."
Guess it can't be helped.
But I'm only helping with chapter five.
The three of us will work on it together.
That good enough?
Yes!
At first, I thought you were a bad person,
but you're actually pretty nice, huh?
I'm not a nice person!
We are going to change Jack!
I just don't want my rivals to fail so early!
That's so cool!
We are going to change Jack!
At any rate, let's put this chapter at the top.
Yes!
Right!
What's with these guys?
Their youth?
No, they've got determination and skill.
So, what should I do to make
chapter five more interesting?
It's felt the same since chapter one,
so maybe add some variation?
Yeah.
All you do is focus on Crow in every chapter.
More than half of new series
disappear in less than a year.
The first 10 chapters will determine whether
or not a series can last in the long run.
Right now, you should focus on
drawing in as many readers as you can.
Yujiro said that to you too, didn't he?
He didn't mention it.
What's he doing telling me and not you
when I haven't even been serialized yet?
"Let's just say that we're having
meetings about the names."
is what he told me.
What the hell is he thinking?
Isn't he just doing that because he
believes in Niizuma's ability?
No.
He was a bit frustrated when I
told him I didn't want to do it,
but he finally caved.
An editor who doesn't have meetings
and a writer who doesn't do names.
Are you guys even taking this seriously?
But if I do a name, I feel like I'm doing
the same thing twice and it's not as fun.
And it's such a hassle.
If you don't have a meeting
and you don't submit a name,
there's no way your editor can judge
if your chapter is interesting or not!
And yet you still ask us how
to make it more interesting?
Stop screwing around!
I guess you're right.
So how do you think I can make it more interesting,
Fukuda-sensei?
What, so now you call me 'sensei'?
Oh, the first time I met you was
at the Tezuka Award Ceremony
and you hadn't debuted in Next
yet, so I called you Fukuda.
But, now that you've debuted, you're Fukuda-sensei.
Nobody cares about that right now.
I call everybody who's debuted 'sensei'.
So I guess that means the only one
here who's not a 'sensei' is Nakai.
That's too bad.
What?
You're saying that in front of him?
And laughing?
At any rate!
Don't just write what's fun for you,
but think about the readers, too.
Oh, think about the readers, huh?
Maybe something with more suspense?
That's it.
You need to create a climax
and end the chapter so that
the readers want to read more.
Oh!
Suspenseful!
Exciting!
Thrilling!
Climax!
Cliffhangers!
Unpredictability!
We never said unpredictable.
But it'd be better with it.
That's it!
The answer isn't in the ink,
Note: The word "beta" means "cliché," but is also used for "inking" manga.
but in a cliché story!
Cliché and unpredictability are one and the same.
So exciting!
It's always the same if he
just beats them every time!
Change the enemy character.
Make him stronger.
Wait, he's really an ally?
And pull in the readers.
Yeah.
I think that's good.
It sure is cliché,
but it's a plot twist that'll attract attention.
Standby.
Music—
Start!!
Don't just start with the manuscript!
But I hate names.
Well that's too bad!
After giving all that advice,
we have the right to see if it's interesting or not.
Whatever you say.
Gachapin!
Green monster.
I'm finished.
19 pages sure goes fast.
That's my line!
It's no good.
He's so fast that I can't analyze how
he thinks or plans anything out.
How is it?
Yeah, it's a lot better.
Tada! Standby on the music!
He did all this with just that much advice
and in this short amount of time?
I guess he's a genius in more ways than one.
I'll be sure to overtake him, though.
But since he is a genius,
that means there's definitely
something I can learn from this.
So Mashiro, why don't you
write your manga by yourself?
Eh?
From what I've seen, it looks like you're
pretty knowledgeable about manga.
If you work in a pair, you only get half the money.
And I've heard it's pretty tough, too.
No, we're a team.
My partner is a lot better than
I am at coming up with stories.
Well, I'm taking off.
Niizuma-sensei!
You look like you're busy rewriting
the chapter, so I'm leaving for today.
I'll be back tomorrow at three.
Gotcha.
I should have the first half done by then.
Oh, and Ashirogi-sensei, Nakai, you won't have
anything else to do until tomorrow afternoon, either.
One more thing.
Let us do the backgrounds.
If you've got time to draw
the backgrounds and effects,
you should be using it to
think more about your story.
But, aren't I the write-from-instinct type?
I think your manga will get better
if you spend more time
thinking about the story, too.
And we've got Nakai here, as well.
He's been an assistant for more than 10 years.
If it's just the background,
he can draw more than you.
His technique is amazing, too.
Isn't that right, Nakai?
Yeah, I can draw anything and any place
from any angle you need without a reference.
Background effects,
inking,
screentones—
Nobody's faster than me.
I don't think that's something somebody who's
aiming to get serialized should be bragging about.
Alright then, I've gotta get
home and get some sleep.
I've got a part time job, too.
A part-time job?
Yeah, an early morning job at a convenient store.
I can't survive on just being an assistant.
At this rate, I'll end up as one of two things:
either a free-lance artist or a mangaka.
Well then, see you tomorrow.
You wouldn't tell just by looking,
but he's actually a pretty hard worker.
Niizuma Eiji.
Fukuda Shinta.
I want to go up against them both in Jack.
But it's too naive to think that
all of us will get serialized.
Mashiro, you want to get some dinner?
S—Sure.
I'll have the steak set with a side of
fried chicken, carpaccio, and french fries.
And a banana parfait for dessert.
Oh, and a cream soda.
Mashiro, just order whatever you like.
R—Right.
Niizuma-sensei is pretty generous.
As long as we have a receipt, he
said we can eat whatever we like.
Right.
Mashiro,
are you staying the night?
Yeah.
I'd planned on working all night, though.
Is that so?
Still young, huh?
You're just getting started, aren't you?
We're back.
He wears headphones at night, huh?
Only because his editor told him that he had to.
There's a break room if you want to hit the sack.
Not yet.
I'm going to stay up with Niizuma for a bit.
I want to get serialized—
S—Sorry.
It's okay.
I think I understand what it feels like.
That kind of makes it worse.
S—Sorry.
It'd probably be better for me to just give
up and become a professional assistant.
But I just can't give up on my
dream of being a mangaka.
Even so, all I do is waste my time going
from one assistant job to the next.
Now I'm already 33.
Whatever you do,
don't let yourself get stuck
being an assistant forever.
Right.
Good morning.
Crow!
C—Crow!
What?
He's already done this much?
Black wings!
There's no background!
Finally some real work to do.
We're about to get busy.
Right.
Last three!
Wow.
Nakai is drawing such a complicated background
freehand and then going over it with the pen.
Hello.
Good afternoon.
Afternoon.
Niizuma,
which of these is chapter five?
There's so many I can't tell.
Oh, that's not ready yet, so leave it.
Not ready?
But you said on the phone the day before
yesterday that you were already finished.
I'm rewriting it.
What?
This is the chapter five name.
Name?
You wrote a name?
What's this?
This is really great!
Is it really?
Yeah, it's amazing!
Yujiro,
I'm sorry for being so rude up until now.
I'll have meetings from now on.
And I'll write the names, too.
W—What happened?
Everybody kept calling me a genius,
so I guess I got a bit conceited.
Is that so?
If you do all that, it'd sure
take a load off my mind.
Keep it up and becoming the best
writer in Jack won't be just a dream.
Not a dream?
The early results for chapter three have you in—
third!
That's better than chapter two.
Chapter three is better?
I guess we were wrong, then.
I don't regret it, though.
We helped him make chapter five even better
and got him to start having
meetings and writing names.
Yeah!
I'm gonna become the most
popular mangaka out there!
I'm glad he got Eiji to start writing names.
I came here for Shuujin.
I'll make sure to learn something before I go back.
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
It sure looks hard to write manga as a pair.
Next
Episode
Maybe so, but we'll push forward together.
If it was me, I'd get into a
fight and split up in no time.
I believe in my partner.
Jealousy and
Love
Next time: Jealousy and Love
We're chasing after the same dream,
right?