I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu