Oh, I'm so full.
I think I ate too much.
You did have two hamburgers.
That's because Mashiro was paying.
That aside, it sure has been awhile.
Has it been two? Three months?
I can't remember.
At any rate, today we start
working as a team again.
Mashiro
Yeah.
We should probably clean up first, huh?
Sorry.
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Cooperation and Conditions
Here.
Huh?
This is the character design.
Thanks.
A con artist detective who sets up
traps for criminals to discover the truth.
I see.
This is pretty interesting.
You think so?
Looks hard to pull off, though.
Eh?
I realized this as I was writing.
A mystery doesn't really
have a whole lot of action.
It's mostly dialogue while
they solve the mysteries.
If it's all just flashy battles, it
won't feel like a proper mystery.
Yeah, you're right.
I ran into the same problem
writing my name, so I stopped.
You wrote a name?
Eh?
Let me see.
Um—
But—
I only did a little bit.
Whatever, just show me.
We're working together again, aren't we?
C'mon.
Remember, I just did a little bit of the beginning.
Make the culprit think the
man he killed is still alive,
and when he comes back to kill him again—
This has been done before, but I
think it'll work nicely as a hook.
It's good to have the main character
in action right from the start, too.
Woah, your drawings are great!
Way better than Takagi's.
The story is more important in a name.
Yeah, yeah.
With this—
Hm?
You think it's okay to have a main
character who can transform?
Eh?
It's a manga and he's supposed to be a
con artist, so we should get away with it.
Transform into what?
The person who was
supposed to have been killed.
So our main character becomes
the bait to lure out the culprit.
I see.
Yeah, he is the main character, so he should
have at least one or two special abilities.
That'll definitely be more interesting.
He can change anything, even
his gender, to fool the culprit.
I knew they worked better as a team.
That's perfect for a con artist!
We just need something after this.
Yeah, we just need a con with some
traps that'll surprise the readers.
I couldn't come up with anything.
If we can do that, it could be really interesting.
This could work.
I want to write this more than
anything we've done before.
Let's go with this,
and get it serialized for sure this time.
Yeah.
But six months, huh?
Huh?
Ten names in six months.
Saiko, six months is our limit, right?
Are you saying you want more time?
No, that's not it.
To be honest, about a week after I told
Hattori that I was writing a mystery—
Be right there.
Sign here, please.
Six boxes?!
And all stuffed full of mystery novels and DVDs.
There was a note, too.
You can't always avoid similarities, so don't worry.
It's all about how you pull it off.
Use this to brush up on your skills.
It would take me at least two
months just to go through all of it.
But you probably should, right?
The important things for a
mystery are the tricks and the story,
so going through it all would definitely help.
You came up with a great character,
so I want to do the same with the story.
That's why I figured we should
probably spend a little more time on this.
I see.
I think you're right.
It won't matter whether we have a good
character or not if the story isn't interesting.
Saiko?
I always make a big deal
about working on my drawings,
so of course you'd want to
really work on your story, too.
I'm fine if you want to do—
I'll do it.
Huh?
All those novels and DVDs.
I'll go through them all and
write down summaries for you.
That way it'll save you the time and
you can keep working on your name.
Your success is my dream too, after all.
Your dream?
What happened to cellphone novels?
I gave that up.
That was fast!
You should really think more
before deciding what to do.
Helping you guys is a lot better than
spending my time writing a cellphone novel
that I'm not even sure will sell or not, isn't it?
I guess it would be a big help if you
wrote down just the important parts.
In that case—
But—
Novels and movies both have a certain atmosphere,
so I think it would be better to do it yourself.
Each person sees the story
in their own unique way.
I guess you're right.
But if you do that, you
won't have enough time to—
It's alright.
I guess I was just trying to rush it.
Azuki already made her debut
and is starting to get popular,
so I kinda felt like I was being left behind.
That's why—
Trying to get an anime by the time we're 18 is—
You can't give up!
That doesn't sound like you at all.
Hey, why are you crying?
I—
This last month, while you
two weren't working together,
was really tough.
I thought it was partially my fault,
but I was more worried about you two.
And—
I was worried about Miho, too.
The thing I want most right now is
for you and Miho to get married.
Thanks, Miyoshi.
We'll get our manga turned into an anime,
have Azuki play the heroine,
and then get married.
Even if it's only a little bit,
I'll be glad to accept your help.
I finally got Mashiro to understand how I feel!
But you're still gonna cry about it?
If everything works out, let's get married too.
Are you talking about me and you?
Who else would I be talking about?
Are you proposing to me or something?
You said you loved me, didn't you?!
Huh?
I said I 'like' you, but I don't
remember ever using the word 'love.'
We even kissed!
W—What the hell are you
doing saying that in front of Saiko?
Takagi!
Here are the summaries I did yesterday.
Thank you.
Let's get going.
Ah, I forgot my bag.
Hold on, I'll be right back.
Miyoshi's sure getting into this, huh?
It's already been a month and she's
been at it every day, hasn't she?
She's summarizing it a lot better
than I thought she would, too.
Um—
Huh?
Me?
Yeah.
What is it?
Takagi.
Are you and Miyoshi from class three
going out?
Yeah, and apparently we're getting married, too.
Is he serious?
Yeah.
I've got a fiancé, too.
Doesn't everybody?
Mashiro.
What?
Tomorrow's November 5th.
Do you know what day it is?
Azuki's birthday.
You remembered, huh?
Don't worry, I'll send her a message.
Is that all?
Love comes in many forms, dontcha know.
St. Visual's
Girls Academy
Mashiro Moritaka
Happy birthday.
That's all you wrote?
Yep.
What about a present?
It's enough to let her know I care.
For now, we're focusing on
our names until next spring.
Hm—
I guess love does come in all different forms.
Oh yeah, "St. Viz Girls" was popular
enough that it got a second season.
Really?
I haven't been watching lately, so I didn't know.
I got a message about it.
And Miho said she's going
to be singing the ending.
She didn't tell me that.
It looks like the recording studio's
producer took a special interest
and is having the three most
popular girls sing the ending.
It was a spur of the moment decision.
That's great!
Azuki really is on her way to
being a full-fledged idol, isn't she?
She also told me to make sure
that Mashiro doesn't see it.
Why is that?
Do you want to say it or will you hold back?
Please don't hide the feelings deep in your heart.
Azuki really sucks at singing.
This explains why I could
never get her to go to karaoke!
Oh, my stomach!
Let them all out.
I'm lonely and I want to see you.
I'm so sad that I might break.
Their skirts are so short.
I want you to look only at me.
This is kind of exciting.
It's supposed to make you want to look, so of
course they're wearing something underneath, right?
Into my heart, never wavering.
Yeah, but still—
Oh, I bet you're in shock, huh?
Eh?
Your touch, your gaze, your body.
Thinking about other people watching her like this—
My heart aches just looking at you.
No, I was just thinking that I can see Azuki
working hard, but Azuki can't see me.
What are you waiting for?
Please tell me.
Why don't you send her a picture?
Want me to take one?
No, stop it!
Why not?
The more I yearn for you, the farther you seem to get.
I—It's embarrassing.
Huh?
Miho says to keep you from watching
and now you're embarrassed?
It's driving me mad.
You guys are so weird.
It's going to be a tearful
Love comes in many forms, dontcha know.
Daybreak Symphony.
Azuki
really is cute.
Here you are.
Please take one.
Hello, this is Takagi.
How's the story coming along?
Oh, I'm working on it, but if I'm going
to spend the next two years on this,
I thought I should go through all
the material you sent me first.
I see.
You must have your hands full.
No, it's a big help.
I'm actually watching one right now.
I'm glad it's coming in handy.
Take your time and let me
know when you finish a name.
I will.
Thanks to you watching that
right now, I think he bought it.
Miyoshi, turn off the TV.
It's Hattori.
Oh, alright.
Hi Hattori.
Good, thanks.
Yeah, I'm having a little trouble with the name.
But I'll do my best.
Mashiro and Takagi are
both taking their time.
I'll call them into the office when they
both have something finished and—
What?
You were doing a mystery, too?!
Yeah, it looks like we both had the same idea.
Then they'll join forces
and Ashirogi Muto will be reborn!
It's all going according to plan.
Heishi.
How are they?
Niizuma said his parents grew these themselves.
Here you are.
Please take one.
"Detective Trap" (Tentative)
Serialization Name (3)
Ashirogi Muto
Eight names for serialization, huh?
We had planned on bringing in ten chapters,
but we didn't make it in time.
You didn't tell me you'd be coming together.
Sorry.
How long have you guys been back together?
We got back together about a month after you
asked me to go two years without saying anything.
Is that so?
I guess you got me.
Well, I guess I'll just take it as proof
that you two make a good team.
It's all thanks to you that we
were able to get back together.
You stopped me from doing the
drawings for a different series
and told Takagi that I was working
on a detective story as well.
Thank you.
Alright then, let me have a look.
Sure.
W—What do you think?
I like it.
This is really great.
You guys really pulled one over me here.
And you really can't wait until
you're finished with high school?
That's right.
If you really think it's good, please submit
it for the next serialization meeting.
I've said this already, but there's really no reason
to get serialized while you're still in high school.
Niizuma is doing it, isn't he?
And he's working by himself.
Fine, but with two conditions.
Conditions?
One, you submit this as a one-shot for the
next "Golden Future Cup" and it does well.
The "Golden Future Cup?"
That's in the summer, right?
And one more thing before that.
You have to bring me a 19 page
story for this series every two weeks.
Even though we're not getting serialized yet?
Yes.
Real serialization is once every week,
but you have the "Golden Future Cup" to
do and you don't have any assistants yet,
so you don't have to do a completed manuscript.
A good rank in the "Golden Future Cup" and
an unfinished manuscript every two weeks.
If you can meet these conditions, I'll
submit this for the serialization meeting.
No matter how you look at
it, that seems a bit harsh.
We'll do it!!
Eh?
And you won't be turning these
names into finished manuscripts.
You'll be making new, unfinished
manuscripts of this level once every two weeks.
When you finish one, you'll bring it in
and have a meeting for the next chapter.
So this is a rehearsal for actual serialization?
That's right.
Do you usually do this sort of thing?
No.
But this is how I want to do it this time.
If you can't do this much, there's no way
you can do it while still in high school.
I'm sorry, but you guys are not Niizuma.
And writing a detective manga is completely
different than writing a battle manga.
And even if you don't get this serialized,
it will be a good experience for you.
Thank you very much.
I never thought that you
worried about us so much.
We'll definitely show you we can do this
and then get serialized for sure.
Good.
If you can pull this off, even
the higher-ups can't say no.
After all, this is really interesting.
Finally looks like we'll be considered, huh?
But before that, we've got the "Golden
Future Cup" and a chapter every two weeks.
I can manage with the story,
but do you think you can manage with the drawings?
I'll do it even if it kills me.
Yeah.
We've made it this far, so we can't stop now.
Oh.
Ah, Fukuda.
Hey, didn't expect to see you here.
Fukuda?
Is this the guy Saiko met when
he was working at Eiji's place?
Here for a meeting?
Yeah, we just finished and are on our way home.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Takagi, Mashiro's partner.
You're the writer, huh?
Hi.
Do you have a meeting, too?
Yeah.
My recent one-shot came in seventh.
It's not as good as I'd wanted, but
the characters were interesting,
so Yujiro asked me to rework it with the same
ones and try it out in the "Golden Future Cup."
Man,
what a pain.
I want to be a serialized author, already.
Us too.
Huh?
We were just told to try our story out in the "Golden
Future Cup" before getting it serialized as well.
Eh?
You were already accepted
for the "Golden Future Cup?"
Well, it hasn't actually been accepted yet,
but our editor said that the way it is
now, it should get accepted for sure.
There are only four or five people
who get chosen for that, right?
Whatever, I'll make sure mine gets accepted too.
If it doesn't, Yujiro's gonna pay!
Hey.
Huh?
I may have lost to you guys in "Next,"
but I'll beat you for sure this time, Ashirogi Muto.
No, we'll make sure to win!
Good.
It's no fun otherwise.
Let's make it a fair fight.
And the winner will be that
much closer to number one.
Sound good to you?
Yeah.
Alright, first step is to get first
in the "Golden Future Cup."
We'll make sure to win!
Yeah, this is good.
Alright, let's talk about chapter two.
Right.
Can you finish the name for chapter
three by the time school gets out today?
Yeah, I'll have it ready to turn into a
manuscript by the time we get home.
Slow down!
Here's the manuscript for chapter three.
And the name for chapter four.
We made it this time, too!
Good job.
Make sure you bring in the name for the
"Golden Future Cup" one-shot next time.
Right.
You won't get serialized if you're
not accepted into the contest.
Take your time and make this even better.
Right.
Isn't this explanation a bit too long?
Hm—
I'll try shortening it a little.
Do you think we should make the main
character look more exciting on the last page?
Hm—
You're probably right.
I'll redraw it.
What should we do about the title?
Huh?
"Detective Trap" is a bit weak, don't you think?
He is a detective,
but he tries to lead the criminals into traps, so—
Maybe 'pseudo-detective'?
He feels kinda like a fake detective, so—
"Shady Detective Trap?"
Yeah.
It makes you wonder what kind of detective he is.
Let's go with this.
Here you are.
Please take one.
It sure was a long wait.
But today you finally find
out the entries for the contest.
Entrants to the Golden Future Cup
Announced
Kinda gets you excited, huh?
If we don't get accepted into the contest,
serialization is out of the question.
And that goes for an anime too, of course.
And Azuki and my dreams.
It'll be fine.
It was really interesting.
The main character was really cool, too.
I'm sure it'll be fine.
It's Hattori.
Hi, this is Takagi.
Right.
Our entry into the contest is official!
Alright!
We did it! We did it! We did it!
This means our manga
will be in the weekly Jack!
This is awesome!
I'm so happy that I'm crying!
Congratulations!
I'll go buy some ingredients and make
some curry for you guys to celebrate!
Thanks, Miyoshi!
I love you!
Saiko, you—
Saiko, before that,
you've gotta message Miho.
Oh, that's right.
What's wrong? You forget because
you're cheating with Miyoshi?
I didn't forget.
And I'm not cheating.
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
We're going to be in Weekly Jack's
"Golden Future Cup" contest this summer.
I'll tell you more when we
Alright.
Send!
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
Ashirogi Muto's entry in the "Golden
Future Cup" has been confirmed.
Next
Episode
Yeah, and we'll make sure to win this time.
What? Why is this guy in the contest?
Eh?
Next time: Literature and Music.
Literature and
Music
Those who get in the way of
our dreams will not be forgiven!