December 16th (Thu)
The serialization meeting
is supposed to start at two.
It's about to start.
Well then, I'd like to begin the Weekly
Jack December serialization meeting.
I, Yahagi, will be leading this meeting.
Assistant Chief Editor   Yahagi
We have 13 serialization candidates this time.
Assistant Chief Editor   Heishi
We'll be proceeding in the order in
which I received the submissions.
First up, we have Orihara-sensei's "Tanktop."
Team Leader   Nakano
Team Leader   Yoshida
Team Leader   Aida
The editor for this one is my group's Uchida.
The story starts at a public high school in a
metropolitan area where the transfer student,
our protagonist Shindo—
Only those of team leader rank or higher
participate in the serialization meetings.
Chief Editor   Sasaki
First, the team leader in charge of the editor for
a given name describes the story and it's aim.
All of the submissions are read
one week prior to the meeting
and the feedback they were
given is written on their envelope.
After reading the feedback, those present
at the meeting discuss the submission.
So I agree with the feedback that
we should be careful about this one.
Now I'd like to hear your
opinions on this submission.
His last series did pretty well, didn't it?
Compared to his previous works, I think
the readers might find this a bit weak.
Yes, but he's changed the
style, and it's fairly well done.
It's true that it's not bad, but it feels like
it's lacking Orihara's usual boldness.
I have to agree. It feels like
he's kind of fumbling around.
This one's a 'No.'
Have him revise it and we'll consider it again later.
Each submission is sorted and given
either a 'Yes' or a 'No' for serialization.
No
Those labeled as 'No' are then told to
either be re-worked for later consideration,
Revise
One-Shot
tested out as a one-shot,
No Good
or given a flat out 'no good.'
Yes
The 'Yes' submissions become serialized.
New Serialization
Then the same number of series
must be decided on for cancellation.
End Serialization
We didn't do so well in the last questionnaire.
I'm worried.
It'll be alright.
Recently, at the most, there
are only three new serializations.
You sure are carefree.
You think so?
We've been going this long, so—
Not including the most popular series,
even mangakas currently being
serialized get worried about these meetings.
Yes and No
Niizuma
Happy Crow!!
It's already started.
I heard from Yujiro that there are 13
submissions for the meeting this time.
And it looks like only about two or three
of those will be chosen for serialization.
That sure makes our chances go down, doesn't it?
And there are four authors
who've been serialized before.
Even if a newcomer were to be chosen,
there'll probably only be one, don't you think?
O—Only one?
First sunrise!!
Explain yourself!
No matter who gets serialized, no hard feelings.
Y—Yeah—
Next up is "Hideout Door."
I'm the editor for this one.
After considering the "Golden Future Cup"
results, I had them write a serialization name.
The writer, Aoki, is a third year college student,
but she has done some one-shots for a shoujo
magazine in a relatively short period of time.
She has no problem getting a
name-style manuscript done quickly.
I'm sure most of you know the artist, Nakai.
He's a veteran assistant who has been supporting Jack from behind the scenes for about 12 years now.
His skill and ability to adapt his art style
to any story leaves nothing to be desired.
Personally, I'd like to bring him into the spotlight.
They are both experienced.
If they are serialized, they won't lose steam.
I believe they are both the
type to continue growing.
I was told to do shounen manga and
ended up a runner-up in "Story King."
But during the "Golden Future Cup," I felt
as if it didn't quite fit and the results were—
That's because it's a shounen manga!!
No, I'm sure it'll be fine.
It's true that Nakai's art really
does bring Aoki's world to life.
Even though they didn't win the "Golden
Future Cup," they got high marks.
Yes, but all three of the entries that
did well in the "Golden Future Cup"
are submissions for serialization.
We have to compare it to them.
We don't have a fantasy story
like this in Jack right now.
I'm not sure we should dismiss it just yet.
Mark it as 'Yes' for now.
Thank you.
Next up is "Kira Kira."
I already told you we don't know yet!
I just can't stop thinking about it.
I'll call you as soon as we know, so just wait!
Alright—
Jeez.
Oh, you ready?
Yeah.
Two-pair, 4's and 10's.
Three of a kind, Jacks.
Jack
It's already been two hours.
It usually takes them about two hours, right?
At the quickest, yeah.
This is no good.
I can't get my mind off it just by playing cards.
Yeah, let's stop.
We'll be alright, won't we?
I'm sure we did all we could.
M—Miyoshi—
Miyoshi Kaya
Just invite her over already.
My heart can't take this.
That one is a 'No,' then.
We'll give it a 'No Good,' then.
Next up is another one of the
"Golden Future Cup" entries.
"Kiyoshi Knight" by Fukuda Shinta.
When we ran it as a one-shot
before, it came in seventh.
In the "Golden Future Cup," it has a lot of male
support, so I think it is well suited for Jack.
Fukuda is 20 years old, so he's not
too much older than the readers.
And I'm sure his ability to write
characters they can relate with
makes this a good candidate for serialization.
That is what Yujiro had to say.
His characters do stand out.
However, I feel like it's the type of story that
does well as a one-shot, but not as a series.
The first three chapters all feel exactly the same.
He's purposely making them feel more like
one-shots to attempt and draw in more of an audience.
It's important to be able to attract
as big of an audience as you can.
Even if that is the case, they all feel too similar.
It feels like he's just relying on his intensity.
Being intense is a good thing!
I can understand your concern, but it did well
as a one-shot and in the "Golden Future Cup."
It's strongest point is
definitely the character design.
Put it down as a 'Yes' for now.
Alright, let's move on to Arai's "Cheese Okaki."
Note: "Okaki" is mochi that has been cut thin, dried, and then either baked or fried.
"For now," huh?
Hello!
I thought I'd help you guys get your minds
off the meeting, so I brought some cards!
Wanna play?
No.
Why not?
Oh.
On top of fixing everything
we pointed out last time around,
I can also say that he has improved
his overall story composition.
It seems like it would be easy
to adapt to different media.
If there were one thing I'd want to see,
it would be a cooler character design.
This mellow design does feel
like Arai-sensei's style, though.
Put this one down as 'Yes' for now, too.
Thank you.
Chief, we've only looked at seven and
you've already said 'Yes' to four of them.
The number doesn't matter.
If it's interesting, it's a 'Yes'.
Next up is "Otter #11" by Hiramaru Kazuya.
I'm the editor for this one.
He's my recommended newcomer.
Oh?
Well that's sure forward of you.
Is that the one that got honorable
mentions in the recent monthly contest?
Hiramaru is 26 years old, but up until
now, he's never really read any manga.
He picked up an issue of Jack from the luggage
rack on a train and thought "I can do this."
He gave his letter of resignation
to his company the very same day
and brought in a submission a month later.
So that's how we got otters—
Most manga writers have liked
manga since they were kids
and got their start from copying the
drawings of their favorite series.
Then they start drawing manga after
learning how to do so from books and such.
Books with that kind of information
have been increasing lately.
However, Hiramaru started with one issue of
Jack and no knowledge of things like screentone,
and through trial and error,
brought in a submission.
And he's already created characters
that can easily be turned into an anime.
He did all of this in only one month.
He's a genius.
If that's true, then we can
expect good things from him,
but do you really think he
should be serialized so quickly?
We would be taking a big risk.
I think it's interesting.
The name's good, too.
It's a 'Yes.'
Thank you very much.
Woah.
Alright move on then.
We have "Shady Detective Trap" by Ashirogi Muto.
The editor for this one is my group's Hattori.
It's a mystery that received good
marks in the "Golden Future Cup."
It seems that everybody is concerned that they
are still second year high school students.
However, I'd like to start by saying that they are
capable of doing a series while still attending school.
What's your reasoning for that?
Other than the three chapters
submitted for this meeting,
they also prepared seven
more names for serialization.
They also completed five 19 page
manuscripts at the pace of one every two weeks.
And this was all while they were also
preparing for the "Golden Future Cup."
At the same time as the "Golden Future Cup?!"
They never missed a deadline and the quality is
just as good as the names submitted for this meeting.
That's some serious determination.
Hey, you guys want to go somewhere?
I'm sure getting out would get your mind off this.
He'll call Takagi's cellphone either way, right?
Let's go!
I don't want to get all depressed or
excited in front of a bunch of other people.
Oh, I see.
Sorry.
How much of a shot do you have?
We either get serialized or we don't, so that
would make it a 50-50 chance, wouldn't it?
What?! Are you sure that's how it works?
No, I'd say we have a 20% chance at best.
Why is that?
You already won the "Golden Future Cup!"
Yeah, but there were three series that did well.
And if you assume only one of those
three gets chosen, that's a 33% chance.
It's not a sure thing that one of the "Golden
Future Cup" winners will be chosen at all,
so it might be lower.
Hattori also kept saying they were
worried about us still being in high school.
That "Crow" guy is a high schooler too, isn't he?
It should be fine, right?
Whether we get a 'Yes' because
Niizuma Eiji set a precedent—
or whether we get a 'No' because they
don't need another 'genius high schooler'—
It feels like you guys are
getting more and more negative—
Because we are.
They only have a little more
than a year left, don't they?
Is now really the time?
They'll have a tough time always
being compared to Niizuma.
Actually, Niizuma Eiji is one of the reasons
they want to do this while still in high school.
If they're this serious, I don't see
why we shouldn't let them do it.
I don't think they need to
push themselves so hard.
I've seen them in here quite a
bit since they were in junior high.
Unlike the last guy, Hiramaru, everything
they've done was to become manga writers.
They don't feel like newcomers at all.
It's true they've been working hard on
names ever since they were in Next.
Almost enough to make you dizzy.
However, it takes a lot of knowledge
to write a detective series.
Wouldn't it be tough for somebody so young?
Yeah, I can see it getting too difficult and turning
into a battle manga somewhere along the line.
After reading their first 10
chapters, I have faith in them.
I'm still worried, though.
They're so young.
Yeah, it might be bad to have too much faith in them.
However, their first three chapters are interesting.
It's a 'Yes.'
Yes.
Alright, thank you.
That sure was a long smoke break.
I just can't seem to calm down.
It's always like this when they have meetings.
Are those the materials you got
from the assistants yesterday?
Yeah.
You sure are working hard.
No, I just can't get my mind off
it unless I'm doing something.
But I can't focus on reading any of it at all.
This time sure is taking a while.
It sure is.
I bet they'll be done soon, though.
We have finished reviewing the 13 submissions.
Request
Please remember to turn off the
lights before leaving.
However, we put seven in the 'Yes'
category and can't serialize all of them,
so let's try and narrow it down.
Hattori sure is something.
Hm?
Ten names and five manuscripts.
He sure is serious.
You managed to bring in quite a find yourself.
But really, to give up his normal job for manga—
I'm going to get him serialized.
Hm?
Hiramaru has no attachment
to becoming mangaka.
If he fails, he'll probably just quit.
Anybody can read manga.
But you can't draw it if you don't have the skill.
He has the skill.
For a person who has the skill
to draw manga to not do so—
would be a sin.
I'm not sure if I'd call that a sin or not,
but no matter how cool you try to
sound, it doesn't quite work in here.
What? Still?
How long are they gonna take?
You said they'd be done in two or three hours.
I said that it normally takes two or three hours.
Just sit tight and wait for me to call you.
What do you care?!
You're not part of the meeting, so
you've got nothing better to do, right?!
Fukuda, you need to watch
the way you speak to me!
If you do manage to actually get serialized,
I'll start by teaching you some manners.
"If I manage to?"
What the hell's that supposed to mean?!
I've been waiting because I
believe I'm gonna get serialized!
Should I teach you to use your words properly?
Fine, I'll teach manners and
you can teach Japanese.
So, it really isn't finished yet?
Yeah, just wait a bit longer.
Jeez, I'm just as irritated about it as you are.
Wanna play cards?
Eh?
It is today, right?
I'm sure of it.
It sure is late.
I wonder if we failed.
Maybe it's too hard to give us the bad news.
I don't think he'd do that to us.
He'd tell us right away if we failed.
Man, I'm exhausted.
S—Should I make something to eat?
There's no way I could eat right now!
You don't have to get mad about it—
Sorry.
I want to get serialized.
I already tested it out as a one-shot
and in the "Golden Future Cup."
This time for sure—
Serialization—
with Aoki.
This is boring.
Who's idea was it to play cards?
It was yours.
Let's just stop.
They sure are slow.
Yeah.
I guess that means we've got a chance, though.
Why is that?
If there are a lot of new series, they have to
take longer to choose which series will end.
I see.
Still doesn't make waiting
any easier though, does it?
My group, gather at the table over here.
Man, you took it.
My group, this way.
Alright, my group—
It's time!
T—This is Takagi.
Congratulations.
Congratulations—
is what he said.
Alright!
Serialization~!
Takagi?
We're alright!
I'm sorry, but you weren't chosen for serialization this time.
Get off, Miyoshi.
I failed again?!
Right.
You made it into the final group, though.
There were four new series chosen.
It really was a tough decision.
Is that so.
They liked each chapter individually,
but they want something with a better
foundation for a continuous manga.
I kept telling you that we should focus
more on how to keep the story flowing!
I guess you did.
Sorry about that.
You did it!
"Cheese Okaki" is getting serialized.
Congratulations!
You really are a genius.
For the next serialization meeting?
Yeah.
I wanted to explain the particulars
with you, so we should have a—
I'm sorry, but could you give me a little time?
Yeah, sure.
Alright, I'll contact you again later.
Thank you.
Alright, we'll see you tomorrow, then.
Thank you very much.
We did it!
This isn't a dream, right?
No, that hurts so it can't be.
I just can't stop smiling.
Saiko.
Thank you.
It's all because of you.
Shuujin—
I couldn't have gotten here without you, either.
Let's keep working hard, partner!
Yeah!
Yeah. Yeah.
Male bonding sure is nice.
Oh, Mashiro!
You've gotta tell Miho!
Right!
I can't wait to see her fast reply!
Mashiro Moritaka
Serialization Get!
"Shady Detective Trap" was
chosen for serialization
during the meeting today!
Serialization.
Alright!
You should be talking to Mashiro.
Eh?
I can't!
Yes you can!
You should at least tell him
congratulations directly at a time like this.
It's Miho!
No, it's Fukuda.
What? Why's he calling?
Ashirogi, congratulations!
I lost again!
Dammit, this sucks!
Y—You mean—
Nakai and I both lost.
I'll make sure to pass the next meeting, though.
So don't go getting cancelled, alright?
You'd better get popular and wait for me.
Got it?!
We will. Thank you.
Here's Niizuma.
Ashirogi-sensei, congratulations.
Just as I promised, I've been waiting for you.
I'm happy you finally made it this far.
But I'm not going to lose.
Bam!
Right.
You are part of the reason
we were able to get serialized.
We'll do our best.
I will as well.
Man, c'mon.
It must be nice to be serialized.
A rival, huh?
Damn.
Fukuda!
Let's be sure to pass next time!
That's a given.
I can't stand to lose.
Yeah—
If you don't keep trying, you're
gonna get dumped by Miss Aoki.
I—It's not like we're going out yet or anything!
So, you do like her, huh?
Even though Fukuda and Nakai
didn't pass, they were still laughing.
Yeah, those two will get it next time for sure.
Have you gotten a reply from Miho yet?
It's not like she always responds right away.
She's probably at work.
I guess so.
I'm sure she'll message you later.
Let's celebrate, then.
Should I go get a cake?
Oh, can we do that some other time?
Huh? Why?
Serialization?
Yeah, we'd start in Jack next February.
Wow.
And what about school?
We'll do both.
How can you say that so easily?
I'll show you we can do both.
I promise.
Do your best, Moritaka.
Grandpa—
Thank you.
Uncle—
I finally got serialized.
It's taken two years—
And we're still just gamblers.
Messages
Is that so?
Is that all you have to say about it?
You and your father are both too easy on him.
Don't say that.
This is a result of his hard work.
Be happy for him.
"Men have dreams—"
"—that a woman wouldn't understand," right?
Yeah.
I'll tell him, but only because
women understand, too.
Is that so?
Thanks to my uncle, I was able to see my dream.
Thanks to Shuujin, I was able to take the first step.
And even though it's been tough,
I was able to continue forward without giving up—
Thanks to Azuki.
I'll be doing the drawings
and this guy will do the story.
I knew it!
That's great!
I'm sure you guys can do it!
S—So, if our manga gets turned into an anime,
we can try and reserve the heroine role for you.
Really? That would be great!
I'll do my best.
I'll become a voice actress
and be in your guys' anime.
This is wonderful.
If our dreams come true, will you marry me?!
I don't know this number.
Mashiro?
This is Azuki.
H—Hi.
I asked Kaya for your number.
I'm sorry for hanging up on you last time.
I wouldn't have been able to talk much anyway.
Um—
Congratulations—
on getting serialized.
Thanks.
We're getting closer to our dream.
Yeah.
I'll work even harder to make that dream come true.
Right.
I'll do my best as well.
It looks like I can talk on the phone after all.
Me too.
What should I do?
Eh?
I didn't think I'd be so happy
about being able to talk to you.
I believe that the time will come
when our dreams come true
and we can be together forever.
Yeah, me too.
Alright, we're all ready.
Let's have Hattori sit over there.
I'm so nervous.
He said we're gonna talk about the
contract, assistants, and some other stuff.
He's here!
Huh?
Congratulation on your serialization.
T—Thank you very much.
Why is there another person?
Is it because we have to sign
a contract or something?
The name's Miura. I started at Jack last year.
Nice to meet you!
Y—Yeah.
Good afternoon.
Starting today, Miura is
going to be your new editor.
Eh?
W—Wait, this is where it ends?
The
Editors
I can't wait to see what happens next!
What kinda guy is this Miura?
What's going to happen with our serialization?!
The
Rival
Please look forward to the
continuation of our dreams in Season 2!
An
Otter?