Ota.
Here!
Kawasaki.
Kibura
Here.
Suzuki.
Sobukawa.
Here.
Takagi.
Tanaka.
Here.
Tonei
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Every worry floats up to and fills the spring sky
shinpaigoto bakari ga tsumoru haru no sora wo
I look up, look down,
miagete utsumuite
and find myself looking back up at the sky
mata kao wo ageteru
I swore I'd find myself in this town
kono machi de mitsukerutte kimeta jibun
I tuck away all my important things into my heart for safekeeping
nakushicha ikenai mono wo mune ni
Your love
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
10 and 2
Here's another draft.
Might not be perfect, but it's what I chose.
It's terrible, but it's hilarious!
You can buy what's in someone's brain?
Terrible, isn't it?
I know this kind of thing
wouldn't work for Jack though.
There he is. Takagi!
Hey Miyoshi.
Sorry for making you leave the other day.
Here.
Let's go after school today,
a welcome-back present.
Can't.
I have a meeting at Yueisha today to
go over our Tezuka Award submission.
Then tomorrow?
Can't.
We're gonna start our next work
using the feedback from the meeting.
But Takagi—
We're going out, aren't we?
But didn't you say—
My dream to become a
mangaka comes first!
Love comes second!
Even if we went out, I wouldn't
have time to actually go on dates!
That's fine. I'll support you.
to me before?
Yeah, but it's just for a little bit—
Don't you get it, Miyoshi?
I have a dream to become a mangaka.
I'm even imposing on Saiko to help me.
I don't have time to go on—
But you need a break
every now and then, right?
Not right now.
Not even a small break?
Not even a small break.
Not even a teeny, tiny break?
Not even a teeny, tiny break!
Yueisha
Sorry for the wait.
Good afternoon.
Thanks for meeting with us!
Huh—
I forgot to bring the evaluation reports.
Do you guys mind coming upstairs with me?
Upstairs as in—
Where the editorial department is?
Yup.
You'll need that badge to get in.
Are you sure it's alright for us to come in?
It's fine.
Elementary and middle school kids
come in all the time on field trips.
I'm so looking forward to seeing
Jack's editorial department!
This way, you two.
Yes, sir.
Everyone reacts like that the first
time they get off the elevator.
And here's the editorial department.
This is the Shounen Jack's editorial department.
When's the manuscript gonna be finished?
This is Jack's editorial department!
This is pretty incredible!
Sorry about that.
Let's go to the table over there.
Sure!
Your judges were Inagaki-sensei,
Ota-sensei, Toriyama-sensei, Kishimoto-sensei,
Tezuka Productions, Editor in Chief of
Jack SQ, and our own Editor in Chief.
Wait, that man—
came to my uncle's funeral!
Mashiro, are you listening?
Y—Yes!
The mangakas gave you
guys a pretty good evaluation.
The editors' evaluation weren't so good.
Can you guys guess why?
Because this sort of work wouldn't get
published in Jack. That's how they evaluate it.
On the other hand, the artists tend to favor
works that wouldn't get published in Jack.
Probably because they value
the originality of such works.
What exactly about it makes it unsuitable for Jack?
That the protagonist is a normal human, just
like in your other work, "The Two Earths."
A typical Jack protagonist has
flamboyant special abilities.
Of course, all our series can't be like that.
A normal human—
Does it still read like a novel?
Maybe, but that's also part of your style.
The protagonist is undeniably weak though.
Um—
Is my art bad?
That's not the case at all.
You got more 4s than 3s on the art.
You still have room for improvement though.
I think they gave you 3s so you'd
keep developing your skills.
You'll keep getting better if you practice.
But you're already very good.
Thank goodness.
I'm not holding Shuujin back.
These are really impressive scores.
You guys just had bad luck this time.
'Cause Niizuma Eiji won
first prize and runner up.
You guys would've at least gotten an
honorable mention, if it weren't for him.
This Niizuma Eiji guy's really good—
He is. Almost too good to be true.
They're saying he's one of
those once-a-decade prodigies.
He actually moved here from Aomori
in preparation for serialization.
Serialization?
A high school student can get serialized?
They can.
Mashiro can probably guess this:
How much time would it save if you only drew
the characters and let assistants handle the rest?
It could be done in a fourth—
No, a fifth of the time!
Right. With assistants, it's doable.
And Niizuma's been able to submit
a work by himself every month,
so it's entirely feasible.
Every month?
And he always wins first
prize and runner up—
Well, Niizuma aside—
In my opinion and according this report,
what you're lacking is a protagonist.
A Jack-like protagonist that
really draws people in.
I'm sure you'll make the cut next
time if you guys can create one.
And you won't have to worry
about Niizuma anymore either.
Niizuma Eiji's already getting
ready for serialization,
and we're still—
Last time, I told you guys I wanted
to submit your work for Next,
but I think you should win
the monthly prize first.
Because if you win, that work
will be your debut piece.
Yes, sir.
Is that the fastest way to get serialized?
If we created a manuscript
with serialization in mind,
and it actually ended up
being serialization-level,
would you let us get serialized?
Saiko! We're not at—
I wouldn't mind, but you'd need to
have at least three chapters drawn.
And they'd have to be
manuscripts, not just names—
And if it was good enough,
we could get serialized?
Doesn't matter how good it is,
if they don't even read it.
It might not even make it
to a serialization meeting.
It might be torn to shreds 'cause
they think you're cocky—
That's not true.
Editor in Chief!
H—He's the Editor in Chief?!
A manga just needs to be good.
Good works will be serialized.
That's all there is to it.
But your work isn't good.
At your level, serialization is still impossible.
It needs to be good.
Good works will be serialized.
Those were Kawaguchi Taro's last words to me.
He knows who I am?
That's what Kawaguchi said when his
termination from the company was announced.
Termination from the company?
Authors serialized at Jack have
an annual contract salary.
Is it okay to tell them this?
They really want to be pros, right?
Then there's no reason to hide the truth.
The pay isn't very high but just think of
it like a baseball player's annual salary.
Each year, the salary and page rate are determined
by how much their work contributed to Jack's success.
But if the series ends and they can't
come up with anything else that's good,
we tell them, "You're no longer needed at Jack."
And their contract is terminated.
Kawaguchi came to this point,
and as the Vice Editor in Chief,
I had to break the news to him.
Sorry for the wait.
So it's come to this.
Your Super Hero Legends was—
It's alright, you don't need to say all that.
It's been seven years and I haven't done
a thing worth mentioning since then.
That's not—
This is easier on me.
I'll start from scratch and
submit works like the rookies.
A manga just needs to be good.
Good works will be serialized.
After that, he brought in works one by
one, without caring what he looked like.
He continued to bring in manuscripts, not
names, until five days before he died.
Um— Is it true Niizuma Eiji's
preparing to get serialized?
Yes, it is.
What's the biggest difference
between us and Niizuma?
To put it simply: how much you love manga.
We love manga too.
I can tell.
But he does to an extraordinary extent.
He picked up a pen at age six and
hasn't stopped drawing since.
Even when I went to go visit him,
he never once put down his pen.
Drawing manga is like breathing
to him, practically involuntary.
I think he'll get continue to improve
whether he's serialized or not.
But he can probably never be number one.
He can't be number one?
He has energy but no depth,
because he's young.
Children might enjoy his works,
but our target readers, middle and high
school students, will expect something more.
That's it!
What?
Considering their age, the work these
two produce is very deep and complex.
Yes, but some parts are too complex—
The depth—
The content—
Takagi, Mashiro, just bring in names from now on.
Just focus on finding a charismatic,
Jack-like protagonist and keep bringing works in!
Then we can decide together which
ones you should draw out in full.
Just names?
Yes. Mashiro's art will get better with
practice, and it's already pretty good.
We need to focus on the content now.
This way, you guys can aim directly for Next.
Good, Hattori. You can evaluate their names.
Create a good piece with Hattori first.
That's the fastest way to serialization.
How's that sound?
Great!
Chief, why'd you bring up Taro
Kawaguchi all of a sudden?
I had a hunch, seeing Mashiro's
last name and address.
He's Kawaguchi Taro's nephew.
He taught Mashiro?
Yeah—
But you'd never guess that.
Getting our names evaluated is
another step forward, right?
Yeah.
Create a good piece with Hattori first.
That's the fastest way to serialization.
Just bring in names from now on.
Then we can decide together which
ones you should draw out in full.
I'm feeling more pressure now.
But Hattori believes in us.
Huh—
Shuujin, you're here al—
Huh?
Shuujin.
Hey Saiko.
What's up?
Sorry.
What?
Just 'cause we were here alone, doesn't
mean we were doing anything weird!
That's not the issue.
I'm sorry, I only realized after she got here.
What is it?
I told you this place belonged to
Mashiro's uncle, a mangaka, right?
Yeah, and?
Saiko doesn't want Azuki to know about this.
Why not? It doesn't matter, does it?
Not like you're doing something bad.
Yeah, but I just—
It's pride or something—
It's complicated.
Pride, huh.
I heard it all from Miho by the way.
It's super weird to "support each other until
you both succeed and not truly date until then."
And after you succeed, you'll get married?
I can't believe Azuki told Miyoshi everything!
What?
Nothing. It has nothing to do with you, anyways.
It definitely does!
She's my best friend!
It's almost Christmas! You two are slacking!
Who are you calling?
Miho, who else?
Miho?
I'm with Takagi and Mashiro right now.
Why don't you come over and the four of us can—
Wait, sto—
She said no.
Azuki and I can't do stuff like that.
Why can't she understand?
I know Miho's easily embarrassed and a little naive,
but it's really hard to tolerate this.
Deciding to get married once your dreams
come true when we're still in ninth grade?
Should we be making promises like that already?
Are you thinking about marrying me?
Not at all.
W—Why'd you—
I was agreeing with what you were just saying!
You answered way too quick.
Plus you said "not at all."
Miyoshi—
That's something that Saiko and
Azuki decided for themselves.
It's not your place to interfere.
I kind of understand their feelings.
It's nice to be an idealist.
Then what would you do if I said I wouldn't
see you until you became a mangaka?
I can't answer that.
What?!
That means it's something that'd
make me kick you again, right?!
So something like, "That'd be annoying"
or "I wouldn't care" isn't it?
Saiko! Help me!
Alright, quit it already.
Anyway, Miyoshi, you absolutely
cannot tell Azuki about this place.
If you tell her, I'll break up with you.
Got it. I won't.
And you, Shuujin, don't bring
Miyoshi here without asking first.
Sorry. Understood.
What?
But you two are always locked in
here writing manga, aren't you?
We can't even go on dates on the weekends!
You were the one who said that was okay!
Don't make me keep reminding you.
But—
Fine, if it's a holiday, you can come.
On school days, you can see him at school.
Really? Yes!
What?
Nothing. Just thinking you're
pretty cute when I look closely,
Miho has good taste!
Thanks.
Hachiouji?
Or something like that. Miho's probably
going to a private, all-girls school there.
But Hachiouji's pretty far from here.
It's close to her lessons and
the production company though.
After entering high school, they might promote her
as an actress first, before getting into voice acting.
Really?
She wouldn't do something like
swimsuit shoots, would she?
I'm not sure—
But as her boyfriend, you wouldn't want that, right?
Azuki'd never do something like that.
Come on Shuujin, let's get to work.
Hachio
They're all terrible.
What?
What happened?
Every protagonist is now done in classic Jack style—
I got it! They're too ordinary.
Too ordinary?
They're all so Jack-like, none of
them leave a lasting impression.
In your attempt to make the
protagonist more Jack-like,
your story's been negatively affected.
Forget Niizuma Eiji, these works
would lose to other rookies as well!
No way!
I apologize. Looks like this
was the wrong approach.
It's clear you two aren't cut out
for classic mainstream manga.
What?
But isn't that a fatal flaw for us?
What should we do now?
We're told our works won't sell in Jack—
Then we're told our works are too Jack-like to be in Jack—
Where does that leave us?
I'm off!
From Hattori?
Yeah.
He wanted to know if we could
stop by after school today.
What do we do?
Yueisha
Thanks for coming.
Sorry for calling you out all of a sudden.
It's alright.
Thanks for meet—
Let's not waste time. Do you
guys know about reader's surveys?
Yeah, we know about them.
They're a postcard that comes with Jack,
asking readers to rank their favorite works.
Right.
Truth be told, if 2 people out of 10
pick your work, it's considered a hit.
Really?
Only two?
Yes, you only need 20%.
Why'd he bring this up all of a sudden?
Why's he being so frank?
Telephone
Age
Boy
Girl
Takagi's strong point is the depth
and maturity of his stories.
I tried to combine that skill
with mainstream devices,
but instead ended up killing it.
Change of plans.
Instead of trying to create a
work that everyone will like,
try to create a work that more
than 50% of people will like.
A work that 2 out of every 10
people will definitely love.
If Niizuma's going through the front door,
this would be called a backdoor route.
I want us to aim for such a piece.
Strictly speaking, Next has fewer
works than a regular Jack edition.
So 20% there isn't good enough.
But a piece that could get 20% in our regular
edition would definitely have good results.
Actually, even if you do it in Next—
A backdoor route—
This is an all-or-nothing gamble!
Please go into the details!
Were there any names you cut 'cause you thought
"It won't sell in Jack" or "Readers won't like it?"
A popular high school boy tries to see how
many girls he can cheat on at the same time.
That's it! Stories like that!
What?
Most people would be turned off,
but there's bound to be fans of it.
What about that one, Shuujin?
The one where you advance by
buying what's in other people's brains.
That's terrible, but great!
Tell me more about it!
You know how cell phones exchange
information through infrared, right?
In the future, this'll be possible with people's
brains, so anyone can buy or sell knowledge.
Of course, intelligent people's minds would
be more expensive 'cause they're worth more.
You need money in order to buy information,
so you'd sell your knowledge
to as many people as possible.
Less intelligent people will advance if you sell to them.
So if you have to sell, sell to
someone as stupid as possible.
And if you wanna buy, buy from
someone as intelligent as possible!
That's it! That would definitely do it!
Huh?
Why didn't you bring that one with you today?
I just didn't think it was—
What's its title?
Maybe it's bad taste, but it's "Money and
Intelligence Make the World Go Round."
That's perfect. Let's go with that!
This is the only way to allow your
individuality to shine through.
I want to publish your works!
So let us work on a name together,
and make the February 13th Jack Next deadline!
Yes, sir!
The boring everyday gets to me sometimes,
BETAAna genjitsu ni tsubusaretemo
but I always get back on my feet, standing strong
uchinomesareta jibun hiroiatsumete
No matter how many times the end approaches me,
nando owari ga otazuneretemo
I'll push my own back forward, keeping me on my feet
sono tabi ni jibun de jibun no senaka otoshita
If I get lost in the meaning of continuing what I do,
tsudzuiteku imi ni nayami
I'll rid myself of those worries and keep myself going forward
sono mayoi sae tachikitte yuku
Always
itsumo
The straight edge that draws the outline of my future
mirai no rinkakusen egaku massuguna jougi wa
is made of all the courage I've mustered up until today
ikutsumo no kinou no yuuki de dekiteru
I'll climb over the tall wall that I never thought I'd face,
omoiegaita no to chigau takaikabe koe
and continue my journey, going past the vanishing point
shoushitsuten no mukou e susunde
This winding road seems to never end,
harukanaru winding road
but it is the road I personally chose
hoka no daredemonai watashi ga jibun de eranda
I set my tiny dreams on fire,
kasukana yume wo zenbu moyashita
and broke through the dark with its light
sono hikaru de yami wo saite
Now that I've broken down the wall,
kudaita kabe no mukou ni
I can see my sky once more
jibun no sora ga mieru
Niizuma, how's everything going?
Next
Episode
I actually came to check in on your work—
N—Niizuma?
Next time: Chocolate and NEXT!
Chocolate and
NEXT!
Next is a rookie's dream!