Mashiro!
Miho got a role as a voice actress!
It's just a small one.
He's just pouting.
Gotcha.
It's still really cool!
So all you guys need to do is get an anime,
use Miho as the heroine, and then get married!
It's kinda scary, but exciting too!
Getting an anime isn't going to be so easy.
And Azuki still has a long way to go
before being able to play a heroine role.
Why are you being so negative about it?
He's just like that.
In any case, let's all watch her debut together.
It's a late night anime, y'know.
It'll be fine!
I'll tell my parents it's to watch Miho's debut.
Even though we're guys?
I just won't tell them that part.
Sorry guys, but I want to watch it alone.
O—Of course.
Sorry.
Well, we're off to the studio.
Eh? Alright.
Hey,
can I watch it with you?
What?
"St. Viz Girls."
I mean, Azuki becoming a voice actress is
related to our dream of getting an anime, right?
Yeah, I guess.
So you want to watch it together at the studio?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Man, I really want to get an anime before Miho
ends up as the heroine of some other series.
I feel the same way.
After all, she has been our
heroine since middle school.
"Our" heroine?
Huh? Does that bug you?
Your heroine, then.
So that makes my heroine—
Miyoshi?
Not good enough for you?
No, she is! She is!
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Wall and Kiss
A heroine—
One everybody will love.
This isn't right.
Crap!
After drawing the realistic style for "The
Two Earths" and "Money and Intelligence,"
I can't draw any cute girls.
Why not use that one?
The drawing of Azuki you
made last year in your notebook.
N—No good?
That wasn't realistic.
And it was really cute, too.
Yeah!
I've heard that a lot of mangakas
draw their ideal girl as the heroine.
Really?
Wow!
This is really easy to draw!
Alright, then here.
This is the first 15 pages.
If you think it's alright, can I get a clean copy?
My Angel
Tentative Title
The main character's an angel, huh?
I've seen pirates, ninjas, death gods, and spirits—
But I don't think I've ever seen an angel
as the main character in a Jack manga.
And I figure if he's good looking,
the girls will like him too.
Wasn't there a manga
called "Flower Angel Ten-Ten?"
Oh yeah.
But that was a gag manga.
I liked it as a kid.
That just means this one will
do well with kids too, right?
Yeah.
If you actually look for a series with an angel
as the main character, you'll find plenty.
If you're worried about never copying anything,
you'll never be able to write anything.
The angel kills somebody right off the bat?
That's an evil angel.
It's the angels' job to send
humans who have died to heaven.
Many angels come down to Earth
and kill humans to gain extra points.
Our angel of justice has come
down to try and prevent this.
He falls in love with a human girl
and fights the evil angels.
Then, I'll give it a moving ending.
I'm pretty confident we can pull this off.
Yeah, this is good.
It's got all the things Hattori mentioned before, too.
It's Hattori.
Hello, this is Takagi.
This is a bit sudden,
but you've heard of the "Golden Future Cup," right?
Oh, yes. You guys did that last year as well, right?
The one where all the
newcomers submit one-shots?
Well, we're doing it again this year,
and since you did so well in Next, we'd like to know if you're interested in submitting a name for it.
Really?
Yeah! We'll do it!
We're actually writing something great right now!
I think about 20 names are up for consideration,
but only four or five will actually be accepted.
However, the deadline is June 25th,
so you don't have much time.
We can make it!
And with time to spare!
This is our chance!
Yeah!
If we can get first, then getting
serialized won't be just a dream.
Let's make this happen.
Let's have a name ready three days before the
deadline so we still have time to make changes!
Right!
I don't think the main character
should look exactly like a human.
I guess you're right.
The readers need to be able to tell the
difference between angels and humans.
Takagi! Mashiro!
Somebody gave me some movie tickets!
You want to go after school?
Sorry, we've gotta go turn in our manuscript.
So what should we do?
In the name, you can always see his wings.
Then how about he has them out
around people who know he's an angel,
but keeps them hidden otherwise?
Azuki Miho
Oh, yeah.
She had a lesson today.
It must be nice to have a dream.
I want a dream too!
This is great!
You've managed to put everything I said about
mainstream battle mangas into the story.
And so naturally, too.
Takagi is even more skilled than I thought.
To be honest, I didn't think he'd be
able to write a battle manga this well.
I apologize.
T—Thank you.
However, I'm just your editor.
I can only give you advice.
The ones who are able to build
on that and take it even further
are the ones who will be successful.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
I think so.
Editors can't write a story
guaranteed to be a smash hit!
If we could, we'd just do it ourselves!
Mangakas must be better than their editor!!
So do you mean this name is no good?
Sorry, that's not what I meant.
This is good how it is,
but if you're aiming to get better,
you have to not only do what I've said,
but also be able to surprise me.
Mashiro's drawings, as well.
They feel pretty solid, so they pass.
But you have to go beyond my advice
and create something original.
Something that nobody else could make.
That might be too much for a Jack-level manga,
but to make me say this much,
you're already very talented.
Right.
In any case, I'll submit this
to the "Golden Future Cup."
I was a little surprised to hear Hattori
say we had what it takes to write mainstream.
He got pretty excited.
We should be fine, right?
Really?
I'm not so sure.
I think we did pretty well,
but did it have anything that really stands out?
Anything that stands out?
We'll probably make it into the contest,
but it feels like we were told that the winner will
be the one that surprises the editors the most.
My uncle said something similar.
There are a lot of people out there
who can debut and win an award,
but the tough part comes after that.
Only a small percentage of those
manage to get as far as serialization.
Man, now I can't even be happy
about being an entry for the contest.
I want to win and get serialized.
Popularity.
I want to be popular!!!
Knock it off! You're embarrassing me!
Thanks for coming by.
Huh? Where's Shimoyama?
Oh, he quit.
Quit?!
Um—
I can manage the drawings on my
own, but the atmosphere is kinda—
It'd be great if I could get one or two more people.
I'll see what I can do.
Niizuma!
I'm taking your manuscript, alright?
Oh, when did you get here?
How is Ashirogi-sensei doing?
Eh? Oh,
they submitted a name for
the "Golden Future Cup."
You mean that contest?
Yeah.
So they'll have another one-shot.
I can't wait!
Ashirogi-sensei will definitely win!
Yes!
Crow!
What?
We didn't even get into the contest?!
Yeah, it's too bad, but that's what they decided.
That, and—
He said he submitted it for
this summer's Next as well,
but it didn't get accepted there, either.
Maybe mainstream really is impossible for us.
I have to write a mainstream manga.
I can't write stories like you do.
Let's just go with something that you—
Don't say that!
We're aiming for the top together!
But to be told today of all days—
Now we can't even enjoy Azuki's anime.
Even though I said that,
I'm still really nervous!
St. Visual's Girls Academy
It started!
We are saints!
My heart starts beating anew.
After we meet, let's ring the school bell.
Your heart—
Well then, everyone.
Take care.
It's almost over.
Is Azuki really gonna show up?
E—Excuse me.
Senpai
There's Saotomeji!
I—
came to this school because you were here.
I—I love you.
Erina-senpai.
"I love you?"
What is this?
What's with this awful development?
Shut up, Shuujin!
Ah.
S—Sorry.
Take care.
So she only had four lines—
But it was better than I imagined it would be.
Azuki—
I'm Otsuki Nanami, the voice of Ijunin Erina
Azuki!
and we're giving away copies of the "St. Viz Girls" album to a few lucky viewers—
Woah! She's on TV!
Man, that was probably embarrassing for her.
Being on TV in cosplay.
No, Azuki's the same as us.
She'd want to be right up in the front.
Azuki's been trying her best to get this far!
We can't just sit around and feel depressed!
Yeah.
Guess you're right.
Suda.
Here.
Segawa.
Takagi.
Takagi's absent?
Takahashi.
Here.
Nice weather, huh?
Your phone's ringing.
Hattori.
I bet it was a bit of a shock, huh?
No, well—
Yes.
Were you disappointed?
Yeah.
Good.
I put your name in here and passed it around
as a candidate for the "Golden Future Cup."
These are all the comments it got.
Have a look.
I can't believe this was written by the same
pair that wrote "Money and Intelligence."
However, the writing is too textbook.
I don't think we should run it. Shows much promise.
Shows much promise.
It looks like they want to write something that will make
it big. They're so young, yet already sound like pros!
I really want to see them get serialized!!
I—I can't—
I can't read any more.
Shuujin—
Hattori, you didn't write
all of this yourself, did you?
I wouldn't do something like that.
Cellphone novel written by female
high school student becomes bestseller
Sold over one million copies!
Akai Baby
Shimaki Hiromi
Cellphone novel written by female
high school student becomes bestseller
Sold over one million copies!
Akai Baby
Shimaki Hiromi
I didn't expect the editing department
to think we have so much promise.
Yeah, I was surprised too.
But that's just putting more pressure
on me to write something great.
Miyoshi sure is amazing.
Yeah—
Yesterday, when I got home, I looked into how many
other newcomers were close to getting serialized.
There're at least 15.
I see.
No matter how much they expect of us,
we've only been in Next once.
We gotta try harder.
They all say your drawings are pretty solid,
so that just leaves my names.
25-4, Class 3 wins.
I'm finally finished.
What?
What what?
You were watching me the whole time.
Oh, I was just watching your
boobs bounce all over the place.
Why are you always such a pervert?!
It was a joke, I swear.
See? Look!
Wow, it's true!
She's in a magazine!
"Beautiful New Voice Actresses?"
She was also on the home page of her agency.
Her high school doesn't allow you to work,
so she almost got in trouble.
I got a mail that said they're going to allow it
because she's always a hard worker.
Yeah, yeah.
As long as she makes her studies a priority.
A serious, cute girl is poison, after all.
Miyoshi,
did you come here just to show us this?
Announcement!
Announcement?
Thanks to you, I have also chosen my dream.
Your dream?
What is it?
I'm going to become a writer.
A writer?!
Miho's a voice actress.
You two are mangakas.
I wanted to fit in with all of
you, so I decided on a writer.
What's with that shallow way of thinking?
Well, it is only cellphone novels.
There are a lot of companies
publishing them online.
And what're you gonna write?
A love story.
I'll model it after Miho and Mashiro.
Of course, I'll replace 'mangaka' and
'voice actress' with 'writer' and 'actress.'
And the part about playing
the heroine in his anime
will be her starring in a drama he wrote.
Oh, that might be interesting!
Why are you supporting her?!
Right? Right?
So, you think you can help me out?
In exchange, I'll tell you how to write a
good female character for your manga.
Well, I guess I do need a good
heroine for the story I'm writing now.
Yay! It's decided then!
I understand that you want to have a dream too,
but I don't want you sticking
you nose into our manga!
Eh? Why?
You need to understand a woman's feelings, right?
It's a shounen manga,
so it's fine with a man's ideal girl.
Is that so?
Well, Takagi's the one writing the story!
And I've already written a bit on my phone,
so could you take a look?
Shuujin!
These are all too textbook! No originality!
They aren't uninteresting,
but they all feel like our "Golden Future Cup" entry.
If we don't change anything,
it'll just end up like before.
Right.
I guess the mainstream
stories I write do all feel similar.
Maybe I'm trying too hard to
do everything Hattori said.
I'll try a different approach and see if that works.
Hey, Saiko.
Do you think I'm any good the way I am right now?
Any good?
It feels like I'm forcing out a story every day.
Like in order to force a character to move,
I'm thinking up strange, fantastic settings.
But—
That's no good, is it?
I've gotta come up with a good character.
Something that'll move on
it's own, like Eiji's characters do.
If I can do that, I think I can write
something better than what I've done so far.
I'm not sure why I can't come up with anything,
but it's summer vacation,
so I think I'm going to take a break and
try and think of something on my own.
Alright.
That's fine.
I'll try—
No,
I'll make sure to write an
interesting name this summer.
Eh? Mashiro?
Yeah, with the runner-up
of the recent "Story King."
Mashiro's drawings would be perfect.
What do you think?
Please don't ask the impossible.
Of course that wouldn't be okay.
Ashirogi Muto is a two-man team, after all.
That's what I figured.
Guess I'll have to try somebody else, then.
Sorry.
How about if he works as an assistant?
An assistant?
You don't mean for Niizuma?
Yeah.
If you were an assistant working
for a 16-year-old mangaka,
it probably wouldn't make you feel too great.
Mashiro is younger and his drawings are great.
It's alright even if it's just for the summer.
Ashirogi Muto sees Niizuma as their rival.
There's no way he'd go.
Couldn't you at least ask him for me?
We're all editors, right?
We should help each other out.
Fine, but only if they both agree to it.
I don't think they will, though.
Takagi!
I'm so excited!
This is the first time you've
invited me out on a date.
So, what where do you want to go?
Movie, karaoke, or bowling?
Bowling.
Shuujin.
He didn't come today, either.
He hasn't contacted me at all
since the break started, either.
I guess writing mainstream really is tough.
That was fun!
I can't believe you scored over 200!
Hey, you broke 100, too.
I was just going easy on you.
Next time, I want to go to karaoke.
Got it.
Yay!
Sorry, my phone's ringing.
Hello?
It's Hattori.
You writing?
Yeah,
sort of.
I'm writing,
but nothing I'm quite satisfied with.
I see.
I actually called because someone is
asking for Mashiro to be an assistant.
An assistant?
I thought I should see if you were
okay with it before talking to him.
I see.
Well—
Actually—
right now I've got writer's block.
I can't really come up with anything.
I'm just making Mashiro wait
and I feel bad.
So if Mashiro says he'll do it,
I won't stop him.
Got it.
Eh?
Me, an assistant?
Yeah, and it's alright if it's just for the summer.
But we're both aiming for
serialization right now.
I talked to Takagi about it already.
He said he wouldn't stop
you if you decided to do it.
Takagi said that?
Yeah, but you'd be working for Niizuma, so—
Niizuma Eiji—
Just make sure that your series continues
and wait for us to get serialized as well.
Roger!
But I might already be
number one by then, you know.
Of course, it's completely up to you.
I was actually reluctant to even ask,
but decided to just in case.
I understand.
I'll do it!
Mashiro as an assistant?
Yeah, helping out another mangaka.
Even though he's part of Ashirogi Muto?
I'm the one making him wait, after all.
Despite the fact that I'm the one who
asked him to write manga in the first place.
Well then, we should be getting home.
Takagi.
Am I getting in the way?
If I go to Eiji's, I should
be able to learn something.
It'll benefit Shuujin as well.
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
I'm Otsuki Nanami, the voice of Ijunin Erina.
Next
Episode
I'm Azuki Miho, the voice of Saotomeji Reika.
Next time on "St. Visuals—
Wrong show, Nanami.
Conceit and
Kindness
Next time: Conceit and Kindness.
If your dreams are conceited,
they're better off not coming true!