Niizuma
Yujiro,
I'm sorry for being so rude up until now.
I'll have meetings from now on.
And I'll write the names, too.
W—What happened?
Everybody kept calling me a genius,
so I guess I got a bit conceited.
Is that so?
If you do all that, it'd sure
take a load off my mind.
Keep it up and becoming the best
writer in Jack won't be just a dream.
Not a dream?
The early results for chapter three have you in—
third!
That's better than chapter two.
Chapter three is better?
I guess we were wrong, then.
I don't regret it, though.
We helped him make chapter five even better
and got him to start having
meetings and writing names.
Yeah!
I'm gonna become the most
popular mangaka out there!
I'm glad he got Eiji to start writing names.
I've come this far for Shuujin.
I'll make sure to learn something before I go back.
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Jealousy and Love
C—C—C—Crow!
Crow!
Crow's Holy Sword!
The most popular mangaka, huh?
If I become the most popular mangaka in Jack,
please give me the power to
end one series I don't like.
Making him first is supposed to be my job—
We'll just have to cross that
bridge when we come to it.
Last two!
A—Alright then, I'll come by
tomorrow at five to pick up the chapter.
We can have a meeting after that, alright?
Roger!
I'll be back tomorrow at five.
R—Right.
Niizuma-sensei only has two pages left to do.
Alright then, good luck.
Yujiro.
I've been meaning to ask you something.
What is it?
The order manga show up in Jack
is the popularity order, isn't it?
It's not in the exact order, but—
Not including gag manga, the popular
manga tends to be toward the front,
while the less popular series are in the back.
Why do you do it that way?
Why?
Most other magazines do it
the same way, don't they?
I have to say, I think it's unfair.
If they're in order of popularity, the readers will
know which are popular and which aren't beforehand.
There are probably a lot of kids out there who
only read what they know everybody else likes.
I think it would be fairer to rotate the order every week.
What are you saying, Fukuda!
That should change the questionnaire
results at least a little as well.
The order the series appear in
is creating a gap in the results
Hey,
why don't you keep your mouth shut
until you've actually been serialized!!
Please just hear me out.
After all, I'm just stating my opinion.
I also don't like that whether a manga is popular
or gets axed is based solely on the questionnaires.
Isn't that like saying the editing department
isn't able to judge whether or not
a manga is interesting on their own?
Fukuda.
I wouldn't be saying that in the
editing department if I were you.
But, I'm a nice guy, so I'll
listen to what you have to say.
Alright then, please listen to this.
In Jack, if you don't have a flashy
chapter one with an exciting climax,
you're on the fast track to getting cancelled.
In the worst case, a series can be cancelled
depending on its chapter three results.
Because of that, writers are afraid to write a manga that
starts out simple and gradually gets more interesting.
That makes all the new
series you see feel the same.
I think the editing department should
have a bit more faith in new series
and at least let them run until
the first volume comes out.
If we gave all the new series that much leeway,
we'd only be able to run about
five new series every year.
But I think there are manga out there that
have potential to get better over time.
Like a main character who starts
really weak, but gradually gets better.
With the current system, a series like that
would never be popular from the get-go.
Yeah,
but even for a series like that,
it just has to have a good
enough hook to not get cancelled.
Why?
Are you writing a series like that now?
No, well—
I'm writing a name where the main
character starts out as a winner.
Well, it just sounds like you're asking for
special treatment in case your series
doesn't do well in the beginning.
I'm not going to argue about
how the magazine is set up.
That's the editing department's job.
You just focus on writing your manga.
Bye, then.
Fukuda-sensei!!
That was amazing!
Especially the part about rotating the order.
That's great.
And sounds fair.
I've never even thought about that before.
After listening to you, it sounds like too
much is based on the questionnaire.
That isn't good for manga.
It'll be the end of manga if the authors
are only writing to get more votes.
Right?
My favorite series in Jack is "To Love-Ru."
What?!
Really?
But it's definitely at a
disadvantage in the questionnaires.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Why is that?
It's a little ecchi,
so nobody wants anybody else to know
that they picked it as one of the top three.
Even I was too afraid to choose
"Ichigo 100%" on the questionnaires.
He submitted the questionnaires?
I'm sure there are grade schoolers out there who have their parents send their questionnaire in.
But it's too embarrassing to choose "To Love-Ru!"
I know what you mean!
Oh, so it's because they're ecchi, huh?
But,
"To Love-Ru" is a shounen manga
for real men, right?
Yeah, we know exactly what you mean!
But I'm sure they're taking that into account.
You think so?
It gets center color pages every once in a while
and the volumes seem to sell pretty well.
Right there!
What? Where?
That's what I'm saying.
The volumes are selling well, so
it should get more color pages!
But I don't think it's good for the
magazine's image to have so many ecchi—
What're you saying?!
Ecchi drawings and panty shots
are what define a shounen manga!
They're every guy's dream!
"We are going to change Jack."
I think I understand what you meant now.
Your ideas are really interesting.
I agree with you.
Any other thoughts?
Yeah, I think the contents
of the stories should change,
but first, rotate the cover
page and the series order.
That's fair.
Oh!
Then, on the inside of the cover,
add a fold out swimsuit poster of an idol.
Huh?
Oh!
No, you can't do that!
That's just something you want to see!
As if!
All the other magazines do it, so Jack should too!
You need an idol in a magazine made for guys!
No, you're wrong!
It's a mark of pride that Jack doesn't
need tricks or models to sell magazines!
What?
Who needs to be proud of
something stupid like that?!
Excuse me—
Eh?
Couldn't you guys save it until
after we finish this chapter?
It's gotta be finished by tomorrow, after all.
S—Sorry.
You're right.
Sorry 'bout that.
I guess I got a little carried away.
Niizuma.
How much longer do you have?
Oh, I'm already finished.
How long do you think it will take you guys?
Whoa!!
The backgrounds are amazing!
This is great!
I said so, didn't I?
Nakai's technique is amazing.
Since coming here,
I've learned the most from watching Nakai work.
You don't have to flatter me.
Just hurry up and do the inking,
whiteout, and screentones.
Right!
It looks like I can leave the rest up to you guys.
You going to sleep?
If you do, you won't wake up until
Yujiro comes tomorrow, right?
Yeah, why?
When he gets here, you'll have your next meeting.
Don't worry, I'll do it.
You should probably think about where you
want the story to go next before you fall asleep.
I see.
You're right.
I'll have just woken up, so if I don't do that,
I'll be too easily persuaded.
Well then, I'll give it some thought.
I'm thinking about
adding
another ally
to the story.
What do you think?
I thought I said I'd only help out with chapter five.
Hm—
A new ally it is.
Notebook, notebook—
Where is that notebook?
Notebook?
Here it is.
It's a very important notebook,
so I put it in my desk drawer.
I need one who can fly—
Maybe that one from the sparrow
manga I wrote back in 4th grade.
Niizuma, is that a list of characters?
I've been drawing manga ever
since I started grade school,
so there are a lot of characters I can use.
My house in Aomori was really
in the middle of nowhere.
Most of my classmates lived
at least half an hour away.
They all played games and stuff
to keep themselves occupied.
But the closest game stores were pretty far away.
And we didn't have much money anyway,
so I just drew manga all the time.
But I always liked doing that best anyway.
Well, I guess most people
who decide to be mangakas
have been doodling in
notebooks since they were kids.
They probably think they're
good enough to make it big.
At least, that's how it was for me.
Even Crow was a character I
came up with in grade school.
Grade school—
Heroes are just legends
Hero Sore wa Densetsu
Hero Legends
Heroes are cool
Hero Sore wa Kakkoii
SUPER
Heroes are the burning energy that resides in you
Hero Kimi no Naka ni Aru
Atsui Energy
Through some turn of events, you've been driven up against a wall
Douiu Wakedaka Dai Pinch
But do not fret or worry, and put on a big, bright smile
Sonna Toki Koso
Waratte Miro yo
Take on the foes who stand before you, no matter how big they are
Kyodai na Aite ni Tachimukae
Now, muster your strength, and charge!
Sou sa Ima, Hashiridasun da
Everyone's smile—
Minna no Egao o
Especially her smile—
Ano Ko no Egao o
Gives me the endless power I need
Omoeba Minagiru Mugen no Power
Heroes are the legends
Hero Sore ga Densetsu
Heroes are super cool
Hero Totemo Kakkoii
Heroes are the burning energy that resides in you
Hero Kimi no Naka ni Aru
Atsui Energy
Mom, it started!
The burning energy
Moeru Energy
Alright, I'll be there in a minute.
Your drawings are so good.
That's right.
Up until my uncle died, I
was always drawing manga.
At home and even at school.
It was so fun
that I lost all track of time.
I got so absorbed in it.
I've loved manga since I was a kid
and always wanted to be a mangaka.
I should have something that
even Shuujin would want to write.
Huh?
Niizuma.
It's a bit sudden, but is it
alright if I quit as your assistant?
Huh?
So you figured something out?
Yes.
That's good to hear.
Then stop here and go home.
Hey, you can't just quit in
the middle of something.
Leave after we're finished with chapter five.
You helped come up with this one, didn't you?
Fukuda—
It's alright.
I can keep up with Niizuma
without anybody's help.
Just leave it to me.
Nakai—
Fukuda, you can quit
whenever you want to, as well.
I can't leave you here all by yourself.
I'll stick around to help
at least until I get serialized.
I'll make sure and get serialized myself, too.
All you need to become a mangaka is
a little will-power and a lot of persistence.
I won't ever give up.
Thank you very much!
I'll be sure and get serialized, too!
I want to be in Jack with everyone else!
Alright then, let's finish this up.
Right!
Takagi
It feels the same no matter what I do.
And if you make it too original,
it isn't mainstream anymore.
Oh crap, Azuki's anime.
We are all holding a ticket to bright, sparkling days.
And a ribbon that—
I wonder if Azuki'll be in this one.
She only had a few lines last week.
"St. Viz Girls?"
Oh, sorry.
Do you have to work early tomorrow?
No, I have tomorrow off.
Record that for me, will ya?
Huh?
Chapter five, 19 pages.
It looks good, guys.
Good work everybody.
Good work.
Alright then, Yujiro, let's have our meeting.
Sure.
Um—
I wasn't here for very long,
but thank you very much.
It really was short, wasn't it?
I would have liked you to stick
around at least another couple weeks.
We don't need three assistants.
Niizuma is quick.
Even so—
Don't worry about it.
After all,
I managed on my own up until the other day.
Two assistants is plenty.
It feels like there's something
different about you today.
Is that so?
I'm going to be writing a name
soon, so please take a look at it.
Definitely.
There's something obviously different about him.
Well, I guess most people
who decide to be mangakas
have been doodling in
notebooks since they were kids.
Even Crow was a character I
came up with in grade school.
My dream from back then
of becoming a mangaka.
The characters I loved back then.
I know there's one.
A character whose story
would be perfect for Shuujin to write.
What is it you wanted to show me?
I'm not telling.
You'll just have to wait and see for yourself.
Is it that exciting?
My room's on the third floor.
Both of my parents are at work
and my brother's still at practice.
I don't think I've been in a
girl's house since kindergarten.
I—It's even more girlish
than I thought it would be.
Look.
I got an email from an
online cellphone novel publisher.
Really? That's great.
Dear Miss Miyoshi.
We have received your story "Love Apart."
and would love to publish
any further work on our website.
Depending on popularity, we may also
make it available for mobile distribution.
Isn't that awesome?
Well, I was the one who wrote it.
Well, Saiko and Azuki were the models,
so I guess it was really easy to write.
Takagi-sensei,
please write more for me.
What?
Give me a break.
I've still got a name to write.
If this was all you wanted me to see,
why didn't you just forward it to me?
I wanted to surprise you
and celebrate with you, too.
And—
I wanted to see you.
Then why didn't you just come to my house?
But your brother is there.
Well, it is summer break.
And he's got the day off.
I wanted to be alone.
Alright, but I'm only going to help out a little!
I'm not going to write it all!
It's really hard trying to
come up with a battle story.
And I'm a manga writer.
Alright.
Then, you can write your scenario here.
You can even use my computer.
Okay?
You don't want to be with me?
No, that's not it.
Then, stay and write here!
You can leave before my parents come home!
Fine, you win.
I'm gonna close your mail, okay?
Okay, go ahead.
Huh?
Oh, that's the submission page.
Submission Form
Working Title
Working Category
Working Summary (400 Character Limit)
Love Story
That's the form you use to send in your story.
Sci Fi
Fantasy
Suspense
Horror
Non-Fiction
Comedy
Mystery
Submission Form
Working Title
Working Category
Working Summary (400 Character Limit)
Love Story
Sci Fi
Fantasy
Suspense
Horror
Non-Fiction
Comedy
Mystery
Historical
Other
There sure are a lot of genres.
Of course there are.
Comedy
Mystery
Historical
I'm home.
Welcome back.
Where's grandpa?
He went to the hot springs
with Takayama next door.
I see.
It's not much, but here's some money.
Put that with what I've made so far.
I'll be sure and pay back
everything I've borrowed so far.
Here they are!
There're a lot, too.
Whoa, what is this?
These are really bad.
I remember them being better than this.
Oh, here it is.
This was a story about becoming the
best suspicious-looking guy in the world.
I remember there being something in here.
No, not this one.
I got an idea for a shady detective
and wrote it in a different notebook.
Here it is.
Con Detective Hikake
He's a con artist who tricks criminals into
exposing themselves in dead-end cases.
Most of the books at Shuujin's were manga,
but he had some detective novels, too.
We were talking about doing a battle manga,
but detective manga are really
popular in shounen magazines, too.
Shuujin can do this.
And he'll probably be great at it.
Hey, Saiko.
Huh? Mashiro?
Huh?
Gimme the phone.
I want to tell him the news.
Don't worry, I'll tell him.
Is that Miyoshi?
Yeah.
She got an email from a
publisher asking her to write more.
Isn't that great?
It's all thanks to you and Azuki.
Did you watch "St. Viz Girls" last night?
Oh, no.
Azuki said she wasn't in it.
I recorded it, though.
People were saying online that
they wanted to see more of her.
What?
It's probably just a matter of
time before she gets popular.
Where are you right now?
Huh?
I'm at Miyoshi's.
And the name?
Oh, I'm doing it.
Takagi, that line's great!
Shuujin.
I didn't want to say this, but—
Huh? What is it?
Why are you with Miyoshi?
"Why?"
Because I like her, of course.
Even so, you can't write anything if
you're always distracted, can you?
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm working hard every day.
With Miyoshi at her house?
Yeah, that's right.
It's normal to want to spend time
with the person you like, isn't it?
You and Azuki are the strange ones.
You're right.
Sorry.
But, it's already August.
I know.
You'll really be done by the end of the break?
Yeah.
I'll let you know when I'm done.
Just wait a bit longer.
Got it.
Later, then.
Bye.
Even I—
Even I want to be with Azuki!
Huh?
Mashiro Moritaka
I have a question...
Azuki, please don't get mad, but
why are you okay with not seeing me?
I wonder if she's busy.
She is starting to get more popular.
Azuki—
It feels like she's getting
further and further away.
Shuujin as well—
along with Miyoshi.
You have one unread message
Azuki Miho
Good Morning
It's because I want to treasure the
promise we made. If we wait until
our dream to meet comes true,
our joy and love will be even greater.
Love
Azuki.
Where are you going?
The studio.
I've decided.
If he can't come up with a name
by the end of summer break,
then I'll write something myself.
For Azuki!
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
Hey, Hattori.
Next
Episode
What is it, Hattori?
Just call me Yujiro.
But your last name is Hattori, isn't it?
Next time: Two and One
Two and
One
Double Hattori.
We are the bridge to your dreams.