Heroes are just legends
Hero Sore wa Densetsu
Hero Legends
Heroes are cool
Hero Sore wa Kakkoii
SUPER
Heroes are the burning energy that resides in you
Hero Kimi no Naka ni Aru
Atsui Energy
Through some turn of events, you've been driven up against a wall
Douiu Wakedaka Dai Pinch
But do not fret or worry, and put on a big, bright smile
Sonna Toki Koso
Waratte Miro yo
Take on the foes who stand before you, no matter how big they are
Kyodai na Aite ni Tachimukae
Now, muster your strength, and charge!
Sou sa Ima, Hashiridasun da
Everyone's smile—
Minna no Egao o
Especially her smile—
Ano Ko no Egao o
Gives me the endless power I need
Omoeba Minagiru Mugen no Power
Heroes are the legends
Hero Sore ga Densetsu
Heroes are super cool
Hero Totemo Kakkoii
Heroes are the burning energy that resides in you
Hero Kimi no Naka ni Aru
Atsui Energy
The burning energy
Moeru Energy