I'll leave the solids to you.
All right!
Azuki's moving tomorrow, isn't she?
We have three days to bring in the finished manuscript.
We must use all the time we have
to make it even a little better.
All right, I'll do my best on it.
I'll wait for you.
I'll always wait for you.
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Every worry floats up to and fills the spring sky
shinpaigoto bakari ga tsumoru haru no sora wo
I look up, look down,
miagete utsumuite
and find myself looking back up at the sky
mata kao wo ageteru
I swore I'd find myself in this town
kono machi de mitsukerutte kimeta jibun
I tuck away all my important things into my heart for safekeeping
nakushicha ikenai mono wo mune ni
Your love
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Early Results and Real Deal
Aren't you going to get that?
Ignore it.
It's probably someone selling
newspapers or something.
Mashiro! Takagi!
You're there, aren't you?!
It's Miyoshi.
Ignore it.
There's no way I can do that.
When she finds out later that I was
here, she'll beat the crap out of me.
Where's Mashiro?
He's drawing.
We've got our deadline in
three days, so don't bother him.
Hey!
Sorry for the intrusion.
Miyoshi!
Mashiro— kun.
What?
Why didn't you tell Miho your email address?
Eh?
Ah, you're right.
I know hers, but she still doesn't know mine.
Unless you email her at least
once, she won't know, will she?
So even though you met with her
after graduation, you didn't tell her?
I wasn't thinking about stuff
like email addresses then.
We both only said one sentence to each other.
One sentence?
What?
I'm not telling you.
Well fine, but you need to tell her your email.
She can't even email you to say she's moving.
I know that because you told me, Miyoshi.
I didn't tell her I told you.
Anyway, at least send her an email once.
It doesn't matter what it's about.
I don't want the first email I
send her to be random like that.
I do think it would be better to do it
sooner, but I need to finish the manuscript.
So I can't email her now.
Okay.
Then go ahead and say
that I told you she's moving.
Then I'm sure she'll send
you a very nice email in reply.
All right, work hard, you two!
Miyoshi sure is a good person deep down.
I know, right?
Okay, we must get this done by the deadline!
I guess the younger they are, the faster they progress.
No, that's not the only reason for this.
It's like they put their souls into this.
What do you think?
I can really feel your desire
to win against Niizuma in it.
This is an amazing manuscript. You did really well.
Yes, thank you very much!
We're finally done. Now I can email Azuki.
Want to go get something good to eat?
Ah, no. I'll be okay for today.
I pulled two all-nighters, you see.
Sorry.
I see. You two do look tired.
Okay then all that's left is to think of
the comment to put in on the last page.
"We worked really hard to draw this, and we would
be delighted to hear your impressions" is fine, right?
Okay, let's go with that.
All right, then.
Ah, do you two have bank accounts?
No, I don't.
Me neither.
Your payment for the manuscript is given
via a bank deposit, so make one by June.
I hate to ask, but how much
is our manuscript payment?
I knew he'd ask.
Newcomers all get 9000 yen a page.
He's definitely calculating that right now.
Now all that's left is the questionnaire results.
Hattori's assessment was good as well.
Seems like we can win.
Are you okay?
Oh, see you later.
"See you later?"
"This is Mashiro. Good evening."
Maybe "Good evening, this
is Mashiro" would be better.
The greeting should be first.
How are you doing?
Spring is here. It's getting warm
No, I don't need this sort of thing.
I should apologize for writing those weird
things to her in class that made her cry.
Oh, and also for not sending
her chocolate on White Day.
Also, sorry for not saying
much on our graduation day.
It's kind of all just apologies—
O–Okay— Now to tell her about us running
in Next and the day it goes on sale—
Huh? I can't type anymore?
Why?
Character limit?!
True, 5000 characters—
No way, I've already typed that much?!
A–Anyway, I have to read
over what I've written so far.
I've looked over it again and again—
It's already 9am—
Well, whatever.
Send!
Okay, guess I'll go to sleep.
An email?
Azuki Miho
Mashiro, your email was way too
long *lol*. Thank you, and
congratulations on getting serialized.
Azuki Miho
Azuki?! So fast!
Mashiro, your email was way too
long *lol*. Thank you, and
congratulations on getting serialized.
Mashiro, your email was way too
long *lol*. Thank you, and
congratulations on getting serialized.
So short!
Mashiro, your email was way too
long *lol*. Thank you, and
congratulations on getting serialized.
I'm really happy she replied, but—
compared to my 5000-character long one—
Okay, I'll just send one in a sort of joking way—
Azuki, isn't your email a little short?
We can finally email each other, so
shouldn't we talk to each other more?
Okay. Send.
Time for bed.
Another fast one?!
Azuki Miho
If you've got that kind of free time, then please draw some manga *lol*! Meh!
Meh!
"Meh?"
That's so cute. She had this kind of side?
And it's still so short.
But Azuki's right.
Hello?
Hey, Shuujin—
in case we get first place in the questionnaires,
start thinking about making a serialization
name for "Money and Intelligence."
We don't have time to play around.
Do it!
Understand?!
What's with that authoritative tone?
Hey, Hattori!
Yes?
This Takagi-Mashiro team has
gotten way better from the name stage.
Yeah, I really thought so.
This thing's really interesting.
Oh, thank you.
Even the ever-scathing Aida—
Vice Editor-in-Chiefs Yahagi and
Heishi both gave good assessments.
This really could beat Niizuma.
That will never become wide-reaching popular.
There's no way Niizuma Eiji will lose.
Yakusa North High
Opening
Ceremony
Takagi, Mashiro!
Yakusa North High
You're both in the same class!
Miyoshi, you showed up?
Of course I did!
You're in class 1 with Suzuki
and Saitou from Ake-middle.
Why am I the only one in class 3?
It's true.
Saiko, do you think we should have a pen name?
Takagi Akito
It would be a pain if this gets out in school.
Like what happened with Ishizawa.
Mashiro Moritaka
I guess so.
I'm fine with it if you are, but
will we make it in time for Next ?
I'll email Hattori and ask.
WJ Hattori
About a pen name
If you can come up with a pen name
today, there's still time to change it.
The sooner, the better. WJ Hattori
He said if we do it today, we can make it in time.
Then could you think of one
during the entrance ceremony?
Me too, me too!
That's okay. We don't need
you to think about it, too.
Don't hit me, okay?
I wasn't going to!
I think it would be best to
make it a blend of our names.
Maki Morito or something—
Well, I guess then no one would figure it out.
Note: The name is made up of the kanjis; "A" from "Azuki,"
"shiro" from "Mashiro," "mu" meaning "dream" and "to" meaning "come true."
Ashiro Muto
How's this?
Ashiro Muto.
"So Miho and Mashiro's dream comes true."
Miho would love this, don't you think?
Why am I not in it?!
I'm not in it either.
You don't have anything
to do with it, I'm the author!
Okay, then—
Ashiro Muto
Ashirogi Muto
Note: Added kanji "gi" from "Takagi."
Ashirogi Muto.
What do you think, Mashiro?
Well, it's kind of cliché, and sort of embarrassing.
Huh? How?
Well, uhh, I don't really care, so—
Then it's decided.
Sounds good. I'll contact Hattori.
Sure.
This is good.
A
shiro
This really might make Azuki happy.
gi
Mu
to
Ashirogi Muto
Okay, send!
That was fast!
Azuki Miho
Mashiro, your pen name is as long as your emails *lol*. I hope our dreams come true just like your pen name says.
I hope our dreams come true
just like your pen name says.
I'm so glad.
Just like I thought, Azuki also—
But—
Azuki Miho
Mashiro, your pen name is as long as your
emails *lol*. I hope our dreams come true just
like your pen name says.
It's really short again!
This is a sample issue I just got.
Thank you so much!
Ours is—
There!
Awesome!
Ashirogi Muto
Survive this World
with your Wits
and Money!
Survive this World
with your Wits
and Money!
This World is All About
Money and
Intelligence
It's a real manga now!
It's totally moving!
Yeah!
Management
Meeting Corner Open Hours
Niizuma Eiji's Crow.
It really is good.
Its sense of speed and intensity
makes you want to read it all at once.
I read ours countless times
since it had became a name—
so I don't know if it's interesting or not anymore.
No, ours is more interesting.
You're really confident, aren't you?
Ah, sorry.
It's just my personal opinion,
but I felt like ours was a more interesting read.
Yeah.
I think you'll win, too.
The story Takagi wrote matches
perfectly with the drawings Mashiro drew.
They draw out each other's good points.
That's my number one
reason for thinking you can do it.
Thank you very much.
But, Niizuma's story and drawing
go well together too, don't they?
Certainly—
both Niizuma's artwork and
story are far from a newcomer's.
Especially the artwork.
But this can't be helped.
He's already been drawing for ten years.
But Niizuma will split votes
with the other battle manga.
Ours doesn't have any works that overlap it.
So then—
You're saying that if we went
one-on-one with him, we would lose?
A magazine will always have
lots of works running in it,
so I don't think this is a bad way to operate.
More than anything—
the most important factor for success
in Jack is the questionnaire results.
Questionnaires—
Jack's manga are ranked every week
according to these questionnaire postcards.
It's a serious battle.
Just like boxers standing in the ring every week.
These questionnaires have me swinging back
and forth between happiness and worry.
I've taken every place from second to twentieth, but—
I've never once been first.
I would really like to get first, even if it's just once.
That's a dream I've had ever since I got serialized.
When do the questionnaire results come out?
There are two; the early result and the real deal.
Early Results
The early result is a hand-counted total
of a hundred cards that came early.
For the main magazine, they come out
on Tuesdays, the day after it goes on sale.
Real Deal
The real deal comes from a
lot more questionnaire results—
obtained by putting a thousand
randomly chosen cards in a computer.
It gives us in detail which manga
got the "most interesting" vote,
as well as the 2nd and 3rd most interesting vote.
It also gives us the average age of the senders,
allowing us a ranking and gender ratio for each age.
That comes out on Friday for the main magazine,
but for Next it's around two
weeks after it goes on sale.
The early report and the real deal—
So it happens twice.
To be precise, we take them one more time,
but we only tell the authors up to the real deal.
So— would you like me to
tell you the early report, too?
The real deal counts for everything, though.
If the real deal is everything,
then hearing the early report doesn't
have much of a meaning, does it?
We have the early report so authors can
get their readers impressions in a chart—
and find out what they want for
what comes next in their story.
There are some that don't want to
hear the real deal or the early report.
They say, "Only tell me when I'm in first."
So even if we don't hear the early report—
No, I'm a little curious about both of them.
Please tell us.
Got it.
I'm pretty sure we can do it, but—
Just as I said before,
we don't know for certain what
will be popular, beforehand.
So you should be prepared for any kind of results.
Right.
Well, there's still quite a while
before the results come out.
The best thing you can do is
think about your next work.
Alright.
Well then, I'll contact you
when we get the early report.
Questionnaires, huh?
It's really put a damper on my
excitement of running in Next.
Well, I think we can win, so—
Shuujin.
We can be serialized while
we're going to high school.
I can finish the names, but what about you?
If it means getting serialized,
I'll do it even if it kills me.
Even if we get first, I don't think
Hattori will try to serialize Money and Intelligence.
Now that you mention it, he did say "next work."
It's normal to get serialized
after getting first in Next.
Especially if we beat Eiji, who
is already up for serialization.
But Hattori won't leave the idea of us only
getting serialized once we're out of high school.
However, if we take first place—
and make a name for serialization
that Hattori approves of—
Certainly.
In that case, he would consider it.
And if he's still reluctant, we can
talk it out with people above him.
Saiko—
Our goal is to have an
anime adaptation by eighteen.
We have to do that much.
It would be all right to have chapter one
overlap with what runs in Next, right?
Let's head back and get started on it right away.
Right!
"In the end this world is money! Smart
people win using the power of money!"
Man, that's so cruel to end it with that line!
This is good.
That finishes off chapter one's fifty-one pages.
Oh, it's an email from Azuki!
Don't look.
Azuki Miho
I saw Jack Next. Your drawings are really
amazing! I don't know much about it, but
your manga really stood out from the others!
Azuki Miho
Azuki—
She really makes sure to send an
email whenever something happens.
So today was the day Next goes on sale?
Oh, that's right!
We sure are incredible.
We got so wrapped up in our name
that we forgot about the release date.
Azuki said it stood out in Next.
That's our Azuki. She has a good eye!
I'm going to reply with "Thank you."
Alright, let's get going on chapter two!
Name
Whoa—
He's actually swimming in all the money.
Isn't this going a little too far?
It's okay. In chapter three all
that money gets taken from him.
Hattori?
Is this the early report?!
Yes? This is Takagi.
Yes.
For the early report, we're first!
YES!
But don't get relaxed.
You two have thirty-three votes.
Niizuma has thirty-one votes.
A difference of two votes?
There's a possibility he'll overtake you.
Below that is twenty-six— nineteen—
That Hattori guy—
If Eiji loses, it will put a damper on our serialization.
No, there's no way Niizuma Eiji will lose.
The real deal will definitely be in our favor!
Hey, if this keeps up and you get first, is Money and Intelligence going to head for serialization?
Now that you mention it—
If we get first place in Next—
Please think about us moving toward serialization.
No, they have still only entered high school.
But the authors probably
really want to, don't they?
They sure do—
Then, we're done.
So should we call Hattori?
Tell him we finished a new name.
Don't tell him they're serialization
names for Money and Intelligence yet.
Got it.
You want to surprise Hattori, right?
Sorry for the wait.
Hello.
Thanks for coming.
First, I just got the results for the real deal.
Your rank for the real deal is—
Third place.
Third?
It's unfortunate you didn't get first, but
third place for your first
appearance in print is quite good.
First place is Niizuma Eiji with 503 votes—
We lost—
Below that was 312 votes.
to Niizuma Eiji—
You two had 308 votes.
No— even more than Eiji—
In other words, you got proportionately the same as in the
early report, but Niizuma and the others increased.
Niizuma, you got first place in the questionnaires.
Congratulations.
What are questionnaires?
When you ran your work for the Tezuka Award,
I told you that you placed second, didn't I?!
Ah, I probably just said "Okay"
because I didn't understand.
I think I can make the character
designs for serialization even better.
I can probably go with this protagonist.
This is fine.
This boy doesn't need to know
about the questionnaires and stuff.
You brought a name for a new
work with you, didn't you?
This is no good!
No good?
While you were talking to us,
I came up with a lot of ideas.
I think we should redraw this now.
And to be honest—
from the shock of falling from first to third,
I'm not really in the mood to talk about this—
But I told you over and over, third is incredible.
If you get disheartened at
something simple like that
you won't be able to make it as a mangaka.
Having said that, the early report was good.
I understand how you feel.
How about we end it here for today?
Sorry—
Shuujin, I want to try for something mainstream.
To be popular in Jack, I think you
have to be mainstream, after all.
But we were told there's no point
in us trying something mainstream.
I think we should just do what we've been doing—
That was the plan to win against Eiji in Next.
But we didn't win.
Eiji got 503 votes out of 1000.
More than half the voters
thought it was interesting.
A manga that two out of ten people
will definitely think is interesting—
That's not good enough?
If we throw out half the votes from
the outset, there's no way we can win!
I was thinking about it
when I saw Eiji's work, but—
even for mainstream, it wasn't
just the artwork that was good.
You could sort of see the author through the work.
It gave off a strong sense of uniqueness.
Yeah, I thought so, too.
A kind of "How does he do this?" feeling.
Shuujin, you're great at making settings,
so if you make a simpler setting
than what we've had so far
and use mainstream
characters, I think we can do this.
In other words, it must be mainstream!
Saiko—
There are a bunch of people who do mainstream,
so being number one is hard.
In other words, doing cult is just running away!
What we're aiming for is number one in Japan!
Cult stories can't be number one.
Let's start again from scratch!
Right!
What are you doing, throwing
scraps of paper all over the place?!
Uh—oh!
Hey, hurry, we have to pick it up!
Y–Yeah!
The boring everyday gets to me sometimes,
BETAAna genjitsu ni tsubusaretemo
but I always get back on my feet, standing strong
uchinomesareta jibun hiroiatsumete
No matter how many times the end approaches me,
nando owari ga otazuneretemo
I'll push my own back forward, keeping me on my feet
sono tabi ni jibun de jibun no senaka otoshita
If I get lost in the meaning of continuing what I do,
tsudzuiteku imi ni nayami
I'll rid myself of those worries and keep myself going forward
sono mayoi sae tachikitte yuku
Always
itsumo
The straight edge that draws the outline of my future
mirai no rinkakusen egaku massuguna jougi wa
is made of all the courage I've mustered up until today
ikutsumo no kinou no yuuki de dekiteru
I'll climb over the tall wall that I never thought I'd face,
omoiegaita no to chigau takaikabe koe
and continue my journey, going past the vanishing point
shoushitsuten no mukou e susunde
This winding road seems to never end,
harukanaru winding road
but it is the road I personally chose
hoka no daredemonai watashi ga jibun de eranda
I set my tiny dreams on fire,
kasukana yume wo zenbu moyashita
and broke through the dark with its light
sono hikaru de yami wo saite
Now that I've broken down the wall,
kudaita kabe no mukou ni
I can see my sky once more
jibun no sora ga mieru
Oh, so this is where Jack is made?
Next
Episode
That's Niizuma Eiji!
Could you be Ashirogi Muto?!
You know who we are?
Next time, Battle and Copying
Battles and
Copying
When you embrace your dreams, rivals appear.