Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love