What do you think you're doing?!
Hattori.
You said that in three years we'd
be good enough to do mainstream.
But you weren't planning
on getting our cult manga,
"Money and Intelligence," serialized
in the first place, were you?
If that's the case, then we
want to do mainstream now.
I'm telling you that you're more likely to make
it big with something that isn't mainstream!
No, we want to do mainstream.
Niizuma is the genius type.
Even if you do a mainstream
manga, you can't beat him.
Most of us here in the editing
department don't think even Niizuma
can become number one in Jack.
How can you say there's no
way we can beat Niizuma?
Again?!
Our mainstream manga has never
been published alongside his.
I can tell just by looking at your name.
What you're really saying is that this
name has no chance of beating him, right?
Fine!
You have six months!
If you can't convince me by then, you
two will listen to what I have to say.
And if you still insist on doing mainstream
after that, then I'll step down as your editor.
Is that alright with you?
Yes!
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Debut and Impatience
Mainstream, huh?
Personally, I don't think there's any room
in Jack for more mainstream right now.
Truth is, with a mainstream manga,
you can't really know if it's any
good until you see the actual votes.
Either way, this name is no good.
I can tell you right now that even in
Next, this wouldn't make it to the top.
First of all, there's nothing original about it.
There are a lot of new writers who bring
in names that take pieces from past hits,
but nothing that'll become a hit itself.
Right.
Hattori really does know his stuff.
Most of the mainstream battle
manga that newcomers bring in
has a lot of the same elements.
The important things are:
A simple, easy-to-understand setting.
A clearly stated reason why the main character
is fighting that the reader can relate to.
Intense battle scenes with
clean, easy to follow composition.
Enemy characters with either a similar battle strength
as the protagonist or some sort of interesting ability.
It's always good to throw in a
cute heroine too, if possible.
Add a bit of humor and some tear-jerker
scenes, and you would have a strong story.
Thank you so much!
Giving us so much advice even though we're
going against your recommendations—
I'm certain that you guys aren't
suited to writing mainstream manga.
I'm just telling you the basics of what
makes a good mainstream manga.
I said tear-jerker scenes will
make a strong story, right?
Yes.
The readers have a good eye.
If you are trying too hard,
they will see right through you.
So you're saying it'll just fall flat instead?
Right.
It's like, you can't force the story—
No, how should I put it—
Just write without thinking about it!
Niizuma!
He's back—
They decided to go with Crow for serialization,
so I told them I wanted to head home
after saying goodbye to Ashirogi-sensei.
Why's he acting so friendly towards us?
Niizuma, what do you mean
by write without thinking?
Hey!
I don't think up a name first.
Or rather, I don't want to.
Even though everybody else
should feel the same way,
all the editors keep going on and
on about them. I think it's strange.
They made me write a name for
"Yellow Hit," but it wasn't any fun.
You sure drew those names quickly a minute ago.
You drew 25 pages for chapter two and 23
pages for chapter three in under 30 minutes.
Even if you did already have them
planned out in your head, that's fast.
Oh, that was a lie.
I hadn't even thought about them yet.
What?!
I said that because I figured they
wouldn't let me serialize Crow
if I told them I didn't have anything planned out.
How were you able to do all that so
quickly with nothing thought out?
The characters have a life of their own!
Move!
I want to help them move and see what they
will do next so much that I just can't stop!
Aren't you the same way?
Characters coming to life and moving on their own—
That's what manga is to him?
Crap.
He's nothing at all like these two.
This won't help them at all.
Movement!
Niizuma.
Huh?
It's great that you enjoy drawing so much,
but it's normal to start with a name.
That's where you make all your decisions.
Hm—
I guess you can't draw
something you haven't thought of,
so I probably think about
something before I draw it too.
Niizuma.
Yes?
That's enough.
I figured out how we
should draw our manga now.
Is that so?
When will I see your next manga?
I'm not sure about that,
but we're going to get serialized
and catch up to you as soon as we can.
That makes me happy.
Let's both give it our best.
Just make sure that your series continues
and wait for us to get serialized as well.
Roger!
But I might already be number
one by then, you know.
I don't think you should be so naive
as to think you'll become number one that easily.
Yujiro, I'm going home.
Oh, and I have no money, so
could you take me home by taxi?
Well then, Hattori.
Let's call it a day.
Ah, right. Good luck.
Right! Thank you!
Niizuma Eiji and those two.
Manipulating us adults like that—
I should have made them
take this home with them.
Oh?
There's something else in here.
Wow!
He brought in a character sketch, too.
There sure is a lot of feeling in this drawing.
It's like you can see the
passion in everything they do.
Even so, what makes or breaks a battle
manga is how well you can draw movement.
Niizuma, I wouldn't have thought you would
be the kind to like "Money and Intelligence."
Oh? I thought it was really good.
But it looks like Ashirogi-sensei
is going to do a battle manga.
That's too bad.
Eh? Those two?
I can't really imagine that—
Rather, I don't think they'll
be able to do it well.
I think Ashirogi-sensei will
become my biggest rival.
Especially the little one.
He'd climb his way up even if he was on his own.
Why do you say that?
You can't tell?!
No, sorry. I have no idea.
You brought those assistants
over earlier today, right?
His eyes were completely different then theirs.
It's like they were calm, but
with an inner intensity like fire.
Just like the eyes of the hero of a battle manga.
What's with this kid?
Is this the way manga geniuses see things?
Niizuma, wait! What are you doing?!
Calm down!!
Niizuma Eiji.
Hattori was talking about it before.
He really is the genius type that'll get a
hit just by writing whatever he wants to.
Yeah.
The type that'll become a huge hit
without even trying are those just like Eiji.
You said before that you figured
out how we should draw our manga.
Were you serious?
Yeah, but it's more like—
I've just gone back to square one.
Mainstream or whatever, there
are two ways to go about it.
Either have the characters
draw themselves like Eiji does,
or be calculating in a way that doesn't
make it look like we're being calculating.
Sounds complicated.
A reason to fight.
Depth.
Comedy.
Tears.
There are a lot of obvious things that we
never really thought about it up until now.
If we include everything Hattori mentioned,
we can come up with something amazing.
I guess so.
Wait a minute.
I'm the one who has to write a calculated
story that doesn't look calculated, right?
Sounds like writing it without
thinking would be better, though.
Oh man! Mainstream really is a lot harder to do!
Don't worry, I'll help out.
But in any case, our real battle starts now.
Lame.
That's sounds like the line out of
the last chapter of some manga.
Prince Eight
Prince Enterprise
Crazy Prince
Thank you very much!
I wasn't good enough, huh?
You won't be able to keep going if you get
so down every time you fail an audition.
Just do your best next time.
Why don't you go change, then we can go.
Alright.
St. Visual's
Girls Academy
It's a late night anime starting this summer
called "St. Visual's Girls Academy."
Would you like to try out for the role of a student?
They're asking all the offices
for recommended new-comers.
It looks like they want someone with
good acting and some singing ability, too.
Yes please!
Let me go, as well!
Good acting. Singing ability.
What about you?
I'll go too!
The audition is the Sunday after next.
The particulars are all in here.
Got it.
Thank you.
St. Visual's
Girls Academy
HACHI           OUJI                              STATION
Sorry!
I'll be there soon!
Miyoshi Kaya
No Subject
Mashiro
Miho!
Sorry I'm late.
Kaya!
Hachioji was pretty far, wasn't it?
Don't worry about it. It kinda
feels like I'm on vacation.
By the way—
H—Huh?
Why'd you change?
I thought we promised to show
each other our school uniforms.
I went home and then went
to my training school first.
If I went in my uniform, I'd stand out too much.
Oh yeah, how was your last audition?
What was it again? That one
about the stuck up princess—
Oh, sorry.
You don't have to apologize.
I guess I just wasn't good enough.
Woah! So this is your new place?
Kaya-chan!
Even bigger than before.
W—What is?
Welcome.
You're starting to look so grown-up.
You think so?
Let's take your stuff upstairs.
Thanks.
Momo! How've you been?
Better be careful, grown-up-looking Miyoshi,
or you'll wrinkle your uniform.
I still act about Mina-chan's age, so it's okay.
"St. Visual's Girls Academy."
What's this?
St. Visual's
Girls Academy
Oh, um, that's for an audition I have coming up.
Audition?
Oh, I'm terribly sorry! My legs are just SO long.
Or—
Huh? Wha? Huh?
Oh my! What's this doing in a place like this?
Who's on earth could it be?
I bet stuff like that happens.
You're probably right!
It is an all girl school, after all.
No way.
Yeah it does!
Birds of a feather flock together, right?
What's that mean?
I think you're using that wrong.
Really?
It's great that you got another audition.
Y—Yeah.
Oh~ how the seasons change.
Forever waiting.
For a brilliant dream.
Kaya, I'm leaving your towel here.
Okay, thanks.
Oh~ how the seasons change.
I wonder if it's okay for me to audition.
Hey, how are things going with your boyfriend?
Oh.
I'd like to know as well.
Have you kissed yet?
Um, well, we haven't really
been able to go on many dates.
Takagi's been really busy lately.
That must be a bit lonely.
But I really want to see him do well.
Takagi and his partner Mashiro
are both working really hard.
Really?
Yep.
In order to write a battle manga,
Takagi even had me beat him up.
And Mashiro is copying hundreds
of drawings for practice.
It's really amazing.
They're giving it all they've got
and not complaining about how hard it is at all.
Miho.
What is it?
You don't want to do the audition?
Eh?
You haven't been yourself all day.
If you don't want to, you can just say so, right?
If they give you any trouble, I'll just beat 'em up.
Thanks.
I'm just not very good yet
and I have no confidence in my singing.
So I was wondering if it's even okay that I audition.
But, I'm gonna try.
I want to try harder like Mashiro.
Good luck.
Thanks.
St. Visual's Girls Academy
Ashirogi Muto
Are you alright?
Oh, I'm sorry! I guess I was just nervous.
Thank you.
Nanba Kana, you're up.
Coming!
Well then, I should get going.
Alright then, please state your agency and name.
Prince Eight. Azuki Miho.
Thank you for seeing me today.
Sorry it took so long.
Don't worry about it.
You come up with anything good?
No, not yet.
Something funny and tear-jerking—
Just planning out something funny is hard enough.
It's best if it flows naturally with the story.
Flows naturally, huh—
It's kinda scary to think that Eiji
wrote that chapter of Crow for Next
without doing a name first.
But I'm glad we got to meet him.
Now I'm more determined than ever.
Yeah, me too.
It's a good thing that even after a
year we can still get fired up like this.
A year?
Yeah.
It's already been a year since I asked
you to pair up with me and write manga.
I guess it has.
It was the day before midterms, wasn't it.
Time sure flies, but that's life.
Let's head over to the studio.
R—Right.
It's really hard to write a
good mainstream manga.
I wonder if we'll ever figure out
the tricks to doing this smoothly.
A whole year, huh?
Even if we say we want to get
an anime by the time we're 18—
Azuki?
Yeah.
Azuki Miho
Report
I got a part as a girl named Saotomeji Reika
in an anime called "St. Visual's Girls Academy."
It's only a small one, but I'll do my best.
Azuki got her debut role.
No way!
Eh? I can read it?
Wow, she really did!
That series running in Young Three, huh?
It looks like a pretty small role, but that's great.
Azuki really got a role as a voice actress.
Hey, we already had our debut in Next.
That means both of you are a little
bit closer to your dreams, doesn't it?
I don't know much about voice acting,
but don't you become popular
a lot faster than with a manga?
I guess that's true.
And if she starts showing up on TV,
she'll probably get popular really fast.
After all, she is especially cute.
If you're worried, just ask
her to stay out of the media.
I'm not worried!
Besides, I can't ask her to do that.
What are you texting for, then?
I've got to say 'Congratulations'.
Congratulations! Even if you get a role as a heroine,
please wait for me.
Send!
This really makes me impatient, though.
Just as fast as always.
Dummy!
Azuki Miho
Report
Mashiro, you dummy! *lol*
That doesn't sound like you at all!
You don't believe what I
said after graduation?!
If you ask again, I'm gonna
ignore you! *lol*
Azuki—
Sorry.
I'll do my best to have a
heroine role ready for you.
Saiko?
What's the matter?
Am I an 'M'?
Huh?
A masochist. I kind of like only
encouraging each other through texts—
and I sort of enjoy it when Azuki scolds me.
She got upset, huh?
And even though I'm crazy about her,
I'm still okay with not seeing her.
You guys are so weird.
But Azuki is crazy about you too,
so she must think the same way, right?
Yeah.
I'd say you're more of an 'N'.
An 'N'?
Yeah, 'N' for narcissist.
Don't you have too many syllables in there?
Note: In Japanese, "Narcissist" is often pronounced, as just "Narsist."
No, I'm saying it right.
Oh, I see.
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
Miho!
Next
Episode
Congratulations on your debut!
Thanks, Kaya.
Announcement!
I have decided on my dream!
Huh?
Next time: Wall and Kiss.
Wall and
Kiss
I'm also going to try my
hardest to achieve my dream!