Niizuma
Eiji, the Shounen Jack people are here.
Hi, Niizuma. I'm Sasaki, an edi—
Niizuma?
What a room—
I have a condition for going to Tokyo.
A condition?
If I become the most popular mangaka in Jack,
I want the authority to end one series I don't like.
W—What're you saying, Niizuma?
There's no way that'd ever be allowed.
How can you even joke about that?
I want to have it as motivation.
Your intention to become the most
popular mangaka is admirable.
Once you've experienced
the hardships of going pro,
and after one of your works
has made it to the cover of Jack,
if you still feel the same way, ask me again.
I see.
Then I'll go to Tokyo.
He's still a child to give in so easily.
Or was he testing me?
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Every worry floats up to and fills the spring sky
shinpaigoto bakari ga tsumoru haru no sora wo
I look up, look down,
miagete utsumuite
and find myself looking back up at the sky
mata kao wo ageteru
I swore I'd find myself in this town
kono machi de mitsukerutte kimeta jibun
I tuck away all my important things into my heart for safekeeping
nakushicha ikenai mono wo mune ni
Your love
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Uncertainties and Expectations
Tezuka Award deadline
Finish manuscript!
Saiko!
A lot of them are still just text, but
I've written up a bunch of outlines.
Okay.
Let me know if any of them interest you.
Got it.
How were they?
None of them were bad.
But none of them were particularly good either.
I see.
Then take a look at these!
Here's my fourth notebook full.
That was fast!
Did anything catch your eye?
I think "The Rabbit and the Camera" was the
most interesting of everything I've seen so far.
Oh, that one.
It's hard to think of something good.
I guess I'll check out the library.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I just haven't been sleeping much.
Yakusa City
Akehi Middle School
Then I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah, see ya.
Shuujin!
Sorry about this.
About what?
This is all because of my selfish request—
But you're working so hard to help me.
I just feel bad.
Don't get the wrong idea.
I do support you and Azuki.
But it was pretty frustrating to hear we
didn't even make it to the final round.
I wanna try for it next time
and see how far we can get.
Strange?
Yeah!
Takagi seemed totally exhausted.
Really?
Why would the smartest kid in our
grade suddenly start pulling all-nighters?
Do you think he's trying to get
into a really tough high school?
Have you heard anything, Miho?
I'm going to become a mangaka!
I came to tell you that!
I'm gonna do the illustrations
and he's gonna write the story.
Hello?
Are you still there?
Hey!
You pay a lot of attention to Takagi, don't you?
Huh?
You really like him.
W—What was that?!
I'm just a little interested
because he confessed to me!
Really now?
"Really" what?
"One in a Hundred Million"
How were they this time?
"One in a Hundred Million" was really good!
Really?
That was my favorite one too!
The protagonist is the same age as us?
Yeah. I thought 15 was the best age
since it's a shounen manga and all.
He's honest and has a strong
sense of right and wrong.
He should have a few friends, don't you think?
That's standard. Of course he will!
And they'll all have their own signature moves!
Sounds like we're ready to start.
Let's do our best on this one too!
There's not much time left though.
We still have 20 days until the Tezuka deadline!
Let's finally head back to the studio!
Yeah!
One in a Hundred Million.
In the near future, everyone is assigned a rank
by a huge government-built supercomputer.
When someone turns fifteen, a
machine is embedded in their brain.
The counter inside their brain announces
their rank every night at midnight.
It's a crime for lower ranked
humans to defy those above them.
In the worst cases,
such defiance leads to the poisoning and
eventual death of a lower ranked person.
Our heroes are trying to put an
end to this ranking world order.
They fight against the high ranked
humans who like the world the way it is.
But they come to realize it's really the
supercomputer controlling the humans.
So it becomes a battle between
humans and this AI machine.
And from there, we'll have the crazy battles.
Maybe with a killing machine
created by the supercomputer!
It'll definitely feel like a shounen
manga if we have fighting robots.
The protagonists should have weapons too!
Swords!
A sword?
A common aspect in lots of popular manga.
Naruto, One Piece, Bleach, Gintama,
and many other works have swords.
That's true.
I didn't notice until you mentioned it.
'Cause no one reads manga
looking for this sort of thing.
Then they should have light sabers!
Yeah, that'd fit perfectly with our setting!
Finish manuscript!
Must finish manuscript!!
Tezuka Award deadline
Finished!
Yes!
Th—This feels like a winner!
Yeah! I gave it my all and I'm
actually satisfied with the artwork.
We can do this. We can do this!
We'll definitely win the Tezuka Award with this!
Yueisha
W—Why isn't he saying anything?
Did we mess up?
Is he too shocked for words?
Is it worse than before?
This is way better than the last one.
What?
I'm surprised.
You've corrected the weaknesses I mentioned
last time, in both your artwork and your storyline.
The story is especially great.
Thank you! This time I
used Mashiro's input as well.
These light sabers were a great idea.
They make the action scenes even more vivid.
Those were Mashiro's idea as well!
I suggested swords to begin with though!
All the popular works right
now seem to have swords.
Thank goodness. Hattori approves of it!
I see.
This is it.
Oh, right!
Today is September 30th.
Why don't you guys try submitting
this for the Tezuka Award?
Yes, sir!
Oh, right—
We'll definitely win the next Tezuka Award.
And they made the deadline—
They just might be able to do it.
No, they definitely can!
I'll get you guys some coffee if you'd like.
Really?
Results for the Tezuka Award come out in November.
There's nothing to do but wait until then.
Write your next work with the
intention of submitting it to Next.
Next?
You know what Shounen Jack Next is, right?
It's a special Shounen Jack issue
that comes out three times a year.
It runs stuff by both amateurs and pros.
If a work is recognized in Next, it
has a chance of getting serialized.
Next is like a gateway to the pros.
O—Of course.
You think we can make it into Next?
It's nothing to be surprised about!
If this wins the Tezuka Award, you guys
will be on your way to your debut!
But, there's no guarantee that
we'll win the Tezuka Award.
That's true—
But even if you guys don't win the Tezuka,
it wouldn't be embarrassing
to submit this somewhere else.
That's what I think.
So next time, write with publication as your goal!
Is it really that good?
I mean, I'm confident, but still—
Your story was great.
I think we can do it.
Really?
Then I'll believe and hope for the best too!
At least my stories don't
read like light novels anymore.
The story is especially great.
The story was really good.
If we don't get it, it'll be because of my artwork.
If we want to stand a chance against the pros
in Next, I have to get better at drawing!
If this wins the Tezuka Award, you guy will be on your way to your debut!
If we win the Tezuka Award,
we can debut as mangakas!
No good?
Nothing stood out to me, Takagi.
Was your last one a fluke?
I've been kind of worried
about the Tezuka Award.
I couldn't really focus; I just kept thinking
about whether we could really win or not.
I totally understand!
I've been trying to practice drawing,
but all I can think about is the award!
I keep dreaming about winning and
debuting and getting serialized—
Yeah, it's so hard to stop fantasizing even
though we know it's not gonna be easy.
Hattori said the results don't come out till November.
We still have a whole month to wait.
Hello?
You have midterms coming up! What
do you think you're doing right now?
Huh?
Hurry up and come home!
2nd Semester        Midterm Rankings
Top 20
Shinbo Hoshitsugi
Iwase Aiko
Takagi Akito
Shuujin!
No way. Why is he?
Man, I don't have any good ideas—
It's already been three weeks
since we met with Hattori.
Everyone was really surprised
that you only placed third.
Huh? What're you talking about?
Midterm exam rankings.
Oh, but that doesn't really matter, does it?
It's more than good enough to get into North High.
But—
Coming up with a name is more important!
Something good enough for Next.
Oh, wait a sec.
What about a story about a mangaka who
gets a machine that produces names for him?
What the heck is that?
If you're going to have a machine like that,
why not just have it produce finished works?
Oh.
Producing a name is only half of it.
This is terrible. My ideas are just getting worse.
I might not be able to write anything at all.
No need to get so depressed.
It's from Yueisha!
What?
But why would they be calling? It's only October!
P—Pick up!
Yes, it's Takagi.
Hello, it's Hattori from Jack.
Hello.
Are you writing?
Y—Yes, doing my best.
I'm actually calling about the Tezuka Award.
Wh—What about it?
You're in the top eight!
Really?!
The final judging will be November 10th.
I'll contact you again when the results come out.
You're already guaranteed to at
least see your name in print!
Really?
Yes.
Got it.
Understood!
Yes.
Yes, thank you very much!
He said we're in the top eight!
We have a 50/50 chance of winning!
Oh man, a 50% chance!
W—Wow.
Last time, there were seven works left in the final
round. Then one winner and three honorable mentions.
We've made it this far. We
can totally make it all the way!
Hattori thought it was great too. We can do this!
We could win—
Tezuka Award
Winners
Announced
Novice Winners
Takagi Akito
Mashiro Moritaka
We could win the Tezuka Award!
Azuki, I've won it!
Mashiro, you're amazing!
Congratulations!
I'm not gonna be able to concentrate
on anything until the results come out!
Let's take a break till the results come out.
But what about Next?
There's no way we'd be able to make something
good when we're like this anyway, right?
Yep, no way.
Tezuka Award Final Round
It's finally time.
Yeah.
I wasn't that calm before now,
but today is really a killer.
Stop, you're making me even more nervous!
I—I wonder if there's a winner's ceremony.
W—Who knows.
But your uncle won the Akatsuka Award.
You didn't hear anything about a ceremony?
I wasn't even born so how could I know?!
Oh, right.
I—I think I'll read some manga!
Times like this call for some—
Dragonball, don't you think?
Shuujin, that's all you ever read.
'Cause I don't know what else to read!
Jeez, don't cry. I'm sorry.
This is pointless. I can't focus at all.
Can't they hurry and call us already?
Just a thought but maybe
they won't contact us today?
What?
Hattori said that the final
round of judging was today,
but he never said he'd call us today.
We don't know what time the judging ends.
These things sometimes take
till midnight to get sorted out.
I completely forgot till just now.
If that's true,
m—maybe I'll call him instead!
I just need to ask for Hattori, right?
We don't know anyone else anyway.
Wait, but we have his email address.
O—Oh right. Which one do you think is better?
Probably email—
Or no, phone!
Which one!
Whichever!
Which one?!
I—It's him!
Incoming call
Yueisha
I—It's Takagi.
We were cut at the final round.
Four works were chosen, one winner
and three honorable mentions,
but we didn't make it.
Seriously?
After praising us that much—
Can we still trust Hattori?
The story is especially great.
B—But I mean, we did better than before.
We didn't even make it to the final
round for the monthly prize, but this time—
I can't tell Azuki about this.
I just can't.
Here are three drafts for Next.
Huh?
I wanted to bring you more, but
I just couldn't write fast enough.
We can't stay depressed.
We're still gamblers, right?
We're gonna get an anime
by the time we're 18, right?
Right!
It wasn't bad but—
It wasn't Next level, huh.
It's alright. Take your time and work on it.
You're Mashiro, right?
Ishizawa.
Yeah, and the next door neighbor—
I saw the new issue of Jack.
What's with this art?
It doesn't look like manga at all.
I can't believe you had the guts
to submit something like this.
Weren't you embarrassed?
That's harsh, Ishizawa.
Ishizawa, why are you here?
Oh look, it's the one who wrote the storyline.
I was wondering why you
lost your number one place.
I never even guessed it was 'cause you
were writing manga with Mashiro.
It's got nothing to do with you.
Do you know what the difference between
you guys and this Niizuma Eiji,
who won both first prize and runner up?
It's the artwork.
In evaluation and storyline, you both got 4 out of 5.
But for illustrations, he got
a 5 while you guys got a 3.
I bet the 3 was a pity score too.
In other words you have the talent,
but Mashiro's holding you back.
Ishizawa, that was too blunt.
I'm just telling the truth.
You know—
You're really asking for it—
Stop, Shuujin!
It's true my artwork's not good enough.
Look, even he admits it.
Have you even drawn a 31-page manga before?
Nope.
But I'm way better at drawing than him.
Wanna see?
If you paired up with me, we'd definitely—
Shuujin!
Apologize to Mashiro right now!
What're you doing?
I'm gonna tell a teacher!
Go ahead!
I'm telling you to apologize!
The boring everyday gets to me sometimes,
BETAAna genjitsu ni tsubusaretemo
but I always get back on my feet, standing strong
uchinomesareta jibun hiroiatsumete
No matter how many times the end approaches me,
nando owari ga otazuneretemo
I'll push my own back forward, keeping me on my feet
sono tabi ni jibun de jibun no senaka otoshita
If I get lost in the meaning of continuing what I do,
tsudzuiteku imi ni nayami
I'll rid myself of those worries and keep myself going forward
sono mayoi sae tachikitte yuku
Always
itsumo
The straight edge that draws the outline of my future
mirai no rinkakusen egaku massuguna jougi wa
is made of all the courage I've mustered up until today
ikutsumo no kinou no yuuki de dekiteru
I'll climb over the tall wall that I never thought I'd face,
omoiegaita no to chigau takaikabe koe
and continue my journey, going past the vanishing point
shoushitsuten no mukou e susunde
This winding road seems to never end,
harukanaru winding road
but it is the road I personally chose
hoka no daredemonai watashi ga jibun de eranda
I set my tiny dreams on fire,
kasukana yume wo zenbu moyashita
and broke through the dark with its light
sono hikaru de yami wo saite
Now that I've broken down the wall,
kudaita kabe no mukou ni
I can see my sky once more
jibun no sora ga mieru
Next
Episode
Takagi really let him have it!
H—He did, didn't he.
But manga? Takagi's writing manga?
S—Seems like it.
Next time: Regrets and Understandings.
Regrets and
Understandings
It's great to have dreams, isn't it?