Hey, Hattori!
Yes?
This Takagi-Mashiro team has gotten
way better since the name stage.
Yeah, I really thought so.
This thing's quite interesting.
Oh, thank you.
For the early report, we're first!
Yes!
But don't get relaxed.
You two have thirty-three votes.
Niizuma has thirty-one votes.
That Hattori guy—
If Eiji loses, it will definitely put
a damper on our serialization.
No, there's no way Niizuma Eiji will lose.
I just got the results for the real deal.
Your rank for the real deal is—
Third place.
Third?
Niizuma, you got first
place in the questionnaires.
Congratulations!
What are questionnaires?
I think I can make the character
designs for serialization even better.
I can probably go with this protagonist.
This is fine.
This boy doesn't need to know
about the questionnaires and stuff.
Saiko—
There are lots of people who do mainstream,
so being number one is hard.
In other words, doing cult is just running away!
What we're aiming for is number one in Japan!
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
On the inside of the sleeve of the shirt you gave me,
kimi ga kureta shiroi SHATSU sodeguchi no ura
the word "FIGHT!" was embroidered in white
shiroi shishuu de tsuzurareta "FIGHT!" no gomoji
Even though I tried so hard by myself
mou hitori demo ganbareru ki de ita
I wonder why my tears still fall?
doushite namida ga deru no darou?
Your love
I'll entrust myself to the wind since we are connected
kimi to tsunagatteru kara boku wa kaze ni makasete
I will walk
aruite yukeru
now there's power in my chest, because I
shinjiru Power kono mune ni
Believe your love
Battles and Copying
Are you really sure about this?
Yup!
Whatever you say, but why
are you going so far for this?
Don't worry about it. Just
make sure you don't hold back.
Hey, what are they doing?
Boxing?
No, that's mixed martial arts!
Hey, keep it down.
We're not playing around here.
Good luck, miss!
Hey! Come on already!
S–Stop it, I give, I give!
Stop it, miss!
What happened, Shuujin?
You got beat up by Miyoshi again?
No, I asked her to do this.
I thought I didn't truly understand the feelings
of the people who fight in battle manga.
Isn't this kind of different?
Well, maybe you have a point—
Did you learn anything?
Fighting is scary.
That's really the truth.
We can't make a story about a protagonist
who's afraid of fighting, though.
Saiko, congratulations
on placing third in Jack Next!
If it were the main magazine,
it would be a different story.
But getting that rank in Next has no meaning.
Huh? Why?
I told you, didn't I?
What we're going for is first.
Otherwise, it's not enough to get us serialized.
Well, that may be true—
But—
In the end, everything in the world has ranks.
I really don't like it.
So, Saiko, why are you drawing Dragon Ball?
Isn't that someone else's manga?!
You're not supposed to copy it, right?
I decided to find scenes that
stood out in ten battle manga—
and copy at least a hundred pages from each.
A hundred pages each from ten works?!
If I can't do this much, I don't think
I'll be able to draw a battle manga.
Doing this will help me
make my own original drawings.
What does he mean?
Well, it's kind of hard to explain, but—
To put it simply, what we did for
Next was a cult type manga.
We thought that to get first in Jack,
we need to do a mainstream battle manga.
So, we're going to try that.
I don't really get what you mean
about this mainstream and cult stuff.
But that's why Mashiro is
studying Dragon Ball's artwork
and why you asked me to fight you seriously?
Basically.
I didn't really learn much from it, though.
You guys are amazing.
How can you face forward and head
straight for your dreams like that?
You know, right?
In the second year of middle school, I went all
the way to the national championships for karate.
But I knew there were tons of
people there stronger than me,
and I also had exams to take, so I quit pretty easily.
Even Miho keeps trying and doesn't get
discouraged when she fails an audition.
So, Azuki failed some auditions?
Didn't you know?
You didn't get an email about it?
I never got one like that.
I get it.
I didn't send her an email about
getting third, which wasn't good enough.
I'm sure Azuki will only tell me
when she overcomes hurdles—
and gets closer to her dream, too.
That seems like her.
I see— Miho sure is strong.
Most girls, when they fail or feel down,
want to be encouraged by the person they like.
I'm going to send Azuki a quick email.
Eh? Why?
To tell her that the results from
Next weren't good this time,
but I'm using it as motivation to try harder.
So, you do have some sense in you?
That will definitely encourage Miho.
Okay, send!
That was fast!
Is that Miho's reply?
They're short, but when they write
to each other, they're always fast.
Well? What did Miho say?
"Kaya told you something unnecessary, didn't she?
Tell her I said, 'Stop talking so indiscreetly!'"
Ah. She found me out.
That's our Azuki.
I'm so jealous of you guys.
I want a dream, too!
Maybe you could do karate again or something?
I don't like combat sports anymore.
I want a more girlish dream.
But I'll never be as good as you guys—
I have no good features.
You're a nice person, Miyoshi.
You've got big tits, Miyoshi.
Is that the way you look at me, Takagi?!
What Mashiro said was way better!
Eh, well you're a girl, so having
a big chest is a good feature!
I wasn't talking about that!
Ah, you total pervert!
Dreams, huh?
You lech!
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack Square
Yujiro, Niizuma Eiji will be
starting Yellow Hit in issue 33.
Yes, sir!
My luck is finally turning around.
Does he have the music blasting again?
I told him several times that the
serialization meeting was today.
I'm going to go have a meeting with Niizuma!
He's just lucky.
Niizuma had been submitting works
for the Tezuka Award for a while,
and he was just the first one to notice.
Niizuma
Niizuma! Niizuma!
NIIZUMA!
Yo, what's up?
It's cool how you always suddenly appear like that.
Turn down the volume!
I've told you to keep your phone
nearby so you can answer it.
How?
You can just leave your cell phone
in a place you can see it, right?
When you get a call, it will light up.
Don't mess with what's on my desk! Don't touch it!
I–I got it, sorry!
Huh? What're you drawing?
It just hit me.
It's really interesting.
Kitchen trash, kitchen trash, combustible traaaash—
Don't draw stuff like that!
Here, Yellow Hit's serialization was decided!
Serialization?!
All right! All right! All right-pin!
I really wanted to be serialized.
I'm happy.
I'm going to be the most popular author!
C–Congratulations.
What?
He's actually happy.
Then don't make it so hard for me
to get in contact with you, dammit.
Also starting is Takano-sensei.
You're going first, starting with issue 33.
The ending manga are—
When is my deadline?
It's starting issue 33, so—
for the color pages, it's the third of June.
The center color page for chapter two, plus the
rest of the chapter, are due on the thirteenth.
Easy peasy.
Crowy cawy.
I hope you'll come to pick it up then.
Well, there are still a bunch
of things, like assistants—
I'll leave that to you.
Do you think this is good for a protagonist?
I think it's fine, but—
If you don't like it—
then next, I'll try something similar to Ishinomori-sensei's "Kamen Rider"
or Hara-sensei's "Hokuto no Ken."
I want to go for a dramatic battle manga.
Uh, I said this was fine.
Anyway, the name—
Right—
In a world where demons run rampant,
there is a sword which houses many demons.
The protagonist is the only human who can wield
the sword without giving into its evil magic power.
When defeating demons who try to steal the sword,
a demon will also appear from within the sword,
which he must defeat.
If the sword is stolen, the world
will be taken over by the demons.
However, if he defeats all
the demons within the sword,
the world will be at peace.
I thought I should try to stay
with swords, like we decided.
Then I got the idea to have the
sword be the main part of the setup.
So honestly, what do you think?
It kind of feels old.
Like it's an idea that's been done to death—
No—
Maybe it's all right to do this sort of
cliché setup for a mainstream story.
The problem will be how the story
plays out and how we show the battles.
Anyway, I think we have to
bring it and show it to him.
Okay.
Thanks for waiting.
Sorry for having to meet at the train station.
No problem.
Okay, let's go.
I kind of feel pathetic though.
Being an assistant to a sensei who's
only in the second year of high school.
Don't say that.
If you're upset about it, just try to
get your own work serialized faster.
Nakai, wasn't it?
I'm twenty-one, but how old are you?
Thirty-three.
Sorry.
No, don't worry about it.
Hey, are we starting today? Work?
Well, about that—
It seems he's done all of
chapter one by himself already—
Eh? Then he doesn't need us, right?
Well, there's still chapter two and past that.
At worst, you can meet him.
At least you can meet him.
so you're better off getting
used to him as soon as possible.
Strange kid?
Anyway, I have to get the
color pages and go right back.
But I'll give you a good introduction, so relax.
What are you doing?!
This isn't your new series, "Yellow Hit!"
It's Crow, the one you did for Next!
Serialize that one.
I finished the first chapter with sixty-four pages.
This is bad—
What're you doing?!
Hattori, you said that in three years,
we'll be able to compete with mainstream.
You never intended to serialize the cult story—
"Money and Intelligence"
in the first place, did you?
So starting now, we're doing mainstream!
Didn't I tell you that you would get
popular without doing mainstream?!
No, we want to do mainstream!
Th–This is crazy!
I don't know how to say this—
Listen, lots of newcomers come
in that have drawn mainstream.
Or, well, it's not that they come
in thinking it's mainstream,
it's just all they're exposed to are
games and mainstream manga.
So, that's all they can draw.
But Takagi can write
stories that aren't like that.
That's your weapon.
But in reality, what's
popular in Jack are things like—
Bleach,
Hunter X Hunter,
Naruto,
One Piece,
all mainstream battle manga.
You are ten years too early to be comparing
yourselves to popular serialized manga!
First, you should be thinking about what
kind of manga you can get serialized, right?
After all that effort, you got third in Next,
that's why I said you should stay on the road you're already on!
But getting third in Next won't
carry us to serialization, right?
All right.
If, in the next issue of Next, you
get the top spot for a newcomer,
third or better overall,
and get within the top eight as a
one-shot in the main magazine,
I'll think about moving it toward serialization.
However, you two can't
get popular with mainstream.
This name isn't interesting at all.
Then—
we'll think up and bring in a mainstream
manga you think is good enough to run.
Shuujin—
You too, Takagi?
I just told you, doing mainstream isn't the best
way for you to utilize your talents and get popular!
Why don't you understand?!
Hattori is having a rare bout of anger.
It's because they're promising newcomers.
Ashirogi Muto.
Do you think they're promising?
Ah, yes. I'm more of an Ashirogi fan than Niizuma.
Though I'm concerned that they
are the type that editors will like,
but who won't do well with the readers.
Excuse me.
Hello?
In the end, you finally made
an excellent setup for a story.
We should be talking about
how to make use of that!
Then I'll do a good setup for mainstream—
What?!
Niizuma Eiji's manuscript for his
new series won't be done in time?!
Niizuma Eiji?!
New series?
What are you saying?
You were just going to get the color
pages and the finished chapter—
with time to spare, weren't you?!
What he was drawing wasn't his new series!
It seems he was drawing the first
chapter for "Crow," not "Yellow Hit!"
"Crow?!" The hell! What are we going to do?!
It's two days before the
deadline for the color pages.
There are nine days until it goes to print,
so I asked if he could draw it
in time, but he refuses to do it!
He doesn't want to!
He can't just not draw it!
We've never had a hole for new serialization
in the entire history of the magazine!
Heishi, let me have the phone for a minute.
Ah, okay.
I'm putting the editor-in-chief on.
This is Sasaki.
Please bring the manuscript he did draw,
along with Niizuma himself, here.
The editor-in-chief just told
him to bring Niizuma Eiji here.
Niizuma Eiji coming here—
Niizuma, we're going
to the editorial department.
I've always wanted to go to
the Jack editorial department.
Does he not understand what he's done?
No—
If I become the number one
most popular author in Jack,
please give me the power to
end one manga that I hate.
He's the kind of kid who'd
say something like that—
I have no idea what he's thinking.
If I'm going to be this kid's editor,
I can't be half-hearted about it—
Dammit, I was too naive!
Niizuma, where's the manuscript you did for the first chapter of "Crow?"
I think you're standing on it, Yujiro.
Heading out!
Sorry!
That's all for today.
I'll call you later.
I wonder if they'll let me
quit being an assistant here.
Niizuma, answer me honestly.
If you have assistants, how many days
will it take you to do sixty-four pages?
I don't want to draw that.
Crow's rival is discovered!
I don't care if you want to draw it or not!
I'm asking if you did draw it,
how many days would it take?!
I've never had assistants before.
If I had four days, I think
that would be plenty.
How many?!
Damn! If the editorial department tells him to
just shut up and draw, everything will be fine?
No, from how he's been acting, he probably
won't be any easier on the editor-in-chief.
Is this the place? It sure is a pretty building.
Hurry!
I brought Niizuma with me!
Ooh, sure is big.
So this is where Jack gets made?
That's the genius—
Niizuma Eiji.
I'm sorry!
I should have kept a better eye on him.
He can't concentrate with people around,
and whenever I called him on the phone,
he always just said he was doing fine.
But when I asked him just now in the taxi,
he said that if he starts
now, he could make it in time.
Then hurry up and have him get drawing!
It's no use, he says that he doesn't
want to draw "Yellow Hit" anymore.
So what if he doesn't want to draw it?!
It was decided in the serialization meeting!
How can he be so selfish?!
Yujiro, let me see that manuscript.
Ah, yes, sir.
They've already decided to
serialize Niizuma, huh?
Why didn't you tell us?
Should I have?
I wasn't trying to hide it or anything.
Of course we would want you to tell us.
He's our rival, after all.
Rival, huh?
Well, coming from these two, that's how it is.
Did you read this?
Take a look at it.
Yes, sir.
"Crow" got first place in Next, didn't it?
Yes.
It actually got the majority of the votes.
The first newcomer to do so in a while.
Are you saying we should serialize this?
Editor-in-Chief, the preview at the end of issue
32 for "Yellow Hit" has already been printed.
I'll take responsibility for that.
With the idea of doing "Crow" in mind,
are the names for chapters two and beyond made?
Eh— No, I'll have to ask the author himself.
Huh?
Where did Niizuma go?
This all happened because of him, and yet—
I knew it!
Like I thought, you're Ashirogi Muto.
I thought "Kono Yo wa Kane to
Chie" was the most interesting one,
is that getting serialized?
No—
Ah, that's too bad.
I could never come up with something like that.
It was incredible!
The natural genius?
You're a two-man team, so that's how your
story and drawings were both so deep.
Is he making fun of us?
Niizuma, what are you doing?!
These two are the ones who
wrote "Money and Intelligence."
I love that manga, I'm their fan.
It's only by one year,
but the fact that you're younger than
me and could draw that is amazing.
Still, I'm really happy to
hear you're close to my age!
I would really like to be
comrades, working in Jack together.
I'm from Aomori, so I don't have
any friends my age here yet.
Let's be friends, please.
Working together?
Comrades?
Be friends?
No, he's not making fun of us.
He's being serious.
Got it. We can have a proper introduction later.
But first, did you do a name for
chapters two and three of "Crow?"
If you did, then they might be
okay with serializing "Crow."
Then we'll serialize "Crow."
So you have the names? Where?
If they're at your apartment, we can go get them.
They're in my head.
It's no use if it's in your head!
Tada!
If you give me an hour, I can put them on paper.
In one hour?
Chapter two is 25 pages and
chapter three is 32 pages!
I've already got them in my
head, so it won't take long.
Crow!
Ah, over there, not here!
You'll be in the way of the meeting.
No, if you wouldn't mind,
I'd like him to draw it here.
Yes, please.
O–Okay.
You two, if you watch Niizuma Eiji,
you'll understand that you don't
stand a chance doing mainstream.
You have to realize that you shouldn't
be starting a mainstream battle.
Understand—
I'm done.
That wasn't even thirty minutes, let alone an hour.
I'll bring this over to the editor-in-chief.
You come, too, Niizuma!
Sorry for the intrusion.
I think you've got a good grasp
on what just happened, right?
Yes—
The series from Next that's getting serialized,
"Crow," is a mainstream battle manga.
Niizuma is a genius-type.
Even if you do mainstream,
you won't be able to beat him.
And it's the general viewpoint
of the editorial department—
that Niizuma won't be able to
become number one in the main magazine.
How can you be sure we won't
win against Niizuma?
Still?
Our mainstream won't even be
appearing together with Niizuma.
After seeing your name today, I can tell!
To be exact, you're saying—
"I can tell you can't win based on this name."
Right?
All right.
Half a year!
If you can't make a name
that I approve of in half a year,
you will follow my plan.
And then if you still insist on doing mainstream,
I'll step down as your editor!
Are you all right with that?!
Yes!
I always wondered "Why am I the only one having a hard time?"
doushite boku dake ga kon'nani tsurai no ka to itsumo omotteta
The people around me all seemed so happy
mawari no hito bakari shiawase sou ni mieta
But when I talked to you, I felt just a little bit better
dakedo kimi to hanashitara sukoshi dakedakedo ki ga raku ni natta
Maybe it's because we were open with each other
nita youna koto uchiakete kuretakara kana
Sometimes the reality you can't see with your eyes is like a monster
kao no mienai genjitsu ga toki ni kaibutsu no you ni
Our ambitions are crushed, but we move on
bokura no kokorozashi wo tsubusou to oshiyosete kurukeredo
I can say from the bottom of my heart that I'm glad I met you
deaete yokatta to kokoro kara ieru
People are multiplying little by little
hito ga sukoshi zutsu fuete ku
While clenching their warmth
sono nukumori wo kamishimenagara
We could support each other or face the boring things head on
sasae attari hikutsu wo butsuke attari
I'll finally arrive at that place alone
hitori ja tadori tsukenai basho ni
We're now proceeding en route
bokura wa ima kitto omomuite iru tochuu
en route
tochuu
Next
Episode
Our time limit is half a year.
In that time, we have to make
something Hattori approves of!
Huh?! Then what about dates?
We won't have that kind of time!
Right away? Then I'm going to Miho's house.
Next time, Debut and Impatience
Debut and
Impatience
Balancing dreams and love is hard!