Coincidentally, the second I got the
nerve to turn around, Azuki turned too.
The seconds felt like hours.
Then I came to my senses
and turned away quickly.
But two or three seconds later, I
couldn't help turning around again.
Farther away, Azuki turned again too.
It's like Azuki and I were
on the exact same wavelength.
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Every worry floats up to and fills the spring sky
shinpaigoto bakari ga tsumoru haru no sora wo
I look up, look down,
miagete utsumuite
and find myself looking back up at the sky
mata kao wo ageteru
I swore I'd find myself in this town
kono machi de mitsukerutte kimeta jibun
I tuck away all my important things into my heart for safekeeping
nakushicha ikenai mono wo mune ni
Your love
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Summer and Names
Wavelength?
She could've turned ten times, and
your eyes just only met twice.
Impossible.
Your conviction's pretty
impressive. I don't get it.
You making fun of me?
Course not. I'm jealous.
In sixth grade, I laid eyes
on Azuki for the first time.
We went to Akehi Elementary
but she went to Akehi Second.
At the school swimming competition,
Azuki and I kept staring at each
other from opposing sidelines.
We weren't embarrassed at all, back then.
Entrance
Ceremony
Our eyes met again at the middle
school entrance ceremony.
This time we were only a few feet apart,
but we turned away quickly.
This has been going on since elementary
school? You might as well have been dating.
That's only with very optimistic hindsight.
Well, no matter how perfectly
in tune you guys are,
if you don't get her email,
you can't communicate.
It's fine, as long as I
get it before we graduate.
Now, we focus on manga!
Is that so?
Well, here's five pages for you then.
That was fast!
I was working on it while you
took your trip down memory lane.
Two Planet Earths
"Two Planet Earths."
The planet we live on is just
a clone of the real Earth.
We too, are merely clones of
that planet's inhabitants.
We were created as mere
components of their experiment.
They recreated their own condition in order
to observe and learn how to make a better world.
As a result of this experiment, there's no
war or global warming on the real Earth.
Shuujin.
What'd you think?
It's no good, right?
Names can't be done on a whim!
I have no idea how to make a
good layout. And my pictures—
Is this story copied from somewhere?
It's not copied, but there might be some
overlapping elements. That's okay, right?
It's a story anyone could come up with.
Not just anyone could come up with this.
At least, I for sure couldn't!
What?
This setting has me totally spellbound.
No way!
Seriously!
But after that, it just becomes a battle
between us and the people from the real Earth.
That's what captivated me!
You can jump straight into a battle!
Or do you have an even better idea?
I thought about doing a sports manga too.
Maybe call it "The Sunglasses Pitcher?"
Yeah?
A Little League fastball pitcher who's aiming
to be pro, gets hit by a line drive and goes blind.
Ten years later, a pitcher with sunglasses
suddenly appears in the pro league.
He has a perfect game, able to throw
any pitch, any course, at 180 km/h.
The startling truth is that the young
boy didn't give up on his dream.
He trained extensively with
his father for ten years.
Get on your feet, sunglasses!
Yes, Dad!
When it gets out that he's blind, the boy must
face the league administrators and other pitchers.
You're good, Shuujin!
I couldn't think up such an
elaborate story in such a setting!
Really?
You really think I'm good?
Yeah! Normally I think you're stupid—
I'm so glad!
I've actually been thinking about
it frantically every day—
You know how sometimes, I'm
kind of overly confident?
If you believe in me, I have
a real reason to be confident.
I'm so glad.
I'm seriously so glad!
I'll work hard too!
I'll draw pictures to match
your amazing stories!
Which story do you wanna do then?
"Two Earths," I think.
"Sunglasses" is better for serialization.
Got it.
Do you have an ideal page count in mind?
I believe the New Artist of the Year
award limits works to 31-45 pages.
That sounds about right.
But don't worry about that right now.
Just write!
Yeah!
Finished already?
Yeah, 'cause I had the
beginning thought out already.
But if it's not interesting,
being fast counts for nothing.
Saiko?
Huh?
Yeah, it's good.
There you are.
Takagi!
Come here a sec!
You're being called.
It's not like I wanna go.
Oh, she's coming over here.
You serious?
Ignoring people when they call you—
She looks really pissed—
I don't hear anything.
Takagi.
I need to talk to you.
What about?
It's fine, stay!
Miho asked me, "Why does Takagi
know about my dream for the future?
You told him, didn't you?"
She got angry at me, you know!
Doesn't really matter, does it?
All I did was confirm it with her.
I did tell him by accident though.
This is my friend Mashiro.
Nice to meet you.
Miho's easily embarrassed, so
I told you not to tell anyone!
I got it!
I won't tell anyone else.
But you ask her, "How's she gonna
be a voice actor if she's that shy?"
Like I could say that.
At any rate, I won't tell anyone
else, so don't worry about it.
So, she turned you down?
Huh?! What are you talking about?
But you talked to her, didn't you?
I told you, it was just to confirm
if that was really her dream or not.
Besides, Azuki already has
someone she likes, doesn't she?
No way. Who?!
I don't know! But it's normal for middle
school girls to like someone, right?
I guess so.
But she never talks about it though.
Why'd you ask me about her then?
That's because—
I wanted to talk to you?
L—Let me think about that.
Huh? Hey, wait!
Miyoshi— san!
Ah, you've done it now.
What?
Even if that was a joke,
there's gonna be tears or pain.
She's participated in national karate
or aikido tournaments, right?
And she's always liked you, hasn't she?
No way!
She told you her best friend's
secret. Doesn't that mean something?
And her "Let me think about that."
If she actually hated you,
she'd never say that.
Now that you mention it—
Wait, this is bad!
Miyoshi's not bad.
Not bad? Why do you say that?
Azuki's best friend can't be bad!
What is it, Kaya?
Takagi confessed to me.
No way!
Really.
What do you think of him?
He's smart and tall—
Exactly! We don't match at all!
That's not true! You're cute, Kaya.
I'm sure Takagi thinks so, too.
I'm cute?
Yeah!
Kaya?
But according to the rumors,
he's definitely with Iwase.
But she's probably hard for guys to approach.
Her whole "boys are so beneath me" attitude?
She's not that—
Oh, right.
Who do you like?
What?
N—No one.
Just like I thought!
Like I said—
Everyone's looking at us!
Hurry up and spill it!
No one, I said!
Guys will think you're stuck up
like Iwase if you keep saying that.
What?
No one's ever seen you talk to a boy.
Isn't that kind of snobby?
Kaya!
Yeah?
I'm just too embarrassed to talk to guys.
To be honest, I like guys
even more than you do!
What?!
Maybe it's because I don't have
any brothers or something,
but I'm really aware of guys, so I blush
really easily and can't talk to them.
Do you understand?
It's funny when you talk
like a teacher, Miho.
Gosh—
But because you spoke so earnestly, I get it.
I know you're not lying.
Thanks, Kaya.
Make sure you go by
yourself to talk to Takagi!
What?
I won't go with you!
What?!
They're back!
W—What should I do?
Do your best!
Miho!
Maybe we're on the same wavelength too.
That was just her turning around.
What do you mean "just?"
Final Exams
Math
Japanese
English
Finished!
It never ends!
No matter how much I rewrite
it, I'm still not satisfied.
And it's almost summer break.
Don't stress about it.
I'm not good enough to turn
it into a manuscript anyway.
We'll be fine if you finish the second
half when I'm done with the first half.
Yeah, I got it.
Mikami Shun
Aida Koji
Shinbo Seiji
Iwase Aiko
Takagi Akito
Rankings
Sixth place! Well done!
1st Semester Final Exam
Just out of our class.
It's just like you said, there's
a pattern to exam questions.
Right, all that's left is—
Our wavelengths—
Hot!!
I wanna go to the beach!!
Summer Vacation
I don't wanna do homework ...
Class over summer break?
Eww
Your father might have agreed,
but you should know I'm against you
spending all summer locked up in that studio.
Semester Final Math
Year 3 Class 2
Mashiro Moritaka
Year   Class
▪
Name
Come home sometimes, okay?
Okay!
Hey, Saiko!
Let me stay over, too.
I don't mind, but don't your parents care?
No, it's fine.
Really?
Here.
Kawaguchi Taro-sensei drank
this to help him focus, right?
Then we should try it too!
You're pretty into these rituals, huh.
Alright, once again.
To completing a manuscript
this summer vacation!
Cheers to that!
That's bitter—
Wow! My name's becoming a manga!
This is still a name.
I'm just fixing the layout
and composition a bit.
But I feel like once you take a pen
to it, it'll become an amazing manga!
It's still far from completion.
We still have the rough draft after this.
It'll be a while until I take a pen to it.
Oh, really?
We're not at that stage yet.
I'll keep practicing up until
the second I do it in pen.
But Saiko, you said there aren't
any boundaries in manga.
Don't you think you're
trying a little too hard?
I think you're already—
No, I'm not even close.
I understand.
Do it to your satisfaction.
I keep working on names
till I'm satisfied too!
Yeah.
I won't say a word about the names.
And you won't say a word about the art.
Right?
Right!
You asleep, Saiko?
Like I could fall asleep that quickly.
I know, right.
It's like we used our brains
so much we can't sleep.
Guess I'll read some more manga.
Going to read in your sleep?
Read anything interesting lately?
Dragonball.
You already liked that, didn't you?
It's loyalty. Or maybe 'cause
it's the crux of everything.
Did you ever pretend like you were
in Dragonball when you were little?
I did!
Fu—
sion!
Ha!
Shuujin, you were late on the "sion!"
My "sion" was perfect!
Your "sion" was too early!
No! If you don't say it with enough
energy, it's not the real thing!
Are you calling my "sion" fake?!
Who's John anyway?
Get back here!
August Schedule
School Day
Oh, you're awake.
Shuujin.
Yes?
I'm gonna try using a pen.
It's already been a month.
I'm still not completely
satisfied, but it's time to start.
I'm not saying you need to hurry the names.
You should keep at it until you're satisfied.
I will.
Alright!
I finished the first half.
Good work. You should take a break!
Yeah, you too.
Yeah.
Want some?
Maybe later.
Oh crap!
I wonder if whiteout can fix this—
Let's go out for a bit.
Alright.
And now, for this week's number one hit—
Released in July, it's already
almost platinum, KOOGY's—
Are you okay?
I thought I was gonna die.
Hey, don't you just love this song?
It's KOOGY, right?
Limited Time Only  360 Yen
It's a song from his new album!
I wanna see his summer tour!
Yeah, we've got to live
it up over summer break!
Shuujin?
Let's get back to work.
Yeah!
I'm gonna go to sleep soon.
Saiko?
He's already done this much?
Sorry it took this long.
I'm going to the convenience store.
Take a break!
I can get the groceries.
After this, I won't be working on
the manuscript anymore, so let me.
Also, if you called Azuki,
I'm sure she'd come over.
"Master, your meal is ready."
I'm kidding, I'm kidding!
I just thought that would perk you up a bit.
Liar!
I know Azuki's not that type of girl.
Sorry, I'd like to get this book—
Excuse me.
You sure took a while.
You didn't go to the nearby store?
No, it's from the usual place.
You got Jack!
Thanks!
Niizuma Eiji!
Eiji's amazing.
It's not just his drawings.
His story's good too.
If we were—
to lose right now—
it's 'cause of our drawings!
S—Saiko!
I don't wanna lose.
I agree, but for illustrations to
be as interesting as the story—
I won't lose!
Is there anything I can help with?
You completed the names all by yourself.
I wanna complete this by myself too.
Middle School
Math
Alright!
The whiteout's done.
All that's left is—
Saiko, I can hel—
I won't say a word about the names.
And you won't say a word
about the art, remember?
I was just hoping to work towards
that moment of completion together—
Can you apply screentone?
Yeah!
Apply this to the pants
of every Earth soldier!
Got it! Thank you!
It's full speed until we finish!
Yeah!
The drawings are good but I
don't know about my story.
The story's good but I'm
not sure about my drawings.
Saiko.
Yeah?
What're doing?
Aren't you embarrassed?
Thank you, Saiko.
Away
Telephone
Directory
Copy
Alright, let's make that call.
The number's probably already programmed in.
Copy
Telephone
Directory
Copy
If we call from here, won't people think
Kawaguchi Taro's come back to life?
No one remembers his number.
But if you don't want
to, use your cell phone.
What should I say?
"I'd like to submit a manuscript" or something.
I'm calling.
Hurry up!
Shounen Jack editorial department.
The boring everyday gets to me sometimes,
BETAAna genjitsu ni tsubusaretemo
but I always get back on my feet, standing strong
uchinomesareta jibun hiroiatsumete
No matter how many times the end approaches me,
nando owari ga otazuneretemo
I'll push my own back forward, keeping me on my feet
sono tabi ni jibun de jibun no senaka otoshita
If I get lost in the meaning of continuing what I do,
tsudzuiteku imi ni nayami
I'll rid myself of those worries and keep myself going forward
sono mayoi sae tachikitte yuku
Always
itsumo
The straight edge that draws the outline of my future
mirai no rinkakusen egaku massuguna jougi wa
is made of all the courage I've mustered up until today
ikutsumo no kinou no yuuki de dekiteru
I'll climb over the tall wall that I never thought I'd face,
omoiegaita no to chigau takaikabe koe
and continue my journey, going past the vanishing point
shoushitsuten no mukou e susunde
This winding road seems to never end,
harukanaru winding road
but it is the road I personally chose
hoka no daredemonai watashi ga jibun de eranda
I set my tiny dreams on fire,
kasukana yume wo zenbu moyashita
and broke through the dark with its light
sono hikaru de yami wo saite
Now that I've broken down the wall,
kudaita kabe no mukou ni
I can see my sky once more
jibun no sora ga mieru
Next
Episode
We brought our first ever manga manuscript
to the Jack editorial department.
I'm so nervous!
Management
Meeting Corner Open Hours
Was the editor we met good or bad?
Management
Meeting Corner Open Hours
Let's do it with passion!
Next time, Carrot and Stick.
Carrot and
Stick
Dreams are sweet but reality is bitter!