I thought you'd definitely come back for this.
So, I waited here for you.
What is this guy after?
Team up with me and create manga.
I—
I'm gonna do the illustrations.
And this guy is doing the story.
I knew it! Awesome!
You two can definitely make it!
Th—Then if our manga becomes an anime,
We'll reserve the heroine's voice for you.
Really? This makes me really happy.
I'm going to try my best.
I'll definitely become a voice actress,
and then I'll voice your anime.
This is wonderful!
Then after our dreams come true, will you marry me?
I didn't get any sleep at all.
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Every worry floats up to and fills the spring sky
shinpaigoto bakari ga tsumoru haru no sora wo
I look up, look down,
miagete utsumuite
and find myself looking back up at the sky
mata kao wo ageteru
I swore I'd find myself in this town
kono machi de mitsukerutte kimeta jibun
I tuck away all my important things into my heart for safekeeping
nakushicha ikenai mono wo mune ni
Your love
Can you see the blue bird,
aozora tobikau Blue Bird
fluttering through the blue sky?
ano tori ga miemasu ka?
Happiness can't be described by a visible color, but I can feel
shiawase wa itsumo mienai Color kanjiteiru
Your love
Idiot and Genius
How long are you planning
to stay in your pajamas?
Hurry and get changed.
Gotcha.
Why can't he just give me
an obedient "yes ma'am?"
Then after our dreams come true, will you marry me?
After our dreams come true, we're getting married.
The King of Manga
That guy coerced me into saying I'll illustrate manga.
But the truth is—
Moritaka!
Takagi is here to pick you up!
Huh?
Hurry up!
Hi.
So annoying.
Morning, Saiko!
Quit calling me "Saiko" and
stop walking me to school.
C'mon.
You can just call me Shuto, too.
Isn't calling someone named Moritaka "Saiko"
different than calling someone named Akito "Shuto?"
How's it different?
"Shuto" makes you think
of soccer, so it's kind of cool.
But "Saiko" just sounds like an insult.
Really?
I got it. I'll just call you Shuujin.
Shuujin? What am I, a criminal?
C'mon. Akito can also be read Shuujin.
See ya, criminal.
At least call me Shuujin.
You're okay with that?
Yeah!
Your uncle died three years ago, right?
You looked him up?
My parents knew because we're neighbors.
They didn't know he was the manga
artist, Kawaguchi Taro, though.
Super Hero Legends
That's because it's a pen name.
His real name was Nobuhiro Mashiro.
There was probably a small obituary in
the newspapers: "mangaka has died."
A mangaka with nothing
serialized is just a NEET.
Seven straight years of unemployment
would make anyone suicidal.
It was suicide?
My parents said he overworked himself,
but he wasn't even employed, so
it couldn't have been overwork.
You don't wanna be a
mangaka anymore, right?
But even if you don't, I'm still going to.
I'm gonna do it too!
We're gonna team up and become
the best mangakas in Japan!
Didn't I say I might not team up with you?
Not that again!
I'm the one who got you into this!
It wasn't you, it was Azuki.
What's up with that?
Thanks for hooking us up, Shuujin-kun.
That's not fair, Saiko.
C'mon, let's do this together.
Takagi.
Iwase.
How are you feeling?
Same as always—
Rather calm, aren't you?
I'm not going to lose to you this time.
These exams cover a lot of
material from last semester.
Oh.
Have you decided which high
school you want to go to?
Not yet—
The top two students in our grade—
Exams are such a downer.
I just gave up yesterday and went to sleep.
No point in ruining my skin.
You'll do fine, Kaya.
It's not like I studied that much yesterday either.
So you say!
But you always get good grades.
That's not true.
See you later.
Everyone, watch what you're writing.
Especially you, Suzuki.
At least get your name right.
Midterm Exam Math
Year 3 Class 2
Mashiro Moritaka
Year      Class
▪
Name
Azuki—
She's the same as always—
It's like last night never happened.
Azuki's dream to be a voice actress,
And mine to be a mangaka.
Fulfilling our dreams—
Then marrying—
M—Marrying Azuki!
I can't take this!
Sir.
What's wrong, Mashiro?
I'm feeling sick.
Can I go to the nurse's
office until the second period?
You do look rather pale.
You can take the make-up exam later then.
No, it's alright.
I'm already half done. It's fine.
Can you make it alone?
I'll be fine.
Sir, me too.
I was up all night studying.
I feel dizzy. Can I go as well?
You too, Takagi?
I'm done with the exam already.
I guess it's fine—
Everyone, concentrate on your exams.
Nurse's Office
Excuse me.
What, you too?
Sorry, I don't feel very good.
So I'm gonna take a little nap.
You look perfectly fine to me.
I feel dizzy and nauseous, and my head—
Hope you feel better.
You alright, Saiko?
So annoying.
You couldn't sleep last night, right?
Did you even eat?
Do you have a fever or something?
I just felt like I couldn't breathe in the classroom.
Couldn't breathe?
Lack of sleep?
My chest feels tight when
I'm in the same room as Azuki.
Stop messing around in there!
S—Sorry!
Your chest feels tight—
Did something happen between
you two since yesterday?
Huh? Nothing happened.
"Nothing happened."
You at least exchanged email addresses, right?
We didn't.
What?
Hey!
If you feel fine enough to talk, then go back to class!
We can't talk here. Let's leave.
Alright, I guess.
Thank you very much.
We're going back now.
Why did you two even come here?
I'll ask Azuki for her email for you.
It's fine.
She'll think I'm pathetic if you do that.
But you can't ask her yourself, right?
If talking to her was that easy,
I wouldn't be in this situation.
Saiko.
You really like Azuki, don't you?
I love people like you two.
You never cease to creep me out.
Look at all the other couples out there.
They're all over each other in public.
And they brag about it too.
You see it all the time.
Compare that to a couple where your chest
feels tight just being in the same room,
I definitely like couples like you two better.
Seems like I can't avoid you liking me.
Anyways, I'm definitely teaming up with you.
Why?
I'm the only one who knows you like Azuki, right?
Yeah, and you better not tell anyone.
And I'm the only one who
can give you romance advice.
I'm irreplaceable.
We'll work together for the sake of love and manga!
Love and manga are entirely unrelated matters.
Oh, right.
Anyways, don't you have to get back to class?
There's still time—
I already finished that exam
with a perfect score, no doubt.
I just don't get it.
If you wanna be a manga
artist, why are you even studying?
It's not like you need the grades.
Insurance.
Not even I'm 100% sure I can
succeed as a mangaka.
That's a prudent outlook.
Do you think everyone in our class is stupid?
Huh?
Do you think you're the smartest in our grade?
Why are you asking me all of a sudden?
I hate questions like that.
Then you do think so?
You think you have to be smart to be a mangaka?
Yeah, I do.
At least you need intelligence and common sense.
But I don't think studying equals being smart.
We've been in the same
class less than two months,
but I knew you were smart just by looking.
That's why I called you out.
Good drawing skills weren't your only appeal.
The fact that you asked, "Do you think everyone
in our class is stupid?" means that you do.
Azuki's smart too.
Rather, I think she's clever.
She's cute, but she doesn't stand out.
She's elegant yet straightforward.
And it's not like she's manipulative.
I think she's much smarter
than Iwase, who can only study.
You've seen Azuki's house.
That house was incredible.
Azuki grew up in a good environment.
That's why she's not greedy.
I think the source of Azuki's charm is her family,
her compassion, her intelligence and her grace.
Grace, huh—
You're complimenting her a lot.
You're not worried or jealous even
though I'm complimenting her
because you're smart, Saiko.
Well, everyone was born into different situations.
Whether it's your house, your family or your looks.
That's why there are so many
idiots who simply remain dreamers.
But I'm smart, so I'm not gonna lose to my dream.
That's what I think.
Anyways, we're gonna have to give it our very best.
Shuujin,
I think I might just team up with you.
What?
We think alike.
And your stories seem like they'd be interesting.
Really?
C'mon, let's do this!
I said "might" didn't I?
If your name's interesting,
then I'll do the drawings.
First period's over.
Think you can take the next exam?
Yeah.
And, what's a "name?"
What?
After hearing about your
uncle's suicide, it occurred to me—
Won't your parents be
against you drawing manga?
It'd make sense if they won't let you,
since it happened once to a relative.
That's true.
Because of the way he died,
they'd be against it no matter what.
I'll convince my parents when I get back.
Just like Ittetsu Hoshi from Star of the
Giants, and Yuzan Kaibara from Oishinbo,
The first hurdle a child must leap is their parents.
This is the policy in my family:
If I need to talk or ask a favor,
I go straight to my mother.
After that, my parents discuss in private.
If my father has anything to say,
my mother relays his message to me.
If she doesn't get back to me, that means they agreed.
So basically, I've never had a
real conversation with my dad.
Here you are, dad.
I'll bring this back after—
Mom!
What? We didn't even know you were back.
I'd like to discuss something with you.
So, what is it?
Just spit it out already.
Um—
I'm going to become a mangaka.
No.
Wow, that was fast—
I'm gonna continue high school and go to college.
I'll quit if I'm not successful by
the time I graduate from college.
So you're just going to go to some
random university and draw manga?
Your uncle debuted when he was in college too.
If you haven't realized,
it's gonna be exactly the same.
I knew she'd bring up my uncle.
Concentrate on studying.
You don't know if it's gonna turn out the same way.
Besides, it's not like I'm feeling suicidal just yet.
You think your uncle killed himself?!
Your uncle was too stressed—
I'm sorry. I get it.
He wasn't serialized but he was
working hard to get serialized again.
He drew himself to death.
That's what I meant by suicide.
At any rate, the answer's no.
I don't think your father would let you either.
This discussion is over.
Mom!
What?
At least try talking to dad about it.
Dad's not back yet.
Kawaguchi Taro
Super Hero Legends
Super
This is so funny!
Manga really is amazing.
I may have said it accidentally, but I've
always wanted to be a mangaka.
Just like my uncle.
He was always drawing.
He drew until he was completely worn out.
Even though he couldn't get serialized in the end—
He may be gone now—
But he left us with these hilarious manga.
I don't care what my parents say.
I'll draw manga even if they disown me.
Welcome back.
Dad's back.
It's been ten minutes.
No, five minutes.
That was fast. So he probably said no right away—
Moritaka, I'm coming in.
A—Alright.
I spoke with your father.
A—And?
"Let him do it."
"Men have dreams that a
woman wouldn't understand."
is what he said.
Come with me to your grandpa's room.
He's the one who lost a son to manga.
You have to tell him yourself.
Right—
Grandpa. May I come in?
Sure.
Grandpa.
What is it, Moritaka?
I'm going to become a mangaka.
Huh—
a mangaka?
Y—Yeah.
Alright.
Moritaka, take this.
A key?
Dad!
Is this your answer?
Where does this key go to?
It's the key to your uncle's apartment.
It's for Nobuhiro's apartment.
I've left his studio exactly
the way it was when he died.
I'm entrusting it to you, Moritaka.
B—But I've only just decided to draw manga.
I won't need a studio for ages.
You're right.
Huh?
It's going to be a while before
you have a real need for it.
But there's no such thing as
preparations that are too early.
That place should have all the things
you need to be a mangaka, right?
So, do you want it or not?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Can I go out for a bit?
What are you saying?
It's past ten already and you've got a test tomo—
Go.
Hurry up and go.
Thank you! I'm gonna get ready.
Dad—
Moritaka has changed.
I was really worried about him before,
but I think he'll be fine now.
My uncle's manuscripts will be much better.
I'm leaving!
Hurry and come back!
Sorry!
I haven't been to my uncle's studio in three years.
Yo! My beloved Saiko-chan!
Did your parents forgive you?
I'm gonna show you what a name is so c'mon!
Huh?
I got my uncle's studio!
What?
The studio hasn't been touched since he died!
W—Wait, did you tell them that you
were gonna be a mangaka?
Yeah.
Awesome!
Where are you right now?
I'm heading towards North Yakusa Station right now.
The studio's in Yakusa.
Just one station away? I'll be right there.
Let's meet at North Yakusa station then.
Yeah!
The boring everyday gets to me sometimes,
BETAAna genjitsu ni tsubusaretemo
but I always get back on my feet, standing strong
uchinomesareta jibun hiroiatsumete
No matter how many times the end approaches me,
nando owari ga otazuneretemo
I'll push my own back forward, keeping me on my feet
sono tabi ni jibun de jibun no senaka otoshita
If I get lost in the meaning of continuing what I do,
tsudzuiteku imi ni nayami
I'll rid myself of those worries and keep myself going forward
sono mayoi sae tachikitte yuku
Always
itsumo
The straight edge that draws the outline of my future
mirai no rinkakusen egaku massuguna jougi wa
is made of all the courage I've mustered up until today
ikutsumo no kinou no yuuki de dekiteru
I'll climb over the tall wall that I never thought I'd face,
omoiegaita no to chigau takaikabe koe
and continue my journey, going past the vanishing point
shoushitsuten no mukou e susunde
This winding road seems to never end,
harukanaru winding road
but it is the road I personally chose
hoka no daredemonai watashi ga jibun de eranda
I set my tiny dreams on fire,
kasukana yume wo zenbu moyashita
and broke through the dark with its light
sono hikaru de yami wo saite
Now that I've broken down the wall,
kudaita kabe no mukou ni
I can see my sky once more
jibun no sora ga mieru
Next
Episode
Let's head to my uncle's studio!
Yeah!
What's left there are warm memories,
stark realities and a shocking truth.
What is it?
Parents and
Children
Next time: Parents and Children
Love and romance keep our dreams alive!